PAUL: Yeah, hello everyone, good morning, am I audible? Please do confirm in the charts.
PAUL: Alright, thanks for the confirmation, Kick, so…
PAUL: I hope already know… every one of you know today's agenda. It will be the basics of land chain.
PAUL: Okay, so, fine. So, let's… before starting our discussion, okay, so we have just recently launched a new course.
PAUL: Okay, in Udemy, so I'll be sharing the access to that.
PAUL: Okay? So…
PAUL: It's a request that everybody, like, just give 5 stars and put your reviews. You are the first people that we are providing this. Okay, it's a course on MCP. Okay, so let me start sharing my screen, and let me show you the details.
PAUL: I think this is my desktop, too. Okay, alright.
PAUL: Okay, so I will be sharing this link to you in the chat. I'm providing the free course access, okay? So this is completely free, you guys.
PAUL: The idea is that, okay, so right now, as you can see here, so zero rating, okay, I'm one student. So the idea is that you guys get the access right now. So, this is the first coupon that has been built for this course, and as you guys know, the coupons are limited, so don't share it with anyone.
PAUL: Please provide 5 stars and the review. I have shared the link in the chat, you guys can access it.
PAUL: Okay, just 30 minutes before we have published it.
PAUL: So, around, I think, 8.30, so I thought, let's give you access, because people were asking regarding the access to the rag batch. So, this month, coupons are done, okay? So, probably for the rag batch, next month the coupons will be coming, then probably I'll be sharing.
PAUL: Okay, so everyone, please get the access. I think everybody, the coupon code is FREEMCP. Okay, so at the end of the URL, you'll be getting that.
PAUL: Okay, so that is the main thing. If it is showing the price for you, okay, manually add the code, okay, like, add to cart, and then add the coupon code, which is FREMC fee. Okay, so…
PAUL: I think from the URL, you guys can get…
PAUL: It should work for everyone. Just now, we have launched it, so I know that it has not been shared in other batches.
PAUL: Okay, so everybody please get the access, provide the stars, okay, I'm giving you 5 minutes, and then we'll be starting the session.
PAUL: Okay, so, like, I think just now I checked my Git access token has expired, okay, so I could not push…
PAUL: today's code…
PAUL: in GitHub, okay, rather than I'll be sharing it in Drive, because the setup to create the token and update, it will take some time for me, so I've just uploaded in the Google Drive, I think.
PAUL: Yes, okay, and I'll be sharing that dev file with you guys.
PAUL: So, everyone, please get the access to this particular course, okay, and provide the 5-star ratings, okay? If any review's possible, please do that.
PAUL: Okay, that is a humble request.
PAUL: Because going forward, like, majorly all the UDME courses, like, in every month, at least one, you guys will be getting.
PAUL: Can you please share the link, please? I just joined.
PAUL: Okay, alright.
PAUL: the Notion link is broken. Alright, let me just check Notion once.
PAUL: The Notion link is broken.
PAUL: Okay, let me just see, view site…
PAUL: No, the link is not broken.
PAUL: The link is working fine.
PAUL: Whoever is told, please do have a check.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Okay, so everybody please get the access to the Udemy course, provide the 5 stars and the reviews.
PAUL: Okay, so by not this one.
PAUL: This is so warm.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: And in the Notion, I'll be sharing the Google Drive link, today's class materials that we'll be discussing.
PAUL: Let's say you'll be getting it in Notion.
PAUL: Okay, the Python TSA course, yes, Mike has done the recordings for that, but, let's see, going forward, it's a long journey of 4 to 5 months, so every month, like, at least one or two courses that we do provide. It's not like every course-free coupon that we do provide.
PAUL: Okay, because there are other batches also, and the coupons are limited, like, I think close to 500 to 600. Sometimes, for a few courses, it's 1,000, but you have to understand that if I share it in 4 batches easily, like, all the coupons will be gone, pretty much.
PAUL: Yes, we will start with installing the stuff. So, pretty much basic stuff today that we'll be discussing. So…
PAUL: at least we'll be using the latest version of Langchen for today.
PAUL: Okay, because in the last 2 months, I feel that there have been massive updates in Lanshan, very specifically starting from the month of August.
PAUL: Okay, so all those things, so…
PAUL: Okay, now let me just reload this page, you guys will be getting the Google Drive link, I think.
PAUL: Yes, the code download link is here. Okay, you guys can access this link.
PAUL: Sort of from where we will start coding. From where we will start? From today, only we will start the coding part. The previous lecture was much more theoretical.
PAUL: Okay, and I have added all the major notes with respect to the previous classes. Okay, so you guys can access those notes, like, in the RAG Details Survey. I will add images, okay, because to add images from the research papers, a little bit of screenshot and other stuff, that part I will update it today.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Alright, so… let me just reload… Okay.
PAUL: Everybody has done it, please let me know. Because right now, I think there are close to 200 folks.
PAUL: Okay, so please let me know that everybody has taken the access to this course, provided the reviews, okay, and with 5-star ratings.
PAUL: please reshare, again. People are joining late. I start the class around 9-10. I give you 10 minutes. I know that it happens that probably.
PAUL: You might, but at least… just be sure that at least by 9, 10, you are in the class.
PAUL: Alright, so whoever is joining late, please get the access. In the meantime, others who have already given the reviews, okay, got the access, please, download that…
PAUL: Material, okay, for today's class, which is available here. Okay, so, Exploring Langchen, 16th November. Here you'll be getting a Google Drive link, and just let me know the Google Drive link is working. I feel that it should work. I've given you a view access, so you guys should download it, but, just check and let…
PAUL: You know.
PAUL: It's a zip file, just do an unzipping operation.
PAUL: Unable to open Google Drive docs. Google Drive is working fine. Others, please let me know. Working fine, working fine, working fine. Okay, so for whom ever it's not working, please have a check, because others have confirmed that it's working fine.
PAUL: In the meantime, anybody who is joining late, just get the access to the free MCP course, okay?
PAUL: So here, one of our mentors, like Buppy, is there.
PAUL: Okay, so, Bhapib with Krish has recorded this course, and this course will give you the core idea of MCP. It's not a very long one, if you suggest it, as you can see here, 8 hours.
PAUL: Okay, so, like, even, like, if you watch it in 2x or 1.5x, it can be done within 5 hours also. So it's just all the, basics of MC.
PAUL: All right, because this module we'll be discussing, probably, I think it is…
PAUL: In your case, when is the module of MCPS coming?
PAUL: I think it will be at later stages, before the project, I think.
PAUL: Because I know MCP is here.
PAUL: in your… what exactly… I need to check. I think before the projects, probably in week 15 or 16, I will be teaching UMCP.
PAUL: Yesterday, any Udemy course link was shared? No. It's, like, once a month activity, generally once a month or twice a month. It's not like every class we share Udemy links.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Where is the link for the drive? It's in Notion.
PAUL: Please check your Notion.
PAUL: Could you please ping me the Notion URL?
PAUL: Over 8.
PAUL: Guys, please bookmark. Going forward, the idea is that you bookmark the link.
PAUL: Okay, whoever has not done it, please do bookmark.
PAUL: Because all the classes that I'll be taking, everything will be maintained here. If mentor changes, then again, like, things can change, but this I personally maintain that way.
PAUL: Somebody's telling new journey, so I don't have Notion.
PAUL: It's a URL.
PAUL: It's not necessary that locally or somewhere you need to have a Notion, it's just an URL.
PAUL: I hope you get that. Anybody can access.
PAUL: Just like a simple website.
PAUL: Can you help me understand the tokenyl LLM? It is a word… Character or a sentence, word.
PAUL: Token always refers to in what?
PAUL: Alright guys, so let me know. So, can we start the class, yes or no, in the chat?
PAUL: Okay, alright.
PAUL: Alright, so first of all, so let's start. Okay, so the idea is that, you guys have this ZIF file with you. Okay, now simply…
PAUL: unzip that particular file that I have given, a folder will be available to you, okay? So, let me just open my IDE.
PAUL: Just open your IDE, I think everybody can open a folder in IDE, please let me know.
PAUL: Yes.
PAUL: Because in your case, like, everything, won't be there, only the necessary things that is required, that only are kept. Other than that, in my case, there will be a lot of other files, you can ignore those things.
PAUL: please zoom a little… just let me know, I think, is it visible? So, for example, if I just try to open a sample notebook.
PAUL: Okay, do I need to… Increase it more…
PAUL: Because then I can only see a little bit less, that's why. Fine, I can just close the final overview, okay? So let me know that once you guys have done the unzipping operation, and you have opened it in some IDE, it doesn't matter, I am using Winstop, you can use VS Code, any stuff like that.
PAUL: Vikram is telling in Notion site, I am unable to see the Google Drive link. Please check, Vikram, try to do a hard refresh or something like that. Okay, because I knew it is there. Other people are downloading that's why.
PAUL: Right, I generally use Google Collab when I need GPUs. Otherwise, most of the things I try to do in Collab. Opened in VS Code, great, guys.
PAUL: Okay, the link is available in Notion. Please…
PAUL: get the link from Notion, guys.
PAUL: It does catches up here. Sometimes catching happens so simple, like Ctrl-Shift-R, which is the hard refresh.
PAUL: You ready? Everybody, please let me know in the chats, because this is the first class, so I will be just taking time, because going forward, the steps will be pretty much standard, and there won't be any type of changes.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: If you remember, I think, after the introduction, last week on Saturday, we talked about, like, creating virtual environments, okay? So that is the first thing that we will be doing today.
PAUL: Alright, so… Okay, so right now I've just opened my terminal.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: And right now, you can see, so this is basically the folder that we'll be working, the simple rag landscape, okay? So I think you guys can also open it. The idea is to create a virtual environment, as simple as that.
PAUL: Now, see, I am using Wrap, it's not necessary you guys use it. If you, guys are using, for example, like,
PAUL: VS Code, directly you can open the terminal of that also, so I have no issues.
PAUL: Okay, so simply, like, in terminal, and from terminal, like, whatever the stuff that you want to do, you can do that.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Because in my case, the virtual environment is already created, but again, I'll be showing you the commands of exactly the things that I'll be doing.
PAUL: Nope, this is…
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: So you can use a terminal of VA support or of RAC, whichever is preferable to you. Totally up to you, I'm giving you the choice.
PAUL: Okay, and please let me know that, yes, you guys are ready to execute the commands. The idea is that you should be, inside the folder, okay? So, let me just close motion for now.
PAUL: That's funny.
PAUL: Okay, so…
PAUL: Let me know, are you in that folder of your terminal, so that we can start our class, executing the commands?
PAUL: All right. So, if you remember, on Saturday, very specifically, we have used UV.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: So, what I will do…
PAUL: like, just a verification, because I know I have UV in my system, okay, and very specifically, like, my version can differ with your version, it doesn't matter. The idea is that we'll be creating the virtual environment using UV.
PAUL: If you are not using UV, that is also fine. You can use the generic Python one, okay? So the generic Python, it means that Python-MBNV, so that also works. So, whichever way you want to create a virtual environment, it's fine. I have no restrictions.
PAUL: Just so UV.
PAUL: So, generally, like, this is the command that I use. Okay, most of the times, UV. Then using the VNV package, I want to create a virtual environment. Okay, the third thing that I have here, very specifically, everybody, okay, so this will be the folder.
PAUL: So generally, I keep my virtual environments with a dot folder. The idea is that it should be hidden, okay? So, otherwise it's not necessary, but it's a good practice to use dot, okay, for virtual environments.
PAUL: So, simply, like, you can execute this particular command. Okay, so if I just change this to something like…
PAUL: test, okay, for now. Later on, I will delete this one.
PAUL: Okay, so right now, directly, you can see. So, I already have an environment, so this is just a test environment that I have created. So, UV VNB test.
PAUL: And right now, you can see, using SciPython, okay, it got created, and then finally activating the source.
PAUL: Okay?
PAUL: So, like, if you want to activate this particular environment, simply, you can do this one, test, okay, bin, activate.
PAUL: Okay? And you will be seeing that here, test will come. So right now, we know that we are inside the test environment. So, similarly, you guys can create your own virtual environment, and please activate it. Because in the next step, we need to install the packages, that's why.
PAUL: Okay, so you can use UV, or you can use the generic Python virtual environment, so… or Conda also works. So, whichever works for you the best, please proceed ahead with that.
PAUL: Yes, you guys can work with Condi, I have no issue.
PAUL: These things I have already taught last week, Saturday, with respect to virtual environments, three ways I have told you. So, whichever way you want to work, please proceed ahead.
PAUL: I don't have Anaconda Ravi in my system.
PAUL: Okay, so I cannot do that.
PAUL: Rather than I can tell you the command, like, conda create hyphen n, okay, then the name of the environment. So, for example, today's luncheon that we are doing, okay?
PAUL: is equal to, like, 3.12.13 that you can use, no issues. Okay, and then hyphen Y for the prompt of yes. So, this is the actual command. These things I've covered last lesson Saturday, so the idea is…
PAUL: Okay, not to repeat and spend time on those things.
PAUL: Alright guys, so please let me know how many of you have created the virtual environment so that we can proceed ahead with our class.
PAUL: 3.14 is also fine.
PAUL: Okay, it is the latest one, so I generally prefer one or two versions before.
PAUL: Alright, so let me just deactivate this environment.
PAUL: Alright, so I have activated my virtual environment, okay, and the idea is basically, to install the package, okay? So, as I'm using UV very specifically, okay, so let me just tell you. So, let's try to explore the file structure that we do have.
PAUL: Okay, so here, if you look into, so right now, initially, we are starting, so I provided a requirement.txt file. Later on, I'll be changing it to a 2ML-based file, which are the latest standards for Python.
PAUL: So, right now, there are a few packages that I have very specifically mentioned here. Okay, if you look here, okay, so, like, the LanChain package, the LanChain code package, the community, the text splitters.
PAUL: Okay, Langchen, OpenAI, okay, and a few other packages will be coming, okay, that we'll be installing. So, the idea is that, you guys, please do the installation of this package, okay? So, for the installation, the command is pretty much simple. Okay, so what I will be doing here, you…
PAUL: If you are using UV, then use UV, otherwise the command is only pip install hyphen R, REQ, press tab, okay? So, this is the command. If you are using UV, this is the command. If you are not using UV, okay, only remove the UV part. Rest of the command is exactly the same.
PAUL: Okay, so for example, like, if I try to do this… Okay, so, like…
PAUL: Okay, so I think text better's version of it later on, I will update it. There can be some type of package, okay, so if you feel that, remove the specific version from there.
PAUL: Okay, so please have a check with that.
PAUL: Because in my case, I have installed very specific versions, and for a few notebooks, it is required. So if you feel that any versions is not compatible, the idea is that we will be using the latest version, so you can actually remove any versions if it is failing in your case.
PAUL: Okay, so… for now, I'm just removing.
PAUL: Okay, so… Alright, Neo.
PAUL: And already the installation commands are there in the notebook also, but I thought about going forward, I'll be sharing always the requirements.
PAUL: Okay? Actually, we're not using Ulama, so…
PAUL: Later on, I think next week, we'll be talking about that.
PAUL: For a CPU-like boomer.
PAUL: Yes, if there is an error, just remove the versions. If you remove the versions, most of the things will be fine.
PAUL: Okay? So, for example, now, if I just try to encrypt the command, I know that it will be working fine, I think.
PAUL: Okay, there is a Pye PDF.
PAUL: Let me check, because here a lot of other packages are there, actually. Because of this versioning, okay, sometimes it fails.
PAUL: So, remove the versions, guys, okay? If anything is there, remove the versions.
PAUL: Okay, otherwise, because here are a few other packages I don't think that I need to share. Take token is fine, just wait.
PAUL: Just wait, okay, so once I do this, directly copy-paste the information that I'm sharing.
PAUL: Okay. Just wait, just wait, give me one minute.
PAUL: Because to make it version-specific, it will be a problem, because you guys will be using different Python versions. Okay, so yes, there can be some type of errors.
PAUL: Actually, I don't think… okay, alright.
PAUL: Okay, I'm sharing it in the chat. You guys can copy-paste it directly from the chat.
PAUL: Okay, I think copy-pasting can be a problem.
PAUL: Okay, so just wait.
PAUL: I'll be sharing it here, okay? So, just update that.
PAUL: From Notion, you guys can just copy-paste it.
PAUL: Okay, so directly from here, copy-paste the stuff.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Alright, now, see, I've removed all the versions, so everything should be working fine.
PAUL: Pypdf data, I forgot to press Ctrl, that's just waste.
PAUL: Okay, yeah.
PAUL: Done.
PAUL: So just be sure you are just removing the versions, and it should work fine. There won't be any type of problem. Please have a check.
PAUL: Please have it checked.
PAUL: okay, so I have shared the requirement.txt file here. Directly, you can copy this from me, okay?
PAUL: So, just copy and try to do the installation.
PAUL: Working, working, working, alright, working, everything installed, fine.
PAUL: Please remove the versions, Sumil Chandra, working great. When to create requirement.txt? When you have a lot of packages for a particular project, then when we create requirement.txt?
PAUL: What is the difference between UV add hyphen R?
PAUL: The idea is that if you want to add packages into requirement.txt, then we use that.
PAUL: Okay, so right now I'm not adding any packages.
PAUL: Okay, so installed, but, how to quick verify?
PAUL: If you want to do a quick verification, simply you can do something like a UV pip list.
PAUL: Okay, so using this particular command, all the packages that got installed will be coming with your version. Okay, so this is just for verification.
PAUL: Can you please share the link? Which link? Naga, yes, I can hear you.
PAUL: It totally depends. Hardik. Both the things does the same job.
PAUL: Okay, but, pyproject.tuml is the latest standard.
PAUL: Please let me know, guys. For everybody, the installation is done.
PAUL: Please remove the versions, Shiva. As you are just pasting it, I know that there is a version. So simply remove the versions, as I have told you.
PAUL: remove the versions. In my case, I just removed all the versions, because
PAUL: you might be using a different version of Python.
PAUL: I'm using 3.13. You probably can be on 12, you can be on 14. Okay, the idea is to remove that.
PAUL: I have already shared the requirement.txt in Notion. Please check.
PAUL: Please have a check, guys, because I know I have shared, so just wait, let me just check one.
PAUL: Okay? Yes, I think you can see it in here.
PAUL: And I've shared it in Notion. Directly, you can copy-paste it.
PAUL: It can be on CMD, it can be on PowerShell also, it totally depends upon your system, how you have done the setup.
PAUL: Okay, AKS, so directly I cannot say what is your system setup. You should know your system setup.
PAUL: Please share the Notion link.
PAUL: I've shared the Notion link for the lan chain. PyPika is taking time, alright, fine.
PAUL: Because for me, just now I showed, okay, the installation is done, and for many of you, you are getting
PAUL: We are not using Torch. I don't think I am using Torch, but Torch… Can be a dependency.
PAUL: Could not find a version that satisfied la- Lanchen Google Gen AI.
PAUL: Clangs in Google Gen AI is the major package. If, see, like, at any point of time, if you get any, always do have a check. For example, this is the official package manager of any type of Python packages, okay?
PAUL: So, if I do, like, PYPI lan chain.
PAUL: Okay, so as you can see, so this is the recent version, 1.0.7. Okay, and from here, you can actually get the command to do the installation.
PAUL: Okay, and if we will go to the release history, so majorly, like, you can see, previously I was working with 105.
PAUL: But, the recent version is this one. So, when you don't pass any parameter, or a specific version, by default, it picks up the latest version always.
PAUL: Okay. So, the idea is that going forward, because the idea is, if you are using the same, Python version, then it's not a problem, but if you're using different versions, then sometimes, there can be compatibility issues.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: torch is mentioned in requirements. If it is mentioned, you can simply put a comment on that.
PAUL: Torch, torch, torch… Where is Torch? I could not see Torch anywhere.
PAUL: Please have a check, guys. Torch is not there.
PAUL: Lunching, luncheon, lunching, luncheon, lunching.
PAUL: Yes, there is no torch. Okay, I have confirmed, please have a check, whoever is getting that.
PAUL: 3.12 issue is solved, great.
PAUL: Okay, tortures. PyPicar. Pipe picker, very specifically, I think it is a dependency package of some other package, that's right.
PAUL: Because very specifically, I'm not installing Pipika.
PAUL: Unable to activate the virtual environment. Please,
PAUL: look into your, I think.
PAUL: tools and installation class, okay, whoever is unable to do the activation of the virtual environment, so here all the commands are given. Please go through that.
PAUL: Because I think you guys should…
PAUL: Able to do the activation of the environment.
PAUL: Because the command is different in Mac, okay, in Windows, so that's why, based on your system requirement, please have it checked.
PAUL: Yes, it's pip install hyphen r requirement.tst, exactly correct. So, if I show you… okay, so if you are working with UV, you need to add UV. Otherwise, if you are not working with UV, just pip install hyphen r-requirement.txt.
PAUL: Please let me know, I think that it should be done by now.
PAUL: If it is no UB, just remove the UB part, no.
PAUL: the command is same. If you are not using UB, this will be the only command. Paper install hyphen r requirement.kht.
PAUL: If you are using UV, just add UV in front.
PAUL: Okay, yes, for sentence transformers, torchilles, dependency, correct.
PAUL: Okay, so… I joined late.
PAUL: Nothing that I can do. Today, right now, we are just installing the packages, and we'll start with the discussion of the notebook.
PAUL: if somebody's asking what is requirement.txt, like, really, I feel you need to have the basics of Python.
PAUL: Then, like, if you're not familiar with Python, it's just like a package, where we keep all our packages. In one shot, we can do all the installation, in simple terms.
PAUL: Okay, so others are telling, sir, please proceed, please proceed.
PAUL: Yes, I can see everybody's message, Sandeep.
PAUL: FIF is your vector store.
PAUL: Okay, so files is your vector store.
PAUL: We are good, sir, alright. Viraj, fine.
PAUL: Because, was able to resolve? Alright.
PAUL: Guys, now see, I have to proceed, because I think I've given you enough time to do the installation. If there is any problem, I'll be looking at… okay, so when will be, like, when I'll be taking the doubts?
PAUL: Okay, alright.
PAUL: Okay, so please let me know. I can proceed, because many of you are telling me, sir, please proceed, that's why.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Alright, majorly, most of you are saying, like, yes, yes, yes. Naga, if you are getting error, please try to solve it. Okay, otherwise, please wait for the doubts. It's not like that I'm going away anywhere.
PAUL: Okay? Ravi Kumar Gagandeep, please answer.
PAUL: Regarding what?
PAUL: See, guys, again, I'm just showing you the step again once more. I don't think, okay, it's very hard, it's pretty much simple, okay? So, what I will do, I will just create a new environment for now, okay? So, let me just create the stuff.
PAUL: So here, UV, VNV, okay, and the name of the virtual environment that you want to give. Okay, so for example, a rag for now that I'm giving, okay?
PAUL: So, the environment, rag got created. Now, in the next step, after creating the virtual environment, please activate the virtual environment, okay? So, rag being activate. So, this is the command. So, similarly, in Windows, the command is different.
PAUL: Okay. I think it is, like, build scripts. Within the scripts folder, you have that activate.pash.
PAUL: Okay, so please use that.
PAUL: Then, once you have done this, just uvpip install requirement.txt, okay? So, this is the rack folder.
PAUL: And done.
PAUL: So, only these 3 steps, which will take max, I think, within 1 minute I have done it. Okay, but probably if you are not using UV, it might take 2 to 3 minutes.
PAUL: So, please… Only 3 things. Create that environment, activate the environment, install the packages. Done.
PAUL: It says, file not found. I know that I have shared the requirement.txt with you. Okay, and the updated version is there in the Notion also. Please have it checked.
PAUL: Somebody was asking how to get the requirement.txt file.
PAUL: It is in Notion, guys, the same thing.
PAUL: It's in Notion, already I've shared it through Google Drive link also. The entire, code files for today that we'll be discussing, all the Jupyter notebooks are there.
PAUL: Alright, so I think enough time, now let's start with our discussion.
PAUL: Alright, so let's start.
PAUL: Bright sold.
PAUL: I don't need to do a digital signature for the file.
PAUL: Naga, okay, you create the virtual environment in your case, okay, and then based on your system, you have to do the activation.
PAUL: Alright, so guys, everyone, please leave the chat, okay? So let's start with our basic version, okay, of LanChain.
PAUL: Okay?
PAUL: Alright, so just let me know the notebooks are working fine, because I think 1, 2, 3, 4, total 8 notebooks that we'll be having. Okay, we will start with the introduction and the fundamentals one, and then I will move ahead with the simple, drag-lanching, okay? So, let's start with the simple one.
PAUL: Alright, so, simply always select your kernel. Kernel is based on the virtual environment, so right now, as you can see, this is my virtual environment, okay? And very specifically for that.vnv, so…
PAUL: By default, please select this virtual environment, okay, that you will be executing in your VS Code, Winstop, cursor, everywhere.
PAUL: Okay, so the local virtual environment that you have created, because within that environment, you have access to all the packages. Or manually, here also, we can do the installation, I will let you know that also. In some cases, if you feel one package is missed.
PAUL: In that case, directly, here also, you can pass it, like, pip install, or UVPIP install, and the name of the package.
PAUL: Perfect.
PAUL: So, first of all, before starting the part, okay, so I want you guys to focus on the package versions, it's important, because, if you look into… okay, so I told you, like, in the last 2 months, there have been…
PAUL: A lot of updates in the LanChain community. Okay, so if you look… so, like, previously, in most of the batches that we have been dealing with, is basically the version, 0.3.27, or something like this, 24, okay, major versions. But right now, we'll be focusing much
PAUL: More on 1.0.5.
PAUL: Okay? So, this is a major version that we'll be working with. Okay, so if you're working with the latest one, this is also fine, but yes, 10.5 will be our major one at any point of time, okay? So, please be sure that for our entire course, we'll be using LangChain version 1.0.5, because this is the latest one.
PAUL: Public. Now… Coming to other packages.
PAUL: Okay, so let's open the Lanshan docs.
PAUL: Alright, so this is a Langchen documentation, okay? Recently, the documentation has changed a lot, okay? So, and very specifically, as we'll be working with Python, so this will be your main go-to guide, okay? Because right now, here, a lot of things are not there. Okay, I feel that
PAUL: the entire documentation has not been updated, okay? Probably the community is working with respect to a few other packages also, but this will be your main one. So right here, all the main things, like regarding installation.
PAUL: Okay, so, how to do the installation of the major packages, okay, like, paper install Langchain, all those things are available. At any point of time, like, we'll be working with a lot of inbuilt functions from Langchain, okay, different classes, okay? So, simply, you can come to this documentation, okay, and you can explore things much more.
PAUL: Because here, yes, examples are there.
PAUL: But I feel that, yes, it's getting updated. Okay, because a lot of things have been migrated from the older version to the new version. So that's why that migration phase, so little bit of documentation updates, I feel that it's a little bit slow.
PAUL: So, right now, this was the main one. Okay, so if you want to upgrade your Langchen, you can use an hyphen capital U, okay, or simply, like, upgrade also works. You can write upgrade.
PAUL: So, the first step was to install the package, which we have already done, okay? Now, let's come to, like, why Langdan, very specifically.
PAUL: Okay, now this particular question can come to your mind. Why?
PAUL: So, first of all, like, in Langshan, what are the major things? Like, it is a completely open source.
PAUL: And if you look into the number of starts in GitHub, simply, like, a lot of starts, I think it's more than 30K.
PAUL: Okay, so… or close to 30K, I think, LanChain PetHub.
PAUL: So, right now, okay, more than 120K, actually. I think Lama was there. That. So, now you can see right from here, it has been accepted by the community. So, majorly, like, a lot of developers are there.
PAUL: Okay, and right now, used by 273K, and you can see, it means that it has been widely used for the past, I can say, 2.5 years, very specifically, this particular project.
PAUL: So, similarly, like, this will be our main, I can say.
PAUL: all the code for language is available in GitHub. So any point of time, if you feel that I want to go in-depth for a particular module, or if you want to change anything, okay, you can always do the contribution for this one.
PAUL: So, let's start now. Okay, by, why it is good, first of all, lesser amount of code. The idea is that to focus much more on the AI functionalities, rather than building the functionalities.
PAUL: Okay, or basically to, build the entire infrastructure. Similarly for deep learning libraries also. For example, if anybody is working with Torch, okay, Torch has really made your life very, very easy.
PAUL: But previous to that, it was, like, back in 2016 and 17, when we were working with Chainer, okay, which is a fundamental, TensorFlow, okay, previous to that.
PAUL: there were a lot of problems. It means that to build everything, you need to write code from scratch. Okay, so similarly, this is a high-level library, you just need to make some calls, okay, to some very specific classes, and based on that, okay, it makes your life much easier.
PAUL: So, for example, if you want to work with any type of PDFs, I think, one example that I have kept it
PAUL: With respect to PDF loading.
PAUL: So… I think somewhere I have…
PAUL: Okay, and one important thing, you need the API key also. Jet, there will be a file.env.example, it's very, very important. Before proceeding or starting our discussion, I want you guys to set up your LLM.
PAUL: I will be using OpenAI, so you can use, your selection, whichever you want to use. So please check, this will be a file.
PAUL: Okay, so, like, OpenAI key. So, majorly in this course, I'll be always using OpenAI.
PAUL: Okay, always I'll be using OpenAI, so don't ask me why you don't use others. It's my personal choice, so similarly, you have your choice, so based on that, you can do the selection. If you want to go for Gemini, a Gemini configuration has been provided. If you want to work with that, that is also fine.
PAUL: Okay? So, most of the times, I'll be working with
PAUL: OpenAI. Like, more than 90% of the times.
PAUL: Okay, because majorly, most of the organizations was going up. Probably, they might use Azure OpenAI, but at the end of the day, the model comes from OpenAI only. Okay?
PAUL: So, any other selections that you want to do, so based on that, you can always customize the existing code, okay, only for the LLM section, because there will be a section in the code that you need to modify if you want to work with some others, okay?
PAUL: So…
PAUL: The first thing that you have to pass here… okay, so in this particular example, I need you guys to create your OpenAI keys and your Gemini key. Two keys, always keep it handy, okay? So, from here, you will be getting your OpenAI keys. So, there is a platform caller, platform.
PAUL: Okay.op platform… yes.openai.com.
PAUL: Okay. Do you guys need to log in here? You need to create your accounts?
PAUL: Okay, so generally, like, I do, I can say, I do refill credit SKUs to $6 or $7. I think that that will be more than enough for this course.
PAUL: Okay, so similarly, you can…
PAUL: Fill up your credits. Okay, otherwise, for now, you can use the Gemini version, so the Google AI Studio.
PAUL: Okay, so here, I think under API keys.
PAUL: Okay, so here you will be getting the option of API keys under your dashboard section. Okay, so this also you can use.
PAUL: Because I think, my Google AI Studio, I have not paid the bill for this one. Okay, because again, like, I need to have a check on the billing part.
PAUL: Because this is a paid account that I have, so no billing is there.
PAUL: Okay, alright. Fine. So, like, whichever you want to use, you are… you can use. So, one is the AIStudioGoogle.com, I am sharing the link.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: And the other one is Platform OpenAI.
PAUL: I think you guys are smart enough to create the accounts.
PAUL: I think…
PAUL: You guys can do it. So simply, like, in my case, already it's there, and very specifically with respect to the different models which are available. Okay, so let me just show you.
PAUL: Okay, so you can just click on this settings in OpenAI, and you can go to the API key section, okay? From the API key section, you can actually look into all your API keys. So, here I have multiple API keys.
PAUL: So, similarly, you can also create your own API key, and with respect to billing part, this also, like, I do have a balance right now, you can see, close to $2. Okay, so if I feel, I can simply, like, generally, for this course, I feel that you need
PAUL: Less than $5.
PAUL: Okay, so simply you can do that particular, if you want, OpenAI. Otherwise, you can use your own custom LLM, I have nothing to worry about that, okay? It's your personal choice. LLM selection is always a personal choice.
PAUL: So, it's not like that you have to use the same one. It's totally up to you. So, Google AI Studio, this you can use.
PAUL: For now, these two are my major ones, because right now in the market, there are so many LLM providers, so whichever you want to use, and just be sure it is available with LandChain, because there can be that you are using a very specific provider, but it is not available in your LandChain.
PAUL: Okay? So, just be sure about that.
PAUL: So, with respect to integrations, okay, so I'm just showing you, for example, if you want to work with OpenAI,
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Okay, so, for example, here, if I'm talking about…
PAUL: Okay, so here you can see.
PAUL: In the documentation, they have provided the major providers. Like, I prefer Anthropic and OpenAI much more, then comes Google, then there is AWS, Hugging Face, Microsoft, Olama, Grok, whichever you prefer.
PAUL: Okay, because in today's class, I won't be using Olama, probably in the next Saturday. With respect to local LLMs, I'll be picking up Olama also.
PAUL: Okay, so similarly, you can see, like, there are different classes, okay, like Chat OpenAI, Azure Chat, OpenAI directly. Okay, then comes this one, OpenAI embeddings, Azure Embeddings.
PAUL: So, similarly, like, most of the times, I'll be working with OpenAI embeddings, if I'm creating any embedding, or it can be Gemini also, so that is also fine. So, if you go into the Google section, so directly you can see Google Generate DBI, so you can use this particular package also.
PAUL: So it's totally upon you, like, which LLM you want to. I don't want to do any restriction, you have to use only this one for this course. Just be sure you always look into the documentation, and based on that, you update it.
PAUL: Yes, if you already have a key, you can use that. Just be sure you have some credits, and Gemini have some limits. Okay, if you have… if you're using the free version, that's the only thing.
PAUL: Alright, so, what you can do, so once you have your API keys, okay, you need the .env file.
PAUL: Okay, so in my case, I have my.env file, so I've given you this example. So, you just need to create your and copy the stuff, like, once you have pasted your key here.
PAUL: Okay, so for example, like, SKY, whatever the key, and here, once you have pasted this key, okay, then just copy this entire thing, okay, and you can create a new file.
PAUL: Okay, create a new file and give it a name, like .env. In my case, already I have the ENV, so I'm not creating it. But I hope you get the point.
PAUL: I'll be loading all the environment variables from this particular file.
PAUL: You can use any one. Okay, it's not required that you use both.
PAUL: But I feel that, yes, you can keep it. One is saved, one is paid, that's why.
PAUL: Okay, so please do this particular configuration. If you're using some other API key, so based on that, please update this .env file. For example, if you're working with Croc, okay, or AgileChat, or TrinAI, okay, or probably some other providers, like Nebius is there.
PAUL: Samba Nova is there. So, so many providers are there. So, simply, based on that, always update the API key for that particular API service, and just be sure you are connected with your LandChain module.
PAUL: Alright, so… Right now, so if I want to just go through this tip… Sure. Langchain, okay?
PAUL: A final… Okay, shows I have written, sorry. It's show, yeah.
PAUL: So, right now, as you can see here, the environment does very specifically. Okay, because… This environment, 0.3.27.
PAUL: Okay, alright. Okay, this is, I think, the default when I need to change my virtual environment. Because of that, I am having this problem. So I always check my virtual environment before starting my work, okay? So I will just do a deactivate.
PAUL: There it is, and then… RM hyphen graduates.
PAUL: Alright, and let me activate my actual environment that I'll be using for this class, which is that .vnvStore.
PAUL: Okay, and here I can do an… You will capture luncheon.
PAUL: Mmm, this is the same one.
PAUL: Just, guys, because I can do a… You rip it.
PAUL: I'll bleed.
PAUL: How can you just let me upgrade the version of Langchen, just wait.
PAUL: I'm just upgrading. The idea is to use the latest one. If I get errors, the idea is to resolve it, because I know all the code that I have done, it's majorly in 3.2.7 if some migration is required.
PAUL: Okay, so… Okay, sorry.
PAUL: Installer, I forgot. That's great.
PAUL: Alright, majorly, right now, most of the things have been updated. Alright, so now I will start with the execution part.
PAUL: I hope that your environment's variables are set in your .env file. Okay, and let's start with the introduction and the fundamentals.
PAUL: So, first of all,
PAUL: Okay, so, like, why Langchain and why it is useful, we'll be talking about the Langchain's modular architecture, what are the core concepts, like document chain, LCL, how to set up your main environment, okay?
PAUL: And, like, if you try to compare LandChain with traditional ML pipelines.
PAUL: So, first of all, it's completely open source, accepted by a lot, a big community of more than 120K, I can say, used by more than 270K plus developers, okay?
PAUL: and all the major LLMs that you feel that, okay, so they always have the integration with your lancher. Okay, whether it's OpenAI, whether it's Anthropic, Amazon, Majorly, all the LLMs.
PAUL: Okay, now, imagine you want to build a chatbot, okay, that can simply answer questions about your company's PDF documents. It means that, some type of private data, okay, or basically some type of external data sources.
PAUL: Okay, searching through your database, remember, previous conversation, okay, calling external APIs, which are… which can be referred as tools. Okay, so we'll be going through tools also.
PAUL: Now, without Lansion, what is the major problem? Write code to load and parse PDF. It means that manually you have to look for a package.
PAUL: Okay, like, here is just one line. Within… you write one line and everything will be done. But if you're writing everything custom, okay, it can be more than, like, 50 to 60 lines of code. So because of that, we feel that, at the end of the day, the main task is about just reading the PDF.
PAUL: Okay? So, LangChain makes it very, very lean.
PAUL: So, similarly, it's not only about Langchain, okay? There are many other libraries. So, in your course, there is a very specific module about parsing, data parsers.
PAUL: Okay, there I'll be talking about major, like, 3-4 packages, which is widely used in the industry. For now, we are starting with Lanching, but there are something better also, because this is the initial learning point for us.
PAUL: Then convert text to embeddings. This is one of the major tasks. So, for this, we need an embedding model.
PAUL: Then comes store embeddings in a vector database. So, yes, we'll be setting up, like, open source vector databases for now. Implementing semantic search, then formatting prompts for the LLM. So, previously, like, in yesterday's class, many of you asked, like, what are prompts? Today, I'll be showing you the example for that.
PAUL: then handle LLM API calls. So, as you will be passing your API key in the .env file. Through that, we will be connecting, okay?
PAUL: And later on, through the specific class, like the OpenAI, or the Langshan, Google Gemini package, we'll be making API calls to a specific model.
PAUL: So, probably, like, it can be GPT 3.5, it can be GPT-4.2, it can be GPT, simply, like, 5 nano.
PAUL: Any model that you want to select, which is available.
PAUL: And finally, like, using Langchain, you can maintain conversation memory also. So, a lot of features that comes inbuilt. So, for developers, it becomes much more easier. The idea is not to do everything from scratch, it's, the components are available, you just need to connect them.
PAUL: That is one of the best things.
PAUL: So, simply abstractions, in simple terms, it means that high-level code. Everything here is high-level code. Majorly, you have to just call the class, and using… within that class, there will be a certain function, which will be responsible to invoke certain type of operations.
PAUL: Then comes the concept of chains. So, chains are basically when you try to perform 3 to 4 different operations in one shot. Okay, so I'll be showing you an LCL example. It means that in one shot, you want to do 3 to 4 different operations.
PAUL: So this is really good. It means that, sequentially, like, step 1, step 2, step 3, step 4, step 5, so all the things that can be done. So, that is referred to as a change. It means that, step by step, tasks will be completed.
PAUL: And, generally, it is done using a pipe operator. Okay, so there will be a pipe operator in the code I'll be talking about. So for now, these are things that we have written in high level, but once we start coding, things will be much more clear. Then comes the concept of agents. Okay, so yes.
PAUL: Right now, in the recent version of LanChain, we have seen that, okay, they have kept it much more, like, agent-focused.
PAUL: Okay, because most of the examples in their recent documentation, they have kept it, much more towards, like, agentic part.
PAUL: But, like, LanChain Core module, the idea is that in LanChain, there is the other package, which is referred to as the LanChain Core.
PAUL: Okay, Langchen-core. This comes, like, pre-installed when you are actually doing the installation of LanChain. Okay, but yes, this is the core package. So, we will be right now focusing much more on the LanChain core part. You have to understand. So, like, LanChain, if you install Langchen, by default, it comes with that.
PAUL: Okay, but what are the core functionalities of LangChain Core? We'll be focusing much more on this one.
PAUL: Because in Langchain, there are a lot of modules, really, guys. Okay, but for now, the core module, the core part, the heart of Langchain, that we'll be focusing on.
PAUL: And, with respect to just wait…
PAUL: I'm just showing you one example, okay, so probably, like, text letters.
PAUL: Okay, so, like, for example, like, chunkers, tech splitters, retrievers, okay, all these major modules, okay, that you have, all this comes under very specifically, like,
PAUL: Under the core concepts, okay, because for this also, there is a very specific package that you need to install, and these all comes pre-installed, so if you actually look into the land chain releases, so from here, you will get better ideas from GitHub.
PAUL: actually, what are the different type of releases that they do? So, like, you can see, if you are using the OpenEN with Langchen, then this is the package, okay? Then, this is the Langchen version, okay? So, recent updates, then the core updates, as you can see here.
PAUL: This is the core module that you have. So right now, in today's class, we'll be focusing much more towards the core module, the text splitting module, okay, few vector DB modules, okay? Then LLM modules.
PAUL: I hope everybody has done. Okay, now I will start with the code execution part.
PAUL: Okay, so these are the major modules that we'll be discussing today. Okay, document loaders, text splitters.
PAUL: embedding models.
PAUL: vector stores, retrievers, prompts, okay, and finally, LLMs. So this becomes your entire chain, the things that we have been discussing. And all these things will be connecting it through
PAUL: a chain operation. It means that this will be called, this will be called, this will be called, this will be called. A step-by-step operation. That will be connecting everything through a chain. So that's why that name comes, like, LAN chain.
PAUL: So, when I'll be showing you the practicals, then you will be understanding that through a pipe operator, you can actually execute multiple operations, okay? But for now, this is the core part.
PAUL: And, if you look here, I have kept just the package structure of Langshan, because really, when you are working.
PAUL: You have to be sure that your packages are compatible with another package. It means that your Langchen core should be compatible with your LangChain OpenAI. Your LangChain community should be compatible with your text pedals.
PAUL: Okay, if there is no compatibility, or some type of compatibility issues during installation, okay, it means that you need to resolve that.
PAUL: The idea is that it should always be compatible, okay? And right now, as you can see, we are using LangChain 1.0+. It means that it can be 5, it can be 7. Okay, so we are directly using the latest version.
PAUL: And these are a few example imports that I have kept. Like, if you want to read any type of document. So, then comes your… this document module.
PAUL: Okay, then comes, like, here also you can see loaders are there very specifically. Loaders are basically, like, document loaders. It can be TXT, it can be Markdown, so different type of loaders that comes here. Then comes your vector stores.
PAUL: Okay? Then comes your OpenAI package. Now, using this package, it helps you to connect with the OpenAI platform. Then you have text splitters. So, this text splitters is actually, like, one of the major ones that we'll be going through today.
PAUL: Now, let's start with the
PAUL: first execution, okay? So, right now, as you can see here, I have executed the first piece of code. So, the idea is to check the Python version, okay, and that version that we have already checked.
PAUL: You don't need to remember this by heart, at least the idea is that when you go through, you understand the basics.
PAUL: Because these things might change after one year, okay? So, really, the imports can change. It totally depends upon the release, so you don't need to remember, but at least what we do remember, that, see, previously, like, if you're working in Lansion one year back, like, text splitters, there was not a separate module.
PAUL: Okay, then, language and core. This module was there, but a lot of things were not there, which has been added now. So, the idea is that at least you should know the main one, like, core, what is their inside core, what is their inside community.
PAUL: Okay, because the list of packages are ready, guys, when I say it's more than, like, what's…
PAUL: more than 100 packages of Lanchen are there. I'm just talking about the major ones.
PAUL: Okay, because when you try to use different vector databases, for every vector database, there will be a Langshan package.
PAUL: Okay, it means that Langchain Quadrant, Langchain ChromaDB. Okay, so Langchain, like, any others that you can think about, Milverse. So, similarly, like, for every vector database there is, for every LLM integration there is. So, the number of packages in Langchain are really, really…
PAUL: A lot you cannot remember, so based on your work, always try to search which package is there.
PAUL: Okay? So, just let me know the code sale is getting executed, and you can see somewhere something like this.
PAUL: that the Python version is compatible.
PAUL: Yes?
PAUL: Yes, Python 3.12 will be fine. The idea is that you should have something more than 3.9, so this is basically a system check that I have kept it for everyone.
PAUL: kernel selection, do the kernel selection, just click here, and select the kernel.
PAUL: As simple as that.
PAUL: Yes, you can do an UV sync also, that also works in HC, Narula. There is no issues in that. The idea is that your package management, it's totally up to you how you handle. If you want to use UV, use UV. Otherwise, use Conda. Otherwise, use…
PAUL: the pure VNB package from Python. It's totally up to you.
PAUL: Alright, now… Let me just…
PAUL: execute this one. So, this is my second cell. So, the first cell, I think, this piece of code, do I need to discuss?
PAUL: Please let me know in the chat, or you guys are able to understand. Because this is pure Python, there is no AI written in this piece of code.
PAUL: Okay?
PAUL: It's a simple system check, we are checking the Python version and those stuff, okay?
PAUL: Now, coming to our second one. So, this is a version check of Langshan, very specifically, that we have done.
PAUL: Okay, so import Langchain, and from Langchain core, import the specific version. So, like, there is a very specific import section. Okay, from that, I am actually looking into what is the version that we have for Langchain, the core version. So, right now, I am sure that, yes, I'm using Langchain 1.
PAUL: If you're using an older version, simply this else statement, please upgrade LANCHIN, so it will be shown in your output.
PAUL: Okay, so if somebody's using an old version, as simple as that. So, this is basically a check.
PAUL: The idea is, at any point of time, when I'll be showing you, there will be always a lot of checks. Okay, so using… because the idea is to keep more print statements in the initial classes. Like, later on, I'll be reducing the print statements, okay? The idea is that the readability should be much more.
PAUL: Okay, so step 2, import Lancer and check the version, which we have already done.
PAUL: Now, in the next step, okay, we'll be loading our environment variables. Very, very important, because here we have passed in the .vnv very specifically, okay? So, like, this is my environment variable. Now, the idea is that this environment variable should be available to our environment.
PAUL: Okay, so for that, I'm using a package, python.env.
PAUL: one of the major packages which is widely used, or you can use the old format of export also, okay? I don't prefer using export a lot, rather than I prefer using it in script.
PAUL: Okay, so this is the package which is responsible to load your
PAUL: environment variables, and very specifically, the environment variables of the LLM, the API keys that I have inside our .env file, to load them. So, very specifically, I'm doing this. So, once I do this load.env, see, it will be loaded into this current environment that I have.
PAUL: Okay? And then simply os.getenv. So, from our environment, I'm looking for this particular API key, which I have inside my .env. Okay, so I can print this key that, yes, it is found. Else.
PAUL: API key not found. Okay, so simply, it will say, create a .env file with this particular OpenAI API key. As simple as that. Similarly, for Google API key, also, I have done the same thing. So, pretty much, this is standard boilerplate, because till now, it's pure Python.
PAUL: I have… this is nothing related to Langchen that we have done.
PAUL: I think everybody agrees.
PAUL: I'm using, right now, OpenAI, because I think my Gemini key doesn't work for me.
PAUL: I was getting some type of error when I checked the API key in the morning, that's it.
PAUL: Alright, so… can we move ahead in the next step? Because, see, everything is written in this notebook, okay? Even if you don't need to listen the lecture, if you just go through the notebook, the core things you can directly cover, okay?
PAUL: Now the first chain, okay, and now the idea is…
PAUL: Creating document. Okay, so we will start with the most basic part, okay? Like, how to create a document.
PAUL: So, there is a document class inside the Lanching Core module.
PAUL: Okay? Everybody please focus and don't tell me that I am having this particular issue right now. Okay, I'll be looking into the issues once we have discussed this, okay? I'll be taking everything in doubt.
PAUL: Okay? So, simply… You can skip the chats for now, I'm… I won't be looking into that.
PAUL: So…
PAUL: First of all, so you have to understand that if you want to create a document, okay, now this document, if you ask me what is the type of this particular document, this is a lan chain document, okay? The default Langchain document class, using that, you can create any type of document.
PAUL: So, right here, see, using this particular class, I'm creating this
PAUL: Okay, and then comes your page content. So, really, guys, we don't use this document class a lot. Rather than we use, like, PDFs, JSON, CSVs, those things we use much more. But, in Langstrain, there is a feature that you can create a document using this particular document class.
PAUL: Okay? So, inside this document, now, what will be the content? Because within… when you are actually creating a document, inside that, you need to pass some type of content. So, that is basically the page content that you have. Okay? And then, see, here, with respect to the different types of metadata.
PAUL: Okay, so this is the core page content, and then comes your metadata. So what is metadata?
PAUL: Anybody? What is metadata? Because this is a pretty much common term, it's not related to AI.
PAUL: about data.
PAUL: Metadata is about data.
PAUL: information about the… Document or the file that you can think about.
PAUL: Okay? Additional information.
PAUL: Very specifically, if I talk about, okay, so these are additional information.
PAUL: Okay?
PAUL: It means that, in the PDF, you always have, for example, I'm taking the core content, okay? And with respect to your metadata, if I'm talking about, it's always about, you can think.
PAUL: the X frame formation, for example, the path that you have, so when you do about a particular file, okay, so it gives you much more.
PAUL: So, metadata is very, very important. Why I feel metadata is important going forward, whenever you are building your rack, you have to do a different type of operations.
PAUL: Okay? So, for example, if you want to do a filtering operation, okay, metadata is very, very useful. So, you can keep information like the total number of chunks of a document.
PAUL: So really, like.
PAUL: the metadata in our… most of the times, like, for every chunk, I have a metadata, okay? And for every chunk, I maintain a very huge metadata, because the most robust and vibrant is your metadata, okay? For later phases, it becomes much easier for me to do any type of operation.
PAUL: It can be filtering and other stuff also, but that is the main task.
PAUL: So, you should always maintain your metadata, like, for every document, whether it's for one PDF, two PDF, so now metadata can be created by LLM also, or manually you can create a custom metadata class, those things we'll be talking about later on. But the poor idea was that whenever we are creating a document.
PAUL: Okay, we always create a metadata, okay? So, right now, let me just execute this.
PAUL: Okay, so this is the main content that we have, okay, and inside the metadata, I've, taken that, okay, the source is introduction.txt, the author is Langchain team, and the date is, like, 25-115, something like that. As simple as that. Okay, and this is the source…
PAUL: file. The idea source always refers to a particular file. So, most of the time, the source will be the actual file path.
PAUL: Okay, like, slash, slash, slash, and then file.txt or file.json.
PAUL: Source, most of the time, just refers to the actual file path, or you can keep it, like, absolute path or relative path, totally up to you. Metadata can be defined by you, so it's not necessary, okay? The idea is that you should keep a lot of information in metadata.
PAUL: Because actually, if your metadata is big, it becomes problem at a certain stage.
PAUL: Okay, and to make the entire metadata for your entire vector DB,
PAUL: Okay, like, somehow a little bit tedious task. Yes, it can be done, you can update the entire metadata, or your entire vector database, but I feel that a little bit tedious. It's better when you are actually creating the vector databases, or basically when you are uploading your embeddings.
PAUL: Okay, for every chunk, you should have a particular metadata, okay? So, just for now, if I show…
PAUL: Use something like this, okay?
PAUL: In which ID I have, I have to just remember, just wait. If I show you some type of metadata information.
PAUL: Okay. Some broad level, at least, so that you guys get an idea with respect to metadata, how…
PAUL: We can maintain it.
PAUL: So, a sample example I will show you, which will help you to get an idea.
PAUL: That in broad, actually, how can happen.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: I'm just logging into the vector database, so just once I get that metadata page, I will share the screen with you.
PAUL: Right now, there is no file permission and other stuff. That is always level.
PAUL: whoever is asking this question. Right now, the idea is to simply create a document. This is a simple document which has been created.
PAUL: in memory, and even I have not saved it anymore.
PAUL: Okay, now I'm just showing a sample metadata so that you guys can get an idea exactly what is going on, okay? So right now, like, for every chunk, so this is, like, one of my chunks that I have, for that I keep, like, category, chunk ID, chunk index, chunk text, okay, chunk tire, complexity level.
PAUL: Content length, feature tags, okay, file name, file type, GitHub URL, has code examples. Now, you can see, this is pretty much
PAUL: Okay, so a vibrant one. The idea is to add more and more information about that particular chunk, okay, from which file it has been taken. So, it actually gives me a lot of ideas. So, the idea is that when you are working, just be sure, okay, so you have a very good metadata.
PAUL: Because at the end of the day, metadata really plays a very, very crucial role.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Now, the next stuff, okay, so let's…
PAUL: Get back, okay. Now, this file that we are creating, okay, it's a simple document class file.
PAUL: Okay, it means that here, when I executed something, okay, very specifically here, so you can see that none where this file got created.
PAUL: Okay, so no file that got created here very specifically. So, this is the default document class using which you can create documents in Langshan, as simple as that. Okay, so this is nothing related with respect to file formations, or saving it in local, okay?
PAUL: There is nothing. It's a simple document class using which you can create the default documents in Lancer.
PAUL: Now, similarly, you can create multiple documents. So, as you can see, using the same, document.
PAUL: class. I'm just calling, like, the same stuff. Page content, metadata for this is document 1, document 2, document 3. At any point of time, if you feel that you want to create some custom documents, okay, which we rarely true to say, like, rarely we do it.
PAUL: This is just for beginners, that yes, we can create documents directly inside Langchen, but most of the time, it will be external sources like PDFs, JSON, and other stuff.
PAUL: Okay, so here you can see, like, document 1, content, category, difficulty, Document 2, you have content, okay? Then category I, okay, then all those things that we have very specifically mentioned. So the idea was to print out the content with the metadata. That we have done very specifically.
PAUL: Let me know that, is this part clear? Because this, using this default document class, you can create just LanChain default docs. Okay, but don't think about these docs as, like, some type of extension files.
PAUL: these files are not even saved, okay? It's only in runtime.
PAUL: Okay, if I close this, it means that the document is gone. It's pretty much runtime stuff.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Alright, so this part is done, okay.
PAUL: Now, I told you that this Langchen, okay, LCA, it is referred to as the Langchen Expression Language, okay, and it makes our life easier. It means that, there is some type of input, okay, and in between that, there are different components, like Component 1, Component 2, Component 3.
PAUL: Now, most of the times in Python, what happens? Okay, like, you have to first call this, then call this, then call this.
PAUL: Okay, so in Lanshin, these guys, they have basically, built a way, okay, using the pipe signal, this pipe.
PAUL: So, what happens, like, you can introduce and bring your own component. It can be any component. Like, using LCL, you can connect any type of line-chain component. So, I feel that this is, for a beginner level, this is one of the easiest tasks.
PAUL: Okay, it means that I'll be showing you when I'll be doing the execution, but this is a simple example. It means that you can execute multiple tasks.
PAUL: directly in one shot. Like, you can see component 3, then Component 2, then Component 1. So, this is the old way of using LCL.
PAUL: Okay, like, before LCL, this is much more the Pythonic way, so one call inside that, another call inside that, another call, okay, and then your actual input that comes. So, with LCL, it becomes much easier, and it's a much more cleaner format, okay? So, this is just language and expression language. You have to understand.
PAUL: This is very specific to Langchain. With other frameworks, it won't work. So, whenever you are creating any type of chains, so the simple example is, like, you will be creating a chain, and you will be adding components, like, okay?
PAUL: I want probably some type of data ingestion stuff, then probably some type of vector debit stuff, probably some embedding stuff, okay? And I want to combine all the tasks that in one shot, they will be executed. So, because of that, this particular chain. I feel that in Pythonic way also you can do it, there is no restriction of using pure Python, but this is less amount of code.
PAUL: Okay, using less amount of code, you can do the same stuff.
PAUL: So that's why I feel that this chain that you have, today we'll be talking about chain. So, using chain, the idea is that you can call multiple components in one shot using this pipe operator. So, whenever you look into a pipe.
PAUL: and you see a chain, it means that we are using the LCL, the Land Chain Expression Language.
PAUL: And this is very, very respective with respect to chain calling. So, whenever you will be seeing some type of LCL expression, which is this pipe operator, this pipe operator, okay, is one of the major, I can say, lanchan expressions.
PAUL: which is widely used with respect to chains. So, what is a chain? Chain is basically a combination of multiple tasks, okay, or basically component, that will be called in one shot.
PAUL: So, what is the meaning of invoke?
PAUL: I think everybody knows the meaning of invoke.
PAUL: Yes, standard, the idea is to invoke a function, it can be, okay, a simple call or an execution in separate terms. So when you call that particular chain, all these things will be…
PAUL: executed in one shot. So, this is the purpose.
PAUL: And later on, I'll be talking about that.
PAUL: In LCL, you have a lot of supports, like streaming, batch processing, async support, okay, debugging, type safety, and other things. So, later on, when we'll be talking about LCL, okay, I'll be coming to these things also.
PAUL: So, first of all.
PAUL: Okay, so this is a simple example that I have kept it, okay, just to, tell you, okay, that, using… there is one concept with respect to runnables and langchain. Okay, and this runnables is very specific with respect to LCL only, okay?
PAUL: Now, what I'm doing, this is a runnable lambda. How many of you have idea about lambda functions?
PAUL: lambda functions.
PAUL: What are lambda functions?
PAUL: anonymous functions, correct, okay? Don't think about AWS lambda functions, guys, okay?
PAUL: Yes, pretty much, yes. Here, it's pretty much anonymous functions, okay?
PAUL: So, the idea was that they have brought that, through Lambda here much more, okay? And here, right now, 3 type of functions that have been created, okay? So, let me know that
PAUL: This particular format is fine for everyone, because here, very specifically, we are using type printing.
PAUL: So you guys are comfortable with type anything, please let me know.
PAUL: Yes, the idea is, hey, because everything I cannot teach you in one day. The idea is that you guys should be familiar with Pydantic.
PAUL: Okay, so, like, the idea is that
PAUL: From the past 2 years, the entire Python world is using Pyth and Tick.
PAUL: Okay, so this is the Pyntic data validation at any point of time. Okay, so little bit you should know. If you don't know, then just be sure that
PAUL: At least you explore and spend at least 30 minutes on this particular module. Because I have not used widely pytentic, I thought about keeping it much more simple, but yes, a form of data validation that we have kept it, using type hinting much more.
PAUL: So that's why at any point of time when we'll be looking into the code, a lot of restrictions will be there. It means that it, like, anything cannot be passed.
PAUL: So, very specifically, you can see text STR through type hinting, I mentioned. The output of this function will always be a string. So, similarly, like, adding the prefix. So, as you can see, this function takes a string, and the output will also be a string, then adding emojis.
PAUL: Okay. Now, here, what I have done, I have created just 3 simple functions. One is the uppercase function, convert text to uppercase, then adding a prefix to the text, okay, and adding an emoji. So, 3 simple functions that I have done.
PAUL: Okay, now he…
PAUL: Now, all these components, so I can say that these three functions are just, like, 3 different components for now, or 3 different type of test text operation that I'm doing. Okay, really, it's not an operation, it's simple, pretty much print statements, but the idea is that I'm making some type of function call.
PAUL: Okay? Now, I need to bind these functions into a runnable.
PAUL: Okay? So that's why this runnable lambda that comes, and here I'm just passing the name of the functions. Uppercase.
PAUL: Okay, add prefix and add emoji, okay? And this becomes your main object, okay? So, object of the class runnable, and I will be directly calling these particular objects inside the chain. So what I've done? I've created a chain, and you can see, okay, so this is the object for this particular function.
PAUL: Okay? Like, runnable lambda, and the function is uppercase. Then, similarly, prefix, the other component, then the emoji. The idea is to execute three things in one shot, okay?
PAUL: Now, here, this is the main one. Okay, chain.invoke. So, this, from here, you'll be getting the major output, okay? Now, here you can see the final output is result hello, luncheon.
PAUL: So, in the invoking part, the text that I have provided, okay, what was the text?
PAUL: the input that I am doing. It is basically Hello Langchain. This is the actual input. Just remember, always, like, the print statements are there so that it becomes easier for you to understand. Otherwise, there is no purpose of using statements.
PAUL: Okay, so as we are in our initial classes, so I'm using a lot of print statements, but always focus on this one, whenever there will be a placeholder, like, result, because this will be the actual final result that you have.
PAUL: Okay? So, here, with respect to the execution that I have, okay, in the chain, the uppercase, the prefix, and the emoji runnable.
PAUL: Okay, so one by one. First, this emoji runnable. As you can see here, emoji, result that you have. Okay? And then finally, based on that, the output that we are getting, which is the, Hello Luncheon, our actual input, or the text that we have passed.
PAUL: So, step 1, step 2, step 3. All the things that have been added here.
PAUL: Yes, the order matters. Yes, the order matters. So, we always start with the, execution that we'll be getting. So, you can see, so generally, if you remember here, okay, so Component 1 input that you have.
PAUL: So, this component one. So, I know that first component 1 needs to be executed, then component 2 will come, then component 3 will be executed. So, based on that, we only… we're getting the output.
PAUL: First, you are having your emoji part, okay, and then the rest, which is basically the result halochi.
PAUL: Okay, yes, the order matters here. The idea is not because this is pretty much, like, execution.
PAUL: then another execution. So, probably, it can be, like, one function can be taking an input from another function. If you're designing the functions in that way, so yes, it can happen. So, based on that, you have to take it.
PAUL: Similar to Linux Pipe, yes, similar to Linux Pipe, yes, correct, I can say.
PAUL: All right, now this was the basics, the idea was, okay, and later on, actually, how we use it in RAD, we'll be talking about that.
PAUL: Okay, now, a few basic LLM calls, how to make LLM calls. Little bit, I want to talk about that.
PAUL: Because, right now, as you can see, I'm using the chat OpenAI. Very specifically, I'm using the chat OpenAI. Okay, it means that, using the API key, I'll be making the call.
PAUL: Okay, this Kushagra, this is pretty long that you have provided, okay? But yes, in Notion, I am adding.
PAUL: Later on, I will format it. It's for Gemini, I think. Kushagra has shared that part with him.
PAUL: I think I need to make it a code block, but yes, like, very specifically with respect to Gemini, if you are making this, even, like, you can use this piece of code.
PAUL: Good.
PAUL: So, I have added in Notion, you guys can open Notion.
PAUL: Alright, so here, I'm using the Chat OpenAI class. Now, using Chat OpenAI. So, similarly, if you are working with Gemini, okay, so you will be seeing that there will be a package, Langchain Google Gen AI package. Okay, so…
PAUL: Similarly, if you use a different… so, then you need to install a particular package for that. At any point of time, you have to understand, see, this chat will be the same, and then comes your actual… your LLM service provider.
PAUL: So Google Generative AI is the service provider.
PAUL: Okay, the chat options will be there directly. Similarly, if you look into OpenAI here, so chat is there, but what is the service provider of the OpenAI? So, similarly, chat will always be there. After that, it can be Azure OpenAI, OpenAI, okay, or any AWS models that you are using.
PAUL: Okay, so that's how they have built the module. So, in my case, I am using Langshan OpenAI.
PAUL: And then you can see, I will be directly calling this particular class that I have, chat opening. And here are a few parameters. Okay, so right now, I've not kept all the parameters, there is a long list of parameters that you can check. But for now, the core things, two things that comes into mind. Okay, one is basically the model.
PAUL: Okay, now here you can pass different ones. It can be GPT-4, it can be GPT-5,
PAUL: 5.1, 5 nano, all those models. The idea was to pass something cheaper, that's why I'm using 3.5 Turbo, okay? And with that, this is a temperature. Now, this is where the output of the… because you have to understand the output of LLM is not deterministic.
PAUL: If you change this, okay, then again the output will change. You will see that always, so that's why this temperature is something like…
PAUL: The idea is to keep it 0 always, so that we get deterministic outputs, but if you change it, like 0.3, 0.4, 0.5, okay, the idea is it has to be between 0 to 1, so don't think anything the number can be, okay? It has to be between 0 to 1, always.
PAUL: Now, this particular chat open here, okay, so let me just go to the official documentation.
PAUL: Because, you guys should also explore what are the different type of parameters are there.
PAUL: Okay, so if I go here, and if I search here, Chat OpenAI, this is the TypeScript, skip this one. Okay, so you can focus on this one, I think. This is a chat completion.
PAUL: Okay, so OpenAI, Chat OpenAI, yes.
PAUL: Okay, now this is the one that I am using. So, in my case, the Langchen OpenAI package is required. Without this package, you cannot make a call to OpenAI. So, in our case, this is available. What are the features here? You can see tool calling, structured output, image input.
PAUL: Audio… okay, now, image input, if you try to pass.
PAUL: Okay, the LLM needs to have a multimodal support.
PAUL: It's not that every LLM has a multimodal support. Majorly, most of the LLMs have a tech support. But yes, there are LLMs which are having multimodal support also.
PAUL: Now, you can see it cannot take a video input. So, simply, the… you have to install the package.
PAUL: Okay, you have to check that your OpenAI key is available or not.
PAUL: And right now, the idea was to show you these number of
PAUL: I can say parameters, okay? Because right now, I am using the model. You can see here, like, GPT-5 Nano that you guys can use, okay?
PAUL: Then, API key, you don't actually need to pass. I prefer always the API key inside an environment variable file, because this part becomes much more hard-coded. Okay, so I don't love this one. Okay, then comes…
PAUL: Max number of tokens, timeout, stream usage, if you want streaming output in that case. Okay, so these are a few of the major ones that I mentioned.
PAUL: That can be used… okay, so you can always test it out, that how the LLM is performing by playing with these parameters.
PAUL: Alright, so I think it's… What's the time, guys?
PAUL: 10… 30. Do we need a break?
PAUL: 10.30.
PAUL: I don't know, in my system why it's showing 1030, then.
PAUL: It's 10.30 or 10.45, let me check my mobile. Okay, it's 10.45.
PAUL: Then what happened to this? Okay, it got updated, fine.
PAUL: Perfect, it's 10.40, but let's go for a break, okay? And then we will resume.
PAUL: Okay, so let me start the timer, a 10 minutes timer.
PAUL: green… Block, okay?
PAUL: Alrighty guys, so I'll be back in 10.
PAUL: Yes, we will be having the doubt session after the class, don't worry.
PAUL: Alright, guys, so we are back with our discussion.
PAUL: Alright, so, as we were discussing very specifically with respect to an LLM, so when you are connecting an LLM, okay, for example here, I'm showing you for OpenAI. Okay, so here, like, one of the major one is model, then you have temperature, so right now.
PAUL: Here you can see temperature is equal to none, so basically you can set a value. Now, if you want a streaming output, so very specifically for that, the condition can be true. Max tokens, or basically, like, how many tokens that you want to generate.
PAUL: Okay, from the LLM. So you can keep a limit there also. Timeout, okay, reasoning, effort, max retries. It means that in one API call fails, then again, it will try to retry the hit, okay, based on that.
PAUL: And base URL organization, so these are some other parameters based on your OpenAI account that you have. Okay? So, token is just a word. So, based on that max token, it means that the max number of polls that you want to generate.
PAUL: Okay, now, in the next step, okay, let's get back here, because this is the first call that we are making. So, what we have done, we are just using this class. Okay, so, like, I'm using OpenAI, so I'm using Chat OpenAI. If you are working with Probably, I can say, Google Generative AI, then you'll be using this.
PAUL: Chat, Google Generative AI class.
PAUL: Okay? And, based on that, like, whichever model. So, here you can see the model is Gemini 2.5 Flash. Now, this is a Google model.
PAUL: So, similarly, I'm using, like, I think 3.5 Turbo, which is an OpenAI model. So, there's a vast list of models. So, if I go to my OpenAI account, you can always check what are the different type of models that you have.
PAUL: Okay, so I think Chat OpenAI… Did I open?
PAUL: platform.
PAUL: OpenAI, and this is the model section.
PAUL: Inside this model section, okay, so majorly, like, all the models that you have the information, like, 5.1, 5 Nano 5, 5 Mini, 5 Pro, so these are the models that you can use.
PAUL: Some open weight models are also available, so you have to understand, these are open-wit models. It means that it's open source. Okay, you can use it for free.
PAUL: So, very similarly, I'm using the version 3.5. The idea is to go with cheaper versions, O3, a very good model, that I feel, than GPT4.1. So, similarly, you can explore so many type of models are there.
PAUL: Okay, so I'm using one. Okay, you can test it out.
PAUL: And always, if you want to know about, okay, there is a feature of comparing different models.
PAUL: Okay, like GPT-5, you can compare with GPT-4.1 or with 04 Mini. So, you can always get to know the different type of features each model has.
PAUL: Okay, so based on that, and one of the major ones that I always look into, the window size. Okay, so I feel that, yes, the window size is important. Like, if you try to compare GPT-5. Okay, so check the context window here, it's…
PAUL: How much? It's 4 lakh. And if you try to compare here, it's close to 1 million. Here, again, if you try to compare 04 Mini, the contact size is much, like, lower, I can say.
PAUL: Close to 2 lakhs.
PAUL: Okay, so, and the knowledge cut-off date, very, very important. Like, that was the last date, so this is 2024. Okay, so majorly, even the latest models, like the GPT-5 models, you can see the cutoff date is pretty much old, I can say. Okay, like, close to one year back.
PAUL: Okay, so from here, you can always compare, like, which model to get, and what is the pricing. The pricing is the most important thing, and most… for every model, the pricing comes with 1 million tokens.
PAUL: Okay, so 1 million tokens, so based on that, like, 1.25, this is close to $2, this is close to, $1.1, okay, so I can say that, yes, 04 Mini is much more cheaper, because this is a mini version. So, similarly, if you change, this to O3 Pro.
PAUL: Okay, somewhere. Can you see?
PAUL: Right now, the Pro model, $20, so you have to always check the pricing of whichever model that you are selecting. It's not that every model has the same price, okay? So, please always have a check on this one. And always use cheaper models. That is the only thing that I want to suggest.
PAUL: So, something like the Nano version, if I say, I feel that this is good. So, you can see the pricing.
PAUL: So this has…
PAUL: gone a lot. So always use, like, the lighter versions or the cheaper models for this course. Don't pick up something very costly model, and later on you come to me and tell me, Paul, my credits are exhausted. It should not be like that.
PAUL: Okay? So always pick up from the list, always have a look into the list, what are the different things?
PAUL: Alright, so right now, as you can see, like, GBT 3.5 Turbo, okay, now this is also a cheaper one, as compared to others.
PAUL: Alright, so please have a look into the models, similarly for Gemini models also, okay? So, I'm just showing you today, like, Gemini models.
PAUL: This is the Google AI Developers page, okay, and from here, like, 2.5 Pro is one of the best models, then comes 2.5 Flash, a little bit towards the lower side. Okay, and this is the ultra-fast one, Gemini 2.5 Flash Lite.
PAUL: Okay, one of the fastest models, I can say, the cheapest one, that you can work with. These are some older versions, like 2.2, 2.2 Flashlight, these things also that you can play with.
PAUL: Yeah, so always have a look, okay, at any point of time, if you want to know more details, the token limit, everything is available here. The capabilities and other stuff.
PAUL: Okay, so please do a selection based on that. The idea is that don't use a very costly model, always use the cheaper versions.
PAUL: Okay, so here, I'll be making the first LLM call, where I've defined my Chat OpenAI class. Inside that, I've defined which model I will be using. Then, very specifically, temperature zero that I have given. The idea is to get deterministic output.
PAUL: Okay, if I make it, like, 0.30, 0.4, you will see the output will change.
PAUL: So this defines, basically, the creativity of the model. And now, you can see, I'll be invoking, okay, LLM.invoke.
PAUL: Okay, the idea is to make that API call, okay? So once this will be invoked, okay, so I'll be getting the output here, inside the response, okay?
PAUL: So, right now, what is Langchain in one sentence? A simple query that I have kept, which will be going to the LLM, and the response will be captured inside this response video. Okay?
PAUL: So, when I execute this, Okay, now this is an API call, so yes, it will take some time.
PAUL: But it should not take too much time also, okay? But yeah, it depends upon the model thus, that one I have selected, okay? So, for example, if I change the model…
PAUL: Okay, so let's get back… Here…
PAUL: Okay, so if I go with GPT-5 Nano, let me see.
PAUL: That's doable.
PAUL: Only this parameter that needs to be changed if you are changing the model.
PAUL: Okay, now you can see the response came from this much faster as compared to that one.
PAUL: Okay, so similarly, if I change it, okay, so…
PAUL: Here, I'm making it, let's make it two sentence.
PAUL: Okay, sentences… Now I'll be getting two sentences in the output.
PAUL: Okay, so… See, I hear two sentences came.
PAUL: So, in that way, so this is a simple API call. Okay, it means that using your API, you are making a call to the cloud-hosted model in a specific environment, or to a specific service provider.
PAUL: Okay, so I think for everybody, it should work. Please let me know.
PAUL: Yes, the LLM calls.
PAUL: rate limit error. So that is your account issue, nothing that I can do. If it's an auth error, you can try creating a new API key, okay, and then it will be working.
PAUL: Isn't 3.5 deprecated? No, 3.5 is available till now.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Now the same thing if I want to do it, Gemini, okay, because I know a few people might not have that, okay? So, I think Kushagra shared that one. Okay, so what I will do…
PAUL: So, the first thing, you need to have this particular package, okay? I'm going to show for Gemini also today, because going forward, these two will be our major LLM providers.
PAUL: Okay? So, like, okay, first couple, I will be just doing a show operation.
PAUL: Lunch… Hmm…
PAUL: Okay, I am using UV, so I have to add UV before this one.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: All right.
PAUL: So, the one it is upgraded.
PAUL: Because, most of the times after installation, and even, guys, you have to remember you can do the installation from notebook also, okay? So, for example, here, if I want to add a markdown cell, okay? Here, very specifically.
PAUL: called Gemini, if I want to add.
PAUL: Now I will add a code cell here. Okay, so a few code cells, let me add it here.
PAUL: So here, also, I can do this stuff.
PAUL: Okay, so in my case, it's not UV, it's… I have to add UV.
PAUL: You can see the number of packages that got resolved, okay? Now, in the next step.
PAUL: Again, back to Notion. So, this is the main import. Let me check that everything is working fine for this import or not.
PAUL: Okay, so here…
PAUL: Okay, you can see that this is working. Okay, so I know that now the next step is making the API call. So for the API call, so this is basically the selection.
PAUL: That you have.
PAUL: And, the rest of them will be pretty much the same style.
PAUL: So, let's get back here.
PAUL: So, LLM here, I'm selecting Gemini 2.5 Flash.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Now, see, my API was not working, so probably I might get an error, okay? But if your… it is working, okay, it will be working fine.
PAUL: I don't know, like, in the morning I was getting some error with respect to the API. Okay, now I got the…
PAUL: Because I made the API call, so now it's working, probably. There is no issue with that.
PAUL: Okay, so similarly for Gemini, it's the same stuff, you can see just one change.
PAUL: exactly for which LLM service provider you are making it, and the
PAUL: Which LLM is available under that service provider. So right now, the Google one that I am using, very specifically. Rest of the stuff you can see, it's the same piece of code.
PAUL: Just one line change that we have done this one. It's only one line change, and your LLM is changed.
PAUL: Yes, guys?
PAUL: How is the key obtained? I think I have already showed that in the class.
PAUL: Okay, I've already showed that. You have to go to Google AI Studio, get your API key. For Gemini, if you want to use for OpenAI, go to platform.openai.com. From there, you'll be getting that.
PAUL: Authentication errors generally happens when you are passed a wrong API key.
PAUL: Okay, if… see, there are some things that need to be taken care from your side that nothing that I can do, okay? So, let me just highlight those points.
PAUL: That nothing from my side that I can do. One is a rate limit error. It means that your limit has been completed, okay?
PAUL: Then comes, quota exit.
PAUL: Okay, so this also might come for a few. Here, also, that nothing I can do.
PAUL: Auth error, this also. If your API key is correct, it should be working.
PAUL: Okay, so here also that nothing I can do from my end, because it's your own account, so I don't have any control, okay?
PAUL: Because these three things, that needs to be taken care by you.
PAUL: Okay, so, like, authentication error, rate limiter error, quota exit. So, majorly, it can happen. Probably you are… you don't have enough credits in your OpenAI account. That can be one reason. Okay, you need to, like, recharge your account, probably.
PAUL: Okay, and generally, like, there is… under the free quota, there is always restriction.
PAUL: Okay, so that's why, like, there will be a certain limit. So generally, when you create your new accounts, there is always a limit, and that limit gets exhausted very, very quickly.
PAUL: Okay, now after that, like, you need to do a recharge in OpenAI. In Gemini, like, every day, there has a very huge amount of limit. So most of the times, like, most of the students prefer using Gemini.
PAUL: So, it's totally up to you. Now, these 3 things that you need to take care of, because really, like, I can… I don't have access to your account, so I cannot do that much.
PAUL: Alright, so let me know that's Gemini and Lanchan, like, out of these two, anyone that you guys have tested.
PAUL: Yes, 1 million token mills, 1 million words, correct. Mammoth.
PAUL: Gemini is working fine, Gemini on OpenAI tested, tested, tested, tested, okay. For most of you, it's working, it's great. Okay, it means that, see, this is just an external call. Okay.
PAUL: Alright, now let's move to the next part, okay? Now, okay, I have one response already. Now, let's focus on the response object, because this response, okay, now, very specifically, inside this response, I was always looking into the content, but there are other things also.
PAUL: That you can actually look into.
PAUL: Okay, so…
PAUL: Now, see, the metadata that comes from the LLM response, okay, now, this is… this will be different for different LLMs, you have to understand.
PAUL: Okay, now this that I have, you can see the model provider is Google Gen AI.
PAUL: Okay, then the model that I am using, which is Gemini 2.5 Flash. Okay, so now this metadata comes from LLM, it means that you don't generate it. Now, this is the one… okay, so similarly, if I make this one, okay, so again, I will show you the OpenAI one also.
PAUL: Okay, so the idea is that you differentiate exactly.
PAUL: Okay, so finish, reason, stop. So, stop is basically the keyword, it means that the task has been done.
PAUL: Safety ratings, okay? So, right now I am not doing any type of safety rating, or neither I am doing any type of block operation. So it's pretty much, based on that, I'm getting the result, okay? Now I have executed the OpenAI, I will see the metadata will change for OpenAI models.
PAUL: Hmm?
PAUL: It should change… I think I have executed a just wait.
PAUL: I've executed the Gemini one.
PAUL: Okay, this is done. Now let me execute the response method, okay? Now it will be updated. Now, you can see, this part has changed.
PAUL: Total number of token used, okay, the completion tokens, okay, total, how much tokens that was being used. Okay, so this is the completion token, so you can see majorly the completion token that is being caught. Okay, and completion tokens, I want to show you here. Okay, so within…
PAUL: the platform of OpenAI.
PAUL: No mortal is just wait.
PAUL: It's sold… models… Okay, now every model will have its own.
PAUL: Okay, so let's go with text generation, okay? So whenever you want to generate any type of text, okay, so there is a completion call. So, using that completion call, you can actually, so by default, the code uses slash completion route.
PAUL: Okay, for the API to meet that particular call. So that's why, like, you can… if you are using the default package of OpenAI, okay, so then, by default, it always pick up that slash completion route.
PAUL: So that's why it's very, very important. Most of the times, it's completion slash V1, okay? Sometimes it'll get changed to V2, but majorly, that is the route.
PAUL: Okay, through which it has been caught.
PAUL: So you can always look into these things exactly, and these things generally don't change, okay? It's pretty much fixed, always.
PAUL: Okay, so… this part.
PAUL: Okay, now,
PAUL: The next part here, okay, so here, this response metadata is a little bit different as compared to Jimmy.
PAUL: Okay, because Gemini was giving me some other details, but here, it's little bit other details. Okay, system fingerprint, NAM, okay, ID, service tag, default, okay, finish, reason, stop. So, same information, but I feel that OpenAI provides much…
PAUL: more diverse metadata as compared to Gemini models. Okay, within the response.
PAUL: So, sometimes it can be of your use, but really, like, it's not an always useful, because this comes from the LLM, so nothing that you can do. If you want some information from here, that needs to be taken care of, or you can do some type of validation on top of that.
PAUL: Alright, so I hope that, in your case, both the metadata you have checked, and I hope you understood the difference.
PAUL: Now, a little bit about the prompts path that, yes, Gemini doesn't throw you the token usage information. It's OpenAI that throws, okay? Ravi Basai. It's… you were correct. Gemini will not throw that.
PAUL: Alright, so now, coming to prompts. Guys, everybody, now focus on prompts, okay?
PAUL: So, very specifically, in LanChain, you have templates. Okay, so, like.
PAUL: there's, inside the prompts module, you'll be having multiple type of prompt templates. So, one of the most common ones is chat prompt template, okay?
PAUL: Now, using this chat prompt template class, okay, so you can actually pass your prompt, like, this is a prompt, okay? Now, what is the difference between a prompt and a text, in simple terms? So, text is always static. If I write something, okay, so in the text format, like text, okay.
PAUL: My name is Paul, okay? As simple as that. But if I want it to be dynamic, probably this is just, like, a variable, I want it to be dynamic, okay? So…
PAUL: Now, this becomes an instruction that will be passed to the LN. So, like, rather than keeping hard-coded text, okay, most of the times, we do prefer using
PAUL: prompt templates. Okay, so now this prompt template, whatever information that you'll be passing.
PAUL: it goes to the LLM, as simple as that. So, for example, explain topic, okay? Now, this topic is dynamic. It means that this is just a placeholder. Later on, I can make it anything. It can be machine learning, deep learning, urgentic AI. Okay, so pretty much dynamic stuff. During runtime, during the call, I can change it.
PAUL: So it's pretty much a placeholder for now.
PAUL: Okay, so inside this, and this becomes my final prompt, like, explain
PAUL: slash machine learning in simple terms, suitable for beginners. Okay, so similarly, I can change the topic. So, for example, if you're building a simple web app on this one, okay, so in the front end, you can just take the name of the topic, and automatically, this prompt will be invoked, always.
PAUL: Okay, so for example, in the front end, in the UI, somebody is passing machine learning. You'll be getting… explain me, like, machine learning in simple terms, if somebody's passing deep learning. So, pretty much dynamic stuff. So, the idea is that we always use these type of templates. So, these are specific set of rules that we are passing.
PAUL: Okay? A specific set of rules, this particular information, that will be cool.
PAUL: to the LL.
PAUL: Yes, see, right now we don't have any type of query, guys, because I'm not using any data sources or anything. It's just the prompt that I'm passing.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Alright, so this is the prompt that we have defined, okay? And within this prompt, you can see, within this prompt, you will have this message, okay, and then, again, within that prompt, you will be having the template. So, this is the final
PAUL: result that you will be getting. So, exactly what is the information if you want to access it within a prompt. So, this is how you can do. So, this is pretty much nested, I can say.
PAUL: But yes, if you want. So, most of the times, we don't need this particular information, but yes, later on, if you want to have a verification or a check at any point of time, so you can use this.
PAUL: Like, we'll be using this one. In our case, I can say, there was one, website with respect to prompts. Anybody remember it's Promptly, or something like that?
PAUL: Boom.
PAUL: I forgot the name, something like that, it was.
PAUL: Wrong… No, it's not prompt guide. Prompting me… So, something like Liying.
PAUL: Because there were a lot of sample prompts out there. No, no, no, not LinkedIn.
PAUL: Yeah, let me see, because I forgot that name. Sometimes I use that website.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Check the GitHub ones.
PAUL: Because that website was really good.
PAUL: That I felt, okay. This is also, like, with respect to prompt engineering, this is much more… Important…
PAUL: But I forgot it. Later on, when it comes to my mind, I will share that. Okay, so there you have a lot of diverse prompts.
PAUL: But for now, let's get back.
PAUL: Okay, so…
PAUL: Blankchain core components, okay, so this is how you, create a prompt, and that prompt that needs to be.
PAUL: passed, very specifically, okay, to the LLM, through this template. It means that we pass this template to the LLM.
PAUL: Guys, I will check it, because don't write different URLs.
PAUL: Yes, I think it's promptly.fyi… yes, this was the one, actually, I was looking for, yes, Amit Kumar. Thanks.
PAUL: Okay, now this one that, I do use sometimes, okay, so it's based on the task. So I feel that this has a lot of different prompts that actually you can go through, and really, like, I do use it, or manually I can do some tweaking and change it, so really, like, promptly.fyi.
PAUL: Yeah, so really, thanks so much.
PAUL: In the last line of code, mentioned keyword and system, Python code is getting an error. Alright, I'll look into the error, don't worry, few people are having, till now, the installation issues. Fine, I will look into it.
PAUL: Alright, so…
PAUL: Now, this is just the prompt execution, okay? Then comes, okay, so somebody was asking me, explain, runnable sequence, okay? So, just see. Now, again, LCL will come into the picture, so I will repeat once more about the LCL concept that we do use, okay?
PAUL: So under LCL concept, it's pretty much simply binding multiple functions, okay? It links function 1, function 2, function 3.
PAUL: Now, to make anything executable as a chain, it needs to be made runnable lambda.
PAUL: It means that without this particular class, I cannot make a normal function runnable within a chain. So that's why we create the function, we wrap the function inside this runnable lambda class, and then we call it through a chain.
PAUL: As simple as that. First, the function, then the function needs to be binded on the runnable lambda.
PAUL: And then, through the object that we have created for runnable Lambda. So, this is the object for runnable Lambda. That object, we pass it directly in the chain, as simple as that. So you can do multiple executions. It can be 10 functions, 20 functions, 30 functions.
PAUL: Now, I will be using this, particular implementation. Okay, so here, so, I think prompt we have already gone through. The next part that comes is a structured output parser. Okay, so, like, structured output parser, I feel that this is very, very helpful.
PAUL: Okay, the idea is that extract just the text from the response. It means the other stuff, simply, it will ignore. So that's why there is a very specific class in Lanching.
PAUL: And this can also be passed directly, okay, within a chain. So, this is one of the added benefits. It means that once you execute the chain, directly you'll be getting the response.
PAUL: Okay, now this feature is available. It's not like that every, one has this. It's very, very restricted to the STR output, parser.
PAUL: Okay? So, that's why, now, okay, structured output. So, in simple terms, what is structured output?
PAUL: its, structured output means we'll be only getting the core text, the actual thing, the actual content. Otherwise, you have to always do this response.content, a nested operation, if you remember.
PAUL: Okay? So, response.content in this way that you have to go through, always. And this is very specifically for LLM calls.
PAUL: And inside a chain, I'm not making any LLM calls. Okay, right now. Later on, I can add the LLM calls, but for now, as you can see, so here, I'm passing the prompt template, then the LLM, because this prompt information that can be sent to the LLM, and finally the structure output, parser.
PAUL: Now, here you can see the different topics that I have done for machine learning, deep learning, okay?
PAUL: Just wait, guys, it looks like my screen blinked for one minute.
PAUL: So, what is completion token? What is completion token?
PAUL: Any ticket that is generated by an LLM, okay, through a single API call, that refers.
PAUL: And there is no such thing like one completion token, like, only one token is generated. I've never seen
PAUL: Like, one token, that will be getting generated. Most of the time, it will be at least, like, I feel more than 20 to 30, but you can very specifically say to the LLM that I need the response in one word.
PAUL: Then only one token will be returned, but to generate that token, a lot of tokens internally that will be used.
PAUL: Okay, the completion token refers for all the tokens that have been used to complete a specific task.
PAUL: That refers to the completion token.
PAUL: Alright, similarly, your prompt token also, like, based on the prompt generation by a specific LLM service provider, it differs. These are dynamic things to give you the output.
PAUL: Alright, now, see, I'll be executing this. Okay, first, I'm looking for direct output, so I'm using this STR output parser.
PAUL: Now, I am passing this SDR output parser here, then comes your prompt, and then comes your LLM. So, 3 things that I am doing are chaining operation. So, this is referred to as an LCL, as simple as that. Whenever you see a pipeline, that is referred to as an LCL.
PAUL: Okay, now I am passing different topics, so I will be getting how many results? Four results. So that's why I'm doing a simple for loop, and based on that, the chain will be invoked. Because the core thing was chain. I need to invoke chain.invoke, and based on that, I'll be getting it.
PAUL: So, let's see…
PAUL: Sir, please, again, STR output parser. STR output parser will just extract a text from the response. I told you, in response, you get a lot of things you can see.
PAUL: But we are only focused on the content. This is the actual thing we are looking for. So, inside X.
PAUL: STI structured output, you get only this main output. The other things are totally neglected, okay?
PAUL: And right now, you can see, with respect to machine learning, okay, so you can see right now, the things that are coming, right now from the LLM, so machine learning, key ideas in blatant terms, okay, so similarly, like,
PAUL: Okay, then comes vector databases, all the things that I have passed it, okay, so one by one, everything that will be executed. Then comes embeddings.
PAUL: Okay, so pretty much machine learning, embeddings, and vector databases. So, three things I pass. For those 3 topics, yes, I am getting the response from the LL. Now, this was a costly call. A lot of tokens, yes, has been generated.
PAUL: Now, this is the output from the LLM that you are getting directly. So, can you see here, you are not getting any metadata and other stuff? Why? Because you are using a structured output parser.
PAUL: So, whenever you are using an STR output parser, STR stands for structured output. Okay, so you will be getting only the content, rest of the things won't be shown to you. So, this is the actual content that is coming from
PAUL: Yep.
PAUL: What is 60 here? What is 60?
PAUL: Yes?
PAUL: I could not get you. What is 60? Where is 60?
PAUL: In the output, is there some 60?
PAUL: reinstatement.
PAUL: This is just a simple print statement.
PAUL: Guys, this is simple Python, nothing I can do. I'm telling to print that equal to 60 times, it means.
PAUL: Really, guys, if you are not comfortable with Python, then how can I proceed?
PAUL: Alright, fine.
PAUL: So let's proceed, okay? So, right now, this is your initial classes, later on, I will remove this print.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Perfect, fine.
PAUL: Now, little bit with respect to, batch processing, okay? So, like, you can…
PAUL: work with batches also. Okay. And, here right now, some type of multiple types of topics that we will be doing.
PAUL: Mmm… P…
PAUL: Somebody is asking, sir, will you be teaching how to build a custom parser? What do you want to parse?
PAUL: It totally depends upon you.
PAUL: Okay, I'll be talking about data parsers, but yes, I won't be changing the lanction functionalities for sure.
PAUL: Okay, so now comes… so this is basically a batch operation. Okay, so, like, topic, RAG, LCL, Lang Chen Agents, okay, now a few of the things that I'll be passing.
PAUL: Now, to really, like, when I'll be passing this, again, you can see the chain operation, the chain is exactly the same one that you have defined last time. So, this chain, that will be used.
PAUL: Okay? Now, within this chain, directly, I'm passing it as a batch. Last time, if you remember, there was a .invoke.
PAUL: Okay, chain.invoke. But rather than here, I am passing it through a batch. So, this is another option, and through this also you will be getting. So, this is a simple print statement to fetch out the results. And right now, this is a batch, so very specifically, like, I am using enum with cell. Okay, so that, it will be in bind format.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Okay, and based on that, I'll be getting the result. How many of you know enough?
PAUL: Enum?
PAUL: And what is it?
PAUL: Yes.
PAUL: People are asking, no, sir, I don't know, please, actually. These are simple Python concepts. If you are not familiar, please go through.
PAUL: Because I cannot start teaching you Python, really.
PAUL: Okay, so right now, based on this, like, the output that is coming, like, RAT transfer, this is… it's a way to bid similarly, LCL isn't simple. Like, really, I feel that the response from LCL that is coming, okay?
PAUL: Land chain agents are, like, small AI assistants that can plan, decide what to do next, okay? A similar call, so this is, called as a batch call. So, generally, see, when you'll be doing batch call, when you feel that the number of topics will be very, very high.
PAUL: at a particular point of time, okay, or you can create multiple batches also, then you can pass it within. So, multiple ways of doing. So, really, it totally depends upon the number of topics that you'll be having.
PAUL: If you feel that you have 2,000, 30,000, 40,000, okay, then only batch is required. Otherwise, I don't feel that every time you're… because whenever you are doing a batching, enum and zip operation actually saves a lot of memory, as compared to doing the same invoke operation. This takes more memory.
PAUL: Okay, so, generally, I, do an invoke operation, because really, I've not worked with, like, 20,000, 30,000, but if you feel that, okay, so yes, if you have quite a high number of hits from the LLM, it means that continuously hitting an LLM, like, 20,000 times, 30,000 times, okay?
PAUL: you can make. And even for OpenAI, then little bit, then I'll be optimizing with respect to the request that is going. So, there also I can make it as a batch. So, batch is very, very important because
PAUL: If you're doing a large-scale operation, and you want to save the memory, enam and zip, so that's why much more memory-saving operations, as compared to directly calling invoke. But.
PAUL: This is less used, you have to understand. This is… like, if you're doing it in production, then only this will be used. Most of the time, 90% of the time, you will be using this one.
PAUL: Okay? So that is much more production-specific, and this is much more learning-specific.
PAUL: This is a batch.
PAUL: Who is asking, like, how to define a badge? This is a badge.
PAUL: It's not like batch size, no argument. There is no batch size. I'm not training a model.
PAUL: the number of information that I am sending, that is the batch.
PAUL: if I'm sending, probably you can think about, a number of embeddings, okay? And then, probably, if I select 32 embeddings, that becomes a bass size. So here, no batch size part.
PAUL: It's simply within a list. Now, within a list, you can decide the number of elements, okay? And now, based on that, you can define your own concept of batch size. Okay, so a custom rule. By default, batch size is not available in Langshan, okay? It has to be a custom rule if you want to define it.
PAUL: Alright, so this is done okay.
PAUL: Then, a few things as compared to comparing with traditional pipelines, you can go through this one. This is simple, pure text, okay? Okay, now, without Langshan, that I feel that whenever you are working with PDFs and other stuff.
PAUL: Okay, so here, really, like, a lot of lines that needs to be done, you can see. And if you are working with Langchain, it's just…
PAUL: You can see 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7. Pretty much 7 lines of code. So it makes your life much more linear at any point of time.
PAUL: So, like, LanChain. Like, one of the best things. And similarly, there are other libraries also, it's not only LandChain. When I'll be talking about data parcels, I'll be talking a little bit about unstructured.
PAUL: Okay, vectorize is there, talk links is there. Okay, so multiple libraries are there for parsing. It's not only that Langchain is responsible. But you have to understand, like, it's not only that people use Langchain only for parsing.
PAUL: Langchen has other multiple functionalities also. Parsing is just a very small module, which Langchen has.
PAUL: Alright, so majorly this part is done. Okay, now I will move to the next notebook.
PAUL: Okay, document… before doing a document loading operation, let me start with a nave rag, I think that is much more important.
PAUL: Okay, so how a nave rack works, so little bit we'll be talking about that, because that name architecture, because rest of the notebooks are easier, anybody can execute it. But at least a simple RAG. Till now, we have not talked anything about RAG, it was all about few line chain functionalities, okay? So, let's start a little bit about RAG.
PAUL: STR output parser is string parser.
PAUL: Okay, very specifically, but most of the times, we refer it as a structured output, okay? Fine such that. Like, it only throws out the strings in that room.
PAUL: No, it is not parallel.
PAUL: Right now, we have a single batch. And this batch processing, don't think about.
PAUL: Right now, you have to think… most of people will think batch in terms of different right now. You have to take the intuition. Here, batch was different.
PAUL: It was a list of topics. Okay, now, probably, if you want to create a batch, you can create a list, and you have to maintain always the size of the list, probably 32…
PAUL: Okay, so, yes, it won't be parallel processing. It will be one batch completed, then batch 2. Batch 2 completed, then batch 3. Okay, and probably you need to look into the API hit limit also. It's not like that you can make 10,000 API calls in one second. Probably you can do some type of a…
PAUL: time slip, probably, you take a 2-second break, then again. Okay, so you have to always…
PAUL: maintain that API hit rate. Every LLM has an API hit rate. It's not like that you can continuously hit it.
PAUL: To get an output.
PAUL: What is the advantage of using the batch? I told you it uses lesser memory as compared to doing an invoke operation.
PAUL: Rashid asking, we have missed the LLM, no, the LLM was defined.
PAUL: It was a GPT-5 Nano that I was using.
PAUL: Please have a look into the code.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: And, STR output parser, very specifically, okay, that is a string output parser.
PAUL: Okay, because most of the times, I use it as a structured one, because it gives much more structure, okay? But, actually, within the output parsers, this is the string one. Similarly, you have your JSON output parser, CSV output parser, okay, so different type of output parsers are there.
PAUL: But it only throws the core content, okay? So, really doesn't matter. It's just an output parser at the end of the day.
PAUL: Okay, so it's the string class that you have, very specifically, under the core module of LanChain.
PAUL: Alright, so now let's get back. Now, we'll be talking with respect to our RAG at the end of the day, because there are so many other things, other notebooks, but really, the idea is that at least today, let's go through RAG, because I feel that most of the things,
PAUL: Right now done, because that LCL part was important, okay? Now, this simple rack chain, guys, everybody, please open this notebook, because we will start the execution of this one.
PAUL: Because in Langchen, you have more than 50,000 to 60,000 inbuilt functions.
PAUL: So really, like, taking every inbuilt function. Okay, so I am discussing only the major ones that we'll be using.
PAUL: Poi, Vendaram is asking Ranabel pass-through.
PAUL: Yes, exactly, like, you want to use it in Langchen, very specifically, why?
PAUL: Let me know that always.
PAUL: Because, again, it's a custom class that you have to pass it with respect to passing in function.
PAUL: Alright guys, please open the Langchain, simple RAG Langchain notebook, because now we will start at least building the most basic RAG in Langchain.
PAUL: Restart your bundle, Krishna Kaam.
PAUL: If you have installed a package, and if the notebook cannot detect it, it means that you have to always
PAUL: Restart the kernel.
PAUL: Pyntic parsers are different. Totally different.
PAUL: Alright, so first of all, so this is the installation check. Okay, I will start executing this one. So, majorly, the libraries that I need, okay, all are mentioned here. Okay, so this is a simple check.
PAUL: Okay, so right now, based on the check, we can see the lan chain, the lanchain core, okay, the community one, we can see, like, langchain hyphen OpenAI is not installed.
PAUL: Okay, but I feel that it is installed.
PAUL: Okay, alright.
PAUL: Because langchen hyphen OpenAI, let me just… Check this.
PAUL: Because if it was working, you'd be, tipped, True.
PAUL: Land chain hyphen opening.
PAUL: Okay, it is verifying.
PAUL: in my environment it is there, probably I don't know exactly, like…
PAUL: what is there? And it might say, like, pip install. If it is there for you, always have a check with the pip show. Sometimes, you might get an error.
PAUL: So you have to just execute this cell and just be sure that all… everything is available or not.
PAUL: You can do an import also, this import statement, actually.
PAUL: gives you.
PAUL: That year, all the imports are successfully done, you can see.
PAUL: It's pretty much, like, the main thing is, this is just a check. Okay, because here there is a pip install, langchen, langchen Core, Langchen community, so all the major packages that we do need for this particular. If you don't have, you can do something like this.
PAUL: Okay, like, you can create a code cell, okay, and then you can do a pip install of all these packages.
PAUL: But I know that you guys have already done the installation, so there won't be any type of problem.
PAUL: Okay, so separately you can do this.
PAUL: Okay, and just be sure, when you execute this, the standard library imports are there. So, everything, and you will be seeing all imports successful.
PAUL: This is the main one.
PAUL: Please have a check on this one.
PAUL: Can you show the part of?
PAUL: path of simple lan chain? I don't have this file. Please, guys, check, I think I have provided this file in the ZIF, please do a confirmation.
PAUL: Two people are telling I don't have this file.
PAUL: It is clear, no? Fine. Okay, okay, fine, fine.
PAUL: Somebody is telling, I don't have this file. Check, Ricky.
PAUL: I'm good.
PAUL: It is clear, okay. Now, okay, Mahumma, your issue is related to kernel crash, so there's nothing that I can do.
PAUL: Try to restart the kernel, or delete the environment, or reinstall, that is the only solution for random kernel crashes.
PAUL: Yes.
PAUL: Just check, the notebook is there. Simple, rack, langchain.ip, nby.
PAUL: It's pretty much standard things.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Actually was hidden, okay?
PAUL: Okay, so, like, here also, if I do, like… Unless…
PAUL: I'll write the simple reaction notebook I have.
PAUL: Alright guys, just try to execute the import cell.
PAUL: Okay, so let me know, like, I feel that you guys should not get any type of errors.
PAUL: It should not take a very long time.
PAUL: But,
PAUL: Initially, like, probably everything should be done, like, 5 to 10 seconds. Import successful, great. No error, no error.
PAUL: Okay, just be sure you are using the same kernel, just like last time you're using the same kernel. Don't recreate the kernel, okay?
PAUL: Alright, it's fine, okay.
PAUL: Alright, so now, for everybody, it's looking. If Langchain AI is not installed, leave it. Just, run this set.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: As simple as that. Or you can do a verification, just like I have done. Do a pip show Langshan Ivan OpenAI. Okay. Sometimes the compiler, does that. Yeah, not a big deal.
PAUL: The core part is, all your imports should be working.
PAUL: Then, once your import is done, then the next part is basically the OpenAI key verification. So, like, you can see I'm loading the environment variable, and then I'm having a check. So, pretty much standard boilerplate.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Then comes… okay, so now is the part from where I will start working with respect to documents. So here, I do have a… attention is all you need, so this is the PDF for that particular research paper, attention.pdm.
PAUL: Okay, I think I have shared this PDF with you. Okay, have a check. Okay, if it is not there, you can download any PDF, there is no restriction.
PAUL: So, right now, this is a path that I have given, attention.pdf. Okay. So, as simple as that. See, right now, this is a simple check with respect to file existing. It means that this file is available or not. I'm just checking that. Then, this is PyPDF. Now, this is the package.
PAUL: Okay, so PyPDF is basically the package using which? Okay, we'll be loading a PDF file. There are different types of file loaders, okay? Now, right now, we know that the file format is .pdf, so very specifically for that, pyPDFloader.
PAUL: That we are using it.
PAUL: And now, even if you look into, I think, inside your requirements, there will be some type of at least one PDF, just 5 PDFs.
PAUL: Okay? For PDF processing, which is required.
PAUL: So, if you… this is the actual package behind the scenes, which is, like, Langchen is using.
PAUL: So here you can see a PyPDF is actually an open source, pure Python, splitting, merging, different type of PDF-based operations that you can do, okay? So this is the actual underlined package, okay, that is being used.
PAUL: So it's not like LanChain is having a package, rather than LangChain is just using that particular package.
PAUL: Okay, so this is the paths that we have provided, file existence, okay. So now, loader, and finally, we are loading the document that we have, okay? So let me just execute this cell.
PAUL: Okay, and I'll be getting that information.
PAUL: So, right now, this is just a document preview, the first 500 characters, basically. Okay, and you can see attention is all you need. Then comes the name of the research papers, the organizations, all those things. So, basically, the starting characters is coming.
PAUL: No, it is not vastly used.
PAUL: So, behind the scenes, it's simple. So, right now, this PDF has total, based on this, okay, 15 pages, okay, and this is the initial few content that we have. Now, what is the metadata which is attached with the PDF? Producer, like, PDF text, LAT text with hyphen, creation date, you can see.
PAUL: 2024. Now, these are all the PDF information, which comes from archive.
PAUL: Okay, so modified date, this is, PDF with the latex version, so PDF texts.
PAUL: Okay, subject and other things that comes around here.
PAUL: So when the PDF was created, based on that, this information was added.
PAUL: Anybody has used that, Adobe PDF reader? When you create a PDF during the export option, okay, there is metadata where you can manually add the metadata to the PDF.
PAUL: Right? If you have not explored, fine.
PAUL: Okay. Now, this was a single PDF. Oh yeah, so similarly, you know that if we have a folder, the same thing that can be done with a for loop.
PAUL: Okay, I think this is also there. So, I don't know, have I shared the .pdups or not? But, there are, like, two files, rag and rack survey, two PDFs, okay, for them also. Now, here, pretty much using a for loop, I am just loading all the files.
PAUL: Okay?
PAUL: And right now, you can see this is a glove function, so star.pdf, so whatever the PDF that will be there inside this .pdf folders. Okay, so all the files that will be read.
PAUL: So these are some… Standard. Now, going forward, you know, what is the purpose of using Glock GLOB?
PAUL: Anyone?
PAUL: Because these are simple Python things.
PAUL: Globus regex.
PAUL: Search, global files.
PAUL: Yes, it's not exactly ready, but it's much more about the file format that we are looking for, okay?
PAUL: global file formats, okay, like, if I pass star.star, like, all the files will be selected, so it's not exactly regex, it's much more of a file format selection that we generally do.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Okay, so I think this should be working for everybody, please let me know. Till now, the courses that we have done, because the next part will be text splitting.
PAUL: Yes.
PAUL: Included. Now, in the next step.
PAUL: Splitting the documents. So now, this is where…
PAUL: Okay, now, in every LLM, there is a token limit. So, based on that, we are, like, we need to take care, like, the idea is that whenever you are creating chunks, splitting a document simply means what? Chunks at the end of the day. You split a document into… it can be 5 chunks, 10 chunks, okay, 20 chunks, totally depends upon your
PAUL: chunk parameter. Okay, so for example, what will be the chunk size? You might say it will be 520.
PAUL: Okay, it means 512 tokens, or there will… can be a chunk overlap parameter.
PAUL: Okay, so… I think that, but railway Viz…
PAUL: Even I forgot on that one.
PAUL: Visual variation.
PAUL: There was a nice visualization to Lia Chungwheel's.
PAUL: Okay, so here you can understand, basically, okay, so the concept of different type of splitters. Generally, in, whenever we are working with NLP, so we take these type of examples just to show you.
PAUL: Okay, so there are different types of splitters, recursive, splitter, okay, and then based on… now you can see markdown format, Python. So let's start with the most common one, which we use 90% of the times, recursive character, text splitter is used.
PAUL: Okay, now these are a very basic one. So here you can see the chunk size that we are defining is only 25.
PAUL: Okay, so 25, pretty small number. We don't use these numbers much more, but you can increase… you can see in blue color that is coming much more.
PAUL: Okay, so the first chunk that you have in this color, within the other one, so probably some chunk might have only a small component. Okay, it's not necessary that every chunk will be of equal size.
PAUL: So, right now, based on that, the total characters, the total number of chunks in a particular document, what is the average chunk size, which is true to 80.5.
PAUL: Now, generally, like, recursive, character text pitter always looks for a double slash, and it means that always it will try to look for a paragraph.
PAUL: Okay, so double slashing is one of the major highlighters, but there are other parameters also. The idea was to show you this particular version, so let me just reduce it for now, 50.
PAUL: Me too.
PAUL: Okay… Now, this particular parameter that I have, the chunk overlap, Okay, tone, okay.
PAUL: Because in, I don't know why in recursive it is not getting enabled.
PAUL: Okay, now in the characters fitter, let me pass an overlap of 15.
PAUL: Yeah, so…
PAUL: At any point of time, when you look into… okay, so the green color actually represents, so when you actually go through this, I'll be sharing the link. Okay, this is just the basics, really. There is no advanced concept, but if you want to really know, okay, so in that way, it is good.
PAUL: So, right now, the chunk size, the character, okay, the length in the characters of your end chunks, and the chunk overlap is basically the green color. Whenever you see this green, green, green comes into the picture, it means that this is an overlap component.
PAUL: Okay, so right now, the formula that we use generally, so based on the chunk size, always use 10%.
PAUL: Now, generally, if it is 134, okay, I will use, based on that, 10-15%.
PAUL: This is something like this.
PAUL: Okay, so you can see here, based on the overlap. So, the green color is basically the overlap that is coming. So, we generally keep it 10-15%. There is no fixed rule, but that's a general rule of thumb.
PAUL: Okay, we have seen that people are using, sometimes, like, the max that we go is 20%. Always remember. Like, if we are working with 1,000,
PAUL: Okay, so we want our chunk size to be, really, 1000.
PAUL: So, at any point of time. Now, this, then 10,000, so max we can go, like, 200.
PAUL: You can go 250 also, but
PAUL: It's always good that keep it around between 10% to 20%.
PAUL: So I always prefer to go in between something around 15%, because sometimes 20, depends upon the data. But usually, most of the time, that 10% to 20% rule works.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Now, what is the meaning of overlap? Overlap means that, at any point of time, okay, so right now, this is the initial chunk that you have, okay? Now, this green color that you have, okay, now this is an overlap, it means that it tries to take some extra token from the next chunk also.
PAUL: Okay, from the next chunk, it will try to take some extra tokens, so that it doesn't lose the context completely. So, for context reservation, chunk overlap is a very important parameter.
PAUL: Okay, because whenever you start, like, every chunk, okay, and before that, some information was there from the other chunk. Okay, so the last information actually becomes the overlap.
PAUL: Okay, so the last information from chunk 1, okay, comes to chunk. So that's why that overlap is a very good component. So, when you are doing an overlap operation, you have the last information of chunk 1.
PAUL: Okay, and similarly, if you try to take it for chunk 3, I can set the last information for chunk 2, as well as the first information from chunk food.
PAUL: Because you will be having multiple chunks, so you always look into what was at the last and what was at the first. So, chunk overlap helps you for context preservation at any point of time.
PAUL: Yeah, it's like a bridge, you can think about, but the core purpose is context preservation, so that suddenly we don't lose the context.
PAUL: Alright, so now, see, there are only two sweaters, like, really bad in performance. Recursive character splitter is something, like, I feel, majorly, we do use it in our practice.
PAUL: Now, in the next step, okay, so we will start with this one only. So, the idea is that you always start with smaller chunks.
PAUL: drone starts…
PAUL: randomly with a big number. Because really, nobody can say that a bigger, chunk size will give you high accuracy. There is no written rule.
PAUL: Okay, so, like, 600 might work for you. Okay, so always start with something smaller. I feel that at least go close to, like, more than 500. So, I always do my experiments starting from
PAUL: 600, or something around 650, and then I take 15% in my chunk overall. So, based on whatever that simple formula that I keep it, okay, and directly I apply that function. So I have to change it, in one shot.
PAUL: Okay, so you always start with smaller. Start with something 500, 600, 700, 800. Okay, there is no fixed rule that, okay, 1000 is good. You have to understand, this is a simple hyperparameter that you need to decide. Nobody is going to tell you. Based on your data, you need to take the decision.
PAUL: Okay, so now…
PAUL: Then comes smaller chunks, more precision ritual. Balanced chunks must be large enough to contain meaningful context, but small enough to be specific.
PAUL: So, the first, splitter that we'll be doing, the chanting mechanism, is the recursive character text splitter, okay? Now, these are some of the parameters which are being followed, okay? Whenever recursive text character, text splitter is implemented.
PAUL: One is this paragraph. So this is… I feel that most of the time, the information is there within a paragraph, a lot of details are there, but you can think about if the paragraph is, condition doesn't satisfy it, then it comes to lines.
PAUL: Sentences, words, and character is the last result. Really, really. True to say, guys, like, 3, 4, 5 is really…
PAUL: Not so much each.
PAUL: I always prefer using the top two, paragraphs and lines.
PAUL: they have much better preserved context. If you are working with characters, zero context. If you are working with words, again, really. Because at the end of the day, to understand an entire context in English language, okay, you need sentences.
PAUL: So that's why I feel that these three things are much more important, the paragraph, lines, and sentences. But these are the last resort. It means that if nothing can be done, then it falls back to these particular conditions.
PAUL: Right here, you can see in the parameters, a chunk size that we have taken is 1024, and based on that, as I told you, like, 10% to 20%, you can take that number, which comes to 128.
PAUL: Okay, so the target size for each chunk, with respect to characters that is coming. Now, the next thing is overlap between the chunks to maintain context continuity. The idea is that context preservation, the same thing that has been written here.
PAUL: Overlap prevents important information from being split across the chunks. So, very, very important parameter. Okay, the chunk overlap.
PAUL: And these two things are the most one. Whenever you are building a rack, you need to make sure that you need to play with these hyperparameters. In one shot, nobody can build it. Even I need to spend at least
PAUL: Okay, like, 3 to 4 hours, just to test it out on different type of documents.
PAUL: Sometimes, like, every document.
PAUL: can have different chunk size. It's not necessary that all documents will be having a simple chunk side. Then you need to have an algorithm that, okay, if this file comes, then you'll be doing this chunk side. If this file comes, then this chunk size. So, pretty much a dynamic chunking algorithm that needs to be built.
PAUL: Okay? Now, with respect to the implementation, it's pretty much standard, you have to understand. A specific library is here, which is referred to as the LangChain text splitters. Okay, so if you look into the imports.
PAUL: I think lunch and text splitters. So this is the actual package. Within that package, you do have, different types of splitters, okay? So right now, we have taken Recursive, which is the widely used one.
PAUL: Okay, so here, so this is, I'm just calling that particular text definition.
PAUL: Okay, so right now, I'm just doing the implementation of that splitter. Okay, so whenever you are implementing a splitter, you need two things, chunk size and chunk overlap. Whatever types of external documents you have, whether PDF, JSON, okay, you can keep a single rule, or you can keep multiple rules.
PAUL: Okay, it's totally up to you, you have to do that particular research based on your data.
PAUL: Okay, and a few specific separators that we are keeping. So, like, sometimes we keep this, but again, not always. Okay, you can keep a very specific rule that, okay, it has to be followed these rules.
PAUL: Otherwise, you know that word 11 and others that comes, it can get a problem.
PAUL: Okay, so that's why this. Now, most of the times, I will say that these two, okay, are not being used. The length function, okay, like, if you want to measure the chunk length, if you feel that, if you require it.
PAUL: Keep it. Okay, and then comes the separators. Okay, so again, not a necessary one. But these two are the most important, chunk size and chunk overlap.
PAUL: There is no cleanup of stock words.
PAUL: Guys, there is no cleanup here.
PAUL: Okay, some… many people are asking, can we see the chunks? Yes, you can. So, once I do this.
PAUL: Okay, you will be seeing the chunk. Can you see chunk 1?
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: So right now, based on the documents that we had, I think two documents we had very specifically, yes. So, 2 PDFs that I have loaded. So, for the first PDF, this is the chunk, okay? Then for the… this one, that… this is the other chunk that you have.
PAUL: For this one, chunk 3. Okay, I'm just printing out 3 chunks.
PAUL: Okay, you can actually print out much more if you want. So here, you can change that number in the for loop, 3 to, like, 5, 10, 20, okay, because the total number of chunks are 218. So you can see all the chunks there.
PAUL: So, let me know the concept of, first of all, this particular
PAUL: Chunk is… like, everybody understood what is a chunk size.
PAUL: It totally depends upon the number of characters that you are selecting.
PAUL: Okay, so the total number of characters, really matters to us, because at the end of the day, okay, you need to count them. So, like, when you are creating your metadata for any type of document.
PAUL: Okay, so very specifically, it can be PDF, JSON. You have to maintain a metadata, so in those metadata, you can actually save this type of information also.
PAUL: Okay, so yes, no preprocessing is required, guys. No stop words and other things. Transformers are capable of handling those things.
PAUL: You have to understand.
PAUL: It's showing 40 documents? I don't think. Okay, so splitting 40 documents…
PAUL: Actually, I think I have only 2 PDFs, let me just check here.
PAUL: Because I have two PDFs only.
PAUL: Okay, because I think, that for… okay, total pages. So, one, page is referred to as a document, so don't get confused. Like, two PDFs, total number of pages are 40. Based on that, 40 is being shown.
PAUL: Okay, so don't get confused.
PAUL: Alright, so this part is the most important one, which was basically, like, text splitting. Now, there are other types of text splitters that we'll be discussing in the next class, but this is, like, the most go-to one, like, 90% of the times. The idea is that you have a PDF document and you break it.
PAUL: Now, the idea is how we want to break it, this decision is totally dependent on two parameters. One is this chunk size, and the chunk overlap, and these two are hyperparameters.
PAUL: But the rule is always take 10% of your chunk size, so 10% to 20%. Other than that, there is no such thing. So, once you have defined this, so simply you are doing a split operation, which is basically the chunk.
PAUL: So, after splitting, you can do the calculation, because the length is there. So, length of the documents, okay, then the length of the chunks that we are simply printing out, and this is how your chunks looks like.
PAUL: Is this part clear? Please let me know in the chat.
PAUL: Now, right now, we are not working with images later on, because images, very specifically for that, like, I have to use a separate library, like Doclinks.
PAUL: Okay, or some other libraries. Directly in pipe PDF, the image extraction directly doesn't support.
PAUL: What is the document here? The document here is these two PDFs.
PAUL: Okay, and when 40 documents… 40 documents refer to each page of the PD.
PAUL: What is the role of a separator? Separator is very specifically, like, when you are doing a splitting operation. Double slash n means a paragraph.
PAUL: Okay, so you can see these are referred to as paragraphs. Normal lines slash N. Sentences end with dot.
PAUL: So, these are the properties based on which the splitting operation takes place. The highest priority goes to paragraph, second priority lines, third priority sentences, okay? So, there can be, no, in a document, there is only one word. There can be only one character.
PAUL: There can be a possibility, so that's why we know that in most of the documents, there will be paragraphs. So, after paragraphs, live. So, there has been a priority which has been decided.
PAUL: By default, if you don't pass anything inside your separators, this is the default priority at any point of time.
PAUL: Okay, so generally, we don't pass the separators.
PAUL: Okay, so it totally depends on, like, markdown documents. So, in markdown documents, when you are working, okay, so sometimes we do separation based on that hash. I think in headings, you know, hash
PAUL: there are, you know, whenever you work with Markdown, like, one hash is the bigger one than two hashes, three hash, yes? So, like, in that way also, you can define a custom one.
PAUL: So, like, when you are creating a custom splitter, so at any point of time, you can define those type of rules. But the default recursive character splitter, it always look for paragraphs.
PAUL: If it could not find paragraphs, it will look for lines. If it could not find lines, then sentences, then finally words, and at the last, it will be looking only for characters.
PAUL: Yes, yes, if you have given wrong document, we can always delete the job, not a big deal.
PAUL: Okay, so now, this is the text splitter. There are other different text splitters that we'll be talking about, with very specifically, there is a separate library which is built
PAUL: only for doing a chunking operation. Okay, because this is not highly optimized chunking, which is provided by the line chain, but later on, like, in production, I feel we can move to other, better splitting mechanisms, which is there.
PAUL: Yes, for sure. If the number of chunks will be higher, the retrieval process will be slow, because at every point of time in the retrieval process, you need to check the similarity score.
PAUL: So, yes. So, it will be comparing with all the necessary charts. So, that's why the speed will be slow.
PAUL: Okay, guys, so after chunking, can we move to the next part with respect to embeddings?
PAUL: Okay, now this is the basic one, when we'll be talking about chunking, because today's class is not about chunking. This is just the basic of chunking to show you. One dedicated class will be there only to show you chunking.
PAUL: Okay? Alright. Now, the next stop that comes is embedding. It means that
PAUL: This information needs to be embedded, okay, into numbers. It means that this needs to be converted into vectors. All this information, for every chunk that you have. That needs to be embedded as an vector, because once you have converted into vector, you will be uploading them into vector database.
PAUL: Now, majorly with respect to, like, chunk one, chunk, okay, three chunks that I am showing, okay? Now, you have to understand now, starting from here, again, paid operation comes into the picture. If you're creating, because right now.
PAUL: text embedding 3 small. Now, this is an embedding model that comes from Opinion. So, similarly, if you want to use a Gemini model, there is Gemini001.
PAUL: Okay, Gemini embedding001 model is there, which can be used. So right now, my chunks are available. In the next step, I will convert these chunks into vectors, as simple as that. And once I have done or converted them into vectors, I can upload them into a vector database.
PAUL: So right now, for our embeddings, I'm using this particular model. Okay, you can see OpenAI embeddings, so this is the actual class, and inside that, I'm using. So, there are other embedding models also, like small, large, but large is very costly.
PAUL: So I feel that the smaller model should be used, like, you should always use in class the smaller model.
PAUL: Okay, the larger model is, like, more than 3 times, so I don't prefer using it. So, I think text embedding 3 small does the job.
PAUL: Now, once you have defined your embedding, so I have defined that, okay, now this is my embedding model. Now, what I have to do, I have to send all my chance, okay, to the embedding model, so that the vector will be generated. Okay, it means that the embedding will be generated. So, the data I am sending to OpenAI right now.
PAUL: So it's basically an API call through which I'm sending the information.
PAUL: Now, in production, generally, we try to do, I can say, modification. This is the part, because right now, it's pretty much simple. But later on, we try to do batch uploads here, because really, the number of documents increases, like, 1,000 to 10,000. So this part, we actually optimize highly.
PAUL: Okay, like, so that you can pass 1,000 documents. But we need to respect the rate limits which OpenAI provides. Like, sometimes I put a sleep operation of 2 seconds between the batches, and that way I try to do the optimization.
PAUL: But very, very important. Okay, because right now we are having the lesser amount of chunks, so not a problem. But when you try to push.
PAUL: Okay, like, 50,000 channels, 60,000 channels, then you have to maintain that batch operation, always.
PAUL: Okay, like, now, so simply what I will do, I have defined the model. Okay, now, see, this is a sample text form now, okay, and based on that, the embedding. The idea is to show you the embedding.
PAUL: Can you see that, the information that we have, the sample text, this is a sentence to demonstrate empathy.
PAUL: Okay, and right now, the embedding dimension. Okay, now, this is the dimension for this particular model, which is 1536.
PAUL: So, like, one model can support different types of dimension, okay, or, like, only one dimension. So, there is no, fixed rule that, one model will support only this, okay? If I show you Gemini models, Gemini models are really good in embedding.
PAUL: Okay, that top, model that comes around. So, Gemini embeddings.
PAUL: Okay, a single model can support different types. You can see here right now, different types of embedding sizes are being shown.
PAUL: So, 2048.
PAUL: Okay, it means that when you try to convert, so this is basically that array, or basically the vector size. So, in your vector, the number of elements will be 2048.
PAUL: It's for a sentence. Right now, in our example, we have taken it a simple sentence. Now, think about this sentence is converted into 100 and, basically, I can say, the 56 numbers.
PAUL: Okay, and right now, you can see I'm just showing you the first 10 values. So, really, the embedding is very big. It's an I-dimensional data.
PAUL: So, when you are actually doing, so this also you need to take care of that, based on which parameter you select. So, it is not necessary that if you are going with higher dimensions, you will get good accuracy.
PAUL: So, if you look into the scores here, so 2048, okay, 68.16. Okay, 1536, it's 68.17.
PAUL: So, there is no such rule directly that I can define. That I can say that if the dimension is higher, it will always perform better. Okay?
PAUL: Now, yes, so these are the main, Mathroshka, okay, so these are, Mathroshka representational learning, like, MLR stands for that, okay? And now these are basically the MTV leader books, okay? Now, I'll be showing you what are the different type of
PAUL: Output dimension it supports.
PAUL: You can see here.
PAUL: Okay, now Gemini supports 128, 3072, recommended is 768. I feel that 768 should be the starting point for you.
PAUL: I always start my experiments with 768. This is really good.
PAUL: Then I test for 1536. You have to… see, this is a two-time increase if I simply say that. Your vector database cost will increase if you try to increase the number of dimensions. So, number of dimension really matters to us.
PAUL: If you are going with higher dimensions, it simply means that you are paying more money at the end of the day.
PAUL: So, it's not that if you select, and it is not necessary that if you are going with higher dimensions, I can say that you will be getting better output. There is no such rule which has been defined.
PAUL: Okay, it can be. So, generally, I feel that most of the time, 768 and 1536 does the job. Okay, does the work for me. So, I feel that these two are really good. 3 layers, 7-2, rarely that I do use.
PAUL: There are more, like 3096 is also there, 4000 is also there. Okay, so there are other models which support higher dimensions. Okay, what one thing that I feel that this input token limit, this is really, really low of Gemini.
PAUL: Okay, this limit should be somehow higher. This is one of the major cons of Gemini, because of which I prefer to switch to open-source models most of the times, I can say.
PAUL: Okay, so similarly, in your, LanChan also, okay, so in your OpenAI also, you can always look into the different types of model, okay? So, OpenAI embeddings.
PAUL: So, you have to actually take this decision.
PAUL: The output dimension, yes, you have to pass it.
PAUL: Okay, so vector embeddings?
PAUL: Okay, so you can see new embedding models, text embedding 3 small and text embedding 3 large. Our newest and most performant embedding models are available. So, these two are very specifically that we are using most of the times. And text 3 small always uses it, because this is the cheapest version.
PAUL: Okay, so you can see here, based on your input, you'll be getting some numbers. Okay, it's not showing all the numbers, but yes, it's showing few. So, right now, you can see this is the actual
PAUL: Now, if you look here, the performance, really. Okay, so let's take the best one, which is the text embedding 3 small. Okay, now here it's 64…
PAUL: dot 6.
PAUL: Okay, and the max input token sets, 8192.
PAUL: Okay? Now, if you go back to Gemini.
PAUL: Okay, so many tabs I have opened, just…
PAUL: Okay, so in this way, you have to actually do the comparison whenever you are doing it, okay? So, I think…
PAUL: Where is Gemini? I thought I opened it.
PAUL: June 9th.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Okay, now, this, I feel that this is very, very less as compared to others.
PAUL: Okay, now see, 2048, now you can compare that 2048, it is giving you 4 times more. So I feel that, okay, so when I need, like, more input at any point of time, there are some use cases where, very specifically, we need more input. Otherwise, like,
PAUL: this can be increased to, like, 20,000, 30,000 to open source models also. But this is also pretty much limited, but it does the job, 8192. But 2048 is really, like, whenever you are doing an embedding operation, so yes.
PAUL: That limit is, like, 2,000 tokens, I feel that it is less, in today's world.
PAUL: Now, with respect to… now, if you look into 62, 64, 61, okay? And here, if you look into…
PAUL: Okay, so all the numbers are much more higher as compared to that. So I feel that Gemini is good, but the only restriction is Gemini.
PAUL: Yes, with respect to the, this, input token limit.
PAUL: Alright, now moving towards…
PAUL: Because in open source models, you always have higher levels. That is one of the best things that I do love.
PAUL: But yes, doing the setup and setting up the infra, that is some other stuff to discuss.
PAUL: Alright, so, right now we have done the embedding, which is a… right now we have used the cheapest model from OpenAI, the text embedding 3 small. Okay, and right now, embed query, so whatever that query that I'm passing, so this is a simple…
PAUL: way of converting your text into your embeddings. And finally, you can see this is how your text is converted into a high-dimensional data, which is 1536.
PAUL: Okay, then comes, like, creating a vector store. So right now, I have taken an open source file, which is from Facebook, directly.
PAUL: Okay, so you can see Facebook AI Similarity Search, okay? Now, directly, I'm using this, so for this, you need to install one package, pip install files, okay? So that package already, you guys have installed it.
PAUL: DYPI files.
PAUL: Okay, so this is the package, Fire CPU. Similarly, there is a package Fires GPU. Like, in GPU, we get better speeds, and this is completely open source. Okay, so this CPU version that we are using for now, so this is the actual vector store that we'll be working with.
PAUL: Now, in the next step, so, the idea is that, okay, you have those chunks, okay, so you can see here, creating and files index, so that's why we call it an indexing operation. Okay, chunks to embedding, finally saving it into vector database.
PAUL: Now, here, I'm just calling files from documents, and then I'm directly passing the chunks and the embeddings. These two things. Okay, so our split document chunks, and then comes our OpenAI embeddings. These two things that I am saving in my vector database.
PAUL: Now, this is the most simplest form of data that you can see.
PAUL: You can create more complex data also, because right now I am not working a lot with respect to metadata, okay? But this is the most simple one. You need chunks and the embeddings.
PAUL: Okay? So, pretty much the standard format that we can see.
PAUL: Now, this is your vector database that we have. Okay, so now, the idea is to save this information. Now, you can save it inside a local file, so as you can see, this is basically a folder that I've created, the fire sentence. So, all this, and this is a local implementation, so if I show you.
PAUL: I think I have… will be having this. You can see a pickle file is there, and there is a file. So, generally, the… most of the information with respect to your vector DB,
PAUL: Okay, the major weights, the numbers, those are all saved in the form of pickles. Okay, so the pickle file is the main one, so never delete your pickle file, at least.
PAUL: Fast file actually saves much more the, I can say, the vector DB information, rather than your core information about the chunks.
PAUL: So that's why these two files are important.
PAUL: Levi, fifth, it can be any name. See, this is a custom path that I've given. You guys can pass anytime, okay?
PAUL: Guys, this is a pickle file, so do you think that if I try to double-click, it will open?
PAUL: Yes.
PAUL: How many of you know about pickle files? What do we save in pickle files?
PAUL: In machine learning, you guys have learned it.
PAUL: model, okay? You save your model.
PAUL: Okay, so it means that what you say, at the end of the day, what is modeling?
PAUL: some type of serialized information, okay, which is basically the weights and biases at the end of the day. Okay, so that works. Okay, and this is all. These files you cannot open, these are all serialized format files.
PAUL: Alright, now let's move to the next part, because once you have executed this, okay, so…
PAUL: in your local vector store. Okay, now this operation takes time. It totally depends upon the number of charts, because this is much more of a saving operation. Okay, it means that all the numbers that you have, it will be saved here.
PAUL: And, very specifically, I kept that, if you have this, you can always reload the data also at any point of time. So, for reloading the data, so loading a saved vector database, okay, so, like, if you already have one vector database, directly you can load it.
PAUL: And really, like, once… if we have done the embedding operation, okay, and we have saved it, then we never do, the operation of creating embedding. So this is a one-time operation.
PAUL: If, till the time new documents are not coming, if new documents are coming, then only I will be doing the embedding.
PAUL: But it's not like that every time you run this thing. You have to understand you are spending money when you are running this thing. So, it should be a one task, one-time task. So, once you have saved it, in the next time, you can directly load it. So, always try to use this load operation.
PAUL: Okay, I've seen students, like, every time doing embedding, embedding. Really not important. Okay? And right now, I'm just, saving two information. See, guys?
PAUL: In the vector store, I'm just saving to documents and embedding. Right now, I'm not saving any metadata. Later on, in some other part I'll be doing about metadata, but for now, I'm just keeping it simple.
PAUL: At the end of the day, the most important thing in a vector TV is the embeddings, you have to understand.
PAUL: Okay? The most important is embeddings. And then comes… I give the priority, like, you can keep your metadata much more diverse, but for now, I have not kept it. This is an RAG implementation, so really not required.
PAUL: Now comes your retriever. As you noted.
PAUL: This is phase one is done. Phase 1 is the data ingestion part.
PAUL: So, this was the data ingestion. Now, your Phase 2 will start, from where your retrieval will come into the picture.
PAUL: Okay?
PAUL: So right now, very specifically, I'm using this vector store as Retriever, as you can see. Okay.
PAUL: And, what type of search operation that I am doing. What is file syntax? It's the name of the folder.
PAUL: Okay, it's the name of the folder where I am saving it.
PAUL: Like, really? I think everybody is clear about file index. Please look into the code. Whenever… if something is written in double quote, it means that it's a hard-coded value.
PAUL: And generally, it refers to path.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: If the document changes, do embedding needs to be rerun? Yes. If your document changes, for sure, embedding needs to be rerun. That's a common thing.
PAUL: Okay? Yes. But you have to understand, the idea is that if you have the same content, don't delete that. If it is continuously, dynamically changing, yes. Because embedding, again, costly operation. So right now, the idea is to look for top K charts.
PAUL: Okay, if you remember, in Phase 2, we'll be doing and activating the retrieval process, and then, based on that, we'll be activating that we have to find the top K charts. Now, to do that search, very specifically, I am telling that, okay, use the similarity.
PAUL: The idea is to find the similarity score. So, by default, Langchain uses cosine similarity for searching.
PAUL: Then comes, how many K? I told you top K chance, so K is equal to 4 that I have passed for now.
PAUL: So, I have initiated the retriever, and later on, I'll be calling it, okay? Now comes your query.
PAUL: Now, see, this is the part where you have your main query.
PAUL: You can see, this is the query, what is the main topic of the document?
PAUL: Okay, this is the actual user query. Okay, that I'll be using it. So, I have the retriever ready. Okay, you know that. To implement the retriever, I need a query. If I don't have a query, then really, I cannot initialize it.
PAUL: So, first comes the query. So, that's by the query definition. Inside that retriever, I am passing my query that I have, which is basically the test query. And based on that, it will retrieve the documents. So, this is the phase with respect to…
PAUL: I can say, document read-driven.
PAUL: Okay? So, now, this part is where it will try to find the top K chunks. So, the output in the retrieve talks will be the top 4 chunks, because I have given the parameter here.
PAUL: Okay, so let me just execute it.
PAUL: dot ENB died.
PAUL: Hmm, okay, alright.
PAUL: Mmm…
PAUL: I will just restart the condo once here.
PAUL: Yes, I need to re-execute the stuff.
PAUL: No, okay… This thing should be working.
PAUL: This I don't need, actually.
PAUL: No, right.
PAUL: I think…
PAUL: My kernel is crashing. Anybody is facing this problem? I don't think so. The kernel crashed while executing the code in the current cell.
PAUL: No, this should not be the issue.
PAUL: Let me just restart it.
PAUL: Because, the idea is not to reuse this one.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: I've restarted it, and I am able to run it. Alright, fine. I know that restart will happen, but again, like, sometimes, because so many executions that I am doing, so it can happen.
PAUL: Alright, so let's… Okay, I won't be using multiple documents. For now, let me take the simpler version.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: I won't be loading multiple PDFs, okay, a single PDF.
PAUL: Should, do that job.
PAUL: Because when you are working with multiple PDFs, I know that
PAUL: Okay? It will be much more costly operation, so a single PDF file that I am doing.
PAUL: So, right now, you can see the number of chunks had decreased. Previously, I think it was close to 218.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Okay, leave this.
PAUL: Her retriever, lightening now, see.
PAUL: If the kernel crashes, why this kernel is getting crashed?
PAUL: Hmm…
PAUL: Alright, this is… because I know if I create a new environment, everything will start working in one chunk.
PAUL: Okay, but it… That's the main thing. I don't want to spend that time in creating that environment.
PAUL: Because I've heard… No.
PAUL: Hmm… Because I think I have enough memory right now. Let me just check that.
PAUL: Memory issues, sometimes there's crashes, but again…
PAUL: Yes, memory is pretty much free.
PAUL: Alright, now, nothing that I can do here. The only solution is creating the virtual environment.
PAUL: Alright, so… what I can do.
PAUL: Let me do a deactivate operation.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: I'm just deleting the entire environment, okay, and I will try once.
PAUL: Yeah, sir, one year's $12.55, so what?
PAUL: See, the idea is to execute this notebook, okay? So, simply, I know that this notebook should be executed.
PAUL: Pick a different… no, no, no, VectorDB. I don't want to pick a different VectorDB, guys. I know that it will work that way.
PAUL: Because previously, I always test my code, no, it's not directly I come here and execute, so… poll rates.
PAUL: I'm just creating a new environment.
PAUL: And, I think I need few packages from here.
PAUL: Just wait.
PAUL: Okay, install all packages in DVJuly. Alright, these are the… IP going, we go.
PAUL: Fine.
PAUL: Because here, a lot of other things are there.
PAUL: LandChain, generative AI, all that.
PAUL: Let me directly do that then.
PAUL: UV, I'm just gone.
PAUL: Forgive me.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Because it should work. That's right. If it doesn't work till now also, Probably.
PAUL: I will try, in the next class.
PAUL: Alright, it's a new environment, I feel. Because of that, it's taking some time. Alright.
PAUL: Okay, document loading… Then comes your text splitting.
PAUL: Then comes your embedding, then comes your vector store, Okay, factors to indexlorite.
PAUL: Okay, now let's invoke the retriever.
PAUL: Damn, again, it crashed.
PAUL: It is crashing at this particular point when I'm invoking the retriever.
PAUL: No, no, I have saved the file. This is an optional, piece of code, actually.
PAUL: I don't think…
PAUL: It is required, okay? This is optional. You don't need to execute this, because, right now, by default, it is loaded.
PAUL: You did it?
PAUL: Alright, I will just look into it, because I don't think it should happen.
PAUL: Mean mirror files is not defined.
PAUL: Hmm… Just clicked.
PAUL: Because I think I have defined files somewhere, just wait.
PAUL: Yes, fire is defined here, so I know that, yes.
PAUL: It should be up and working.
PAUL: And generally, like, if you have the embedding which is created, you don't need to create directly, you can load it also. So, for example.
PAUL: Okay, so if I go here…
PAUL: Okay, a meeting is not defined. Okay, I need to execute.
PAUL: Where embedding definition was termed.
PAUL: Because this is the main cellulite.
PAUL: Okay, I will just look into this crash issue, because for a few people it is executing, as you have told, but few people it is crashing, really, like,
PAUL: Because the other we had to look into.
PAUL: Alright, in the meantime, I know a few people might have some installation issues, okay? I will look into that one first. Okay, first only, I will be taking… looking into people who are facing installation issues in today's class. Then I will come to other questions. So, one by one, you guys can start raising your hand, okay?
PAUL: I will just stop sharing.
PAUL: Okay, people who have, first of all, installation issues, they first raise their hand.
PAUL: Because at least the things that I'm doing, or the previous notebook that I have executed, those things should be at least executing in your system. Yes, the class is finished, okay?
PAUL: Probably, like, if this is not working.
PAUL: Because I think this is the starting month, so… probably… because this is a very small thing, I need only 15 to 20 minutes to do this. But,
PAUL: That's why I feel that sometimes extra classes are much good.
PAUL: Alright, Naga, yes, please tell me. People who are having install and shipping issues, please let me know. I have issue with OpenAI and PyPDF.
PAUL: Web app, Maroke. Alright, web app.
PAUL: Yes.
PAUL: What is the…
Naga: You must have… How do I share my screen?
PAUL: Is there a share button here around scenes? No, no, no, no, no, I will add you to panelist, but then only you can see.
Naga: Okay.
Vaibhav Kumar: Who is going first?
PAUL: Naga is going first, then Webb. Others, please mention in the chat?
PAUL: R is asking if we want to use OpenAI, then what do we need to buy credits, yes.
PAUL: But in free accounts, you have limited credits that you can use, but remember, they get exhausted very quickly. Okay, like, if you try to do a few embedding operations and LLM calls, it will be exhausted. After that, you need to do, because with every new account.
PAUL: I think they give you, close to $5 credits that can be used.
PAUL: Always buy the bare minimum, like $5 or $6, something like that.
PAUL: Okay, I think the minimum is 6.
PAUL: Okay, so use that.
PAUL: Okay, yes, others can drop, yes, you guys can drop.
PAUL: Okay? Yes.
Naga: I started with the…
PAUL: Now, tell me your installation issue, like, what is the issue that you are facing?
Naga: Yeah, the issue I was facing was, it was saying one error, which was the first one we were executing, like,
PAUL: The first one is the introduction and fundamentals that only we have executed today.
PAUL: I'm using Google Generation, but if you find it, just be sure you are using the Gemini model.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Yeah.
Naga: direction.
PAUL: which is deprecated.
PAUL: Alright.
Naga: What's…
PAUL: Just wait people who are having issues.
Naga: So… some aren't…
PAUL: Tell me the error.
Naga: I don't… Python, I have 3.11, okay. Then, when I try to… do this, I'm getting,
Naga: LandChain is not there. Import line chain and check for some.
PAUL: So, like, in Python, if you… I think you are comfortable with Python.
PAUL: In Python, when you get… if in Python, if you get a module not found there, so what is the meaning of that?
Naga: Yeah, that import is, I mean, I've not imported that one. That environment also, I think I… when I tried to do an environment, it was giving me an error, like,
Naga: C.
Naga: I'm gonna take it…
PAUL: CCC.
Naga: Yeah, that.
PAUL: Error.
PAUL: C.
Naga: Huh?
PAUL: Just listen first.
PAUL: Based on the error, if it's a module not found error, it means that there is some issue with respect to the import. If there is an issue with respect to the import, first thing that you need to check is that the package is installed or not.
PAUL: So, for that, you can do a simple pip show, okay? And just be sure that the environment at where you have installed lan chain, the same place, or basically the same environment, you are using it for the kernel also. These are the simple three things that you need to take care of.
Naga: No, but, like, it was saying some, like, the permissions not available for some, you know, in here.
PAUL: Show me, show me where permissions are not available. Show me.
PAUL: Because without CPRS, it's very hard for me to…
Naga: Yeah, here, right, yeah, it's not digitally signed, it was coming. Then I bypassed this one, okay, so…
Naga: Okay, we may activate.
PAUL: So, first of all, why you are using partial, just tell me. In Saturday's class, I have to always use CMD, CMD, CMD.
Naga: Sorry, PowerShell, why I'm using, that's what you're saying.
PAUL: Yeah.
Naga: -
PAUL: Because most of the things are supported in CMD, in partial, a lot of error that comes into the picture.
Naga: Our shell is not around, so how do I go to sleep?
PAUL: It's a simple drop-down option is, these things I have done on Saturday.
PAUL: I've shown how to change shells. Yes, from there, there is a drop-down. You can select whichever shell, like, command prompt is the one.
Naga: Oh, okay, no one.
PAUL: Yes.
PAUL: Now your environment is getting… so, by default, you can see this is the base environment.
PAUL: So, whichever environment you have created for, for, activate that environment first.
Naga: Upload…
PAUL: These are environment things, this is nothing related, this is pure Python stuff that you are doing. There is no land chain and other stuff.
Naga: So, now install…
Naga: So, the initial document goes…
PAUL: So, just tell me…
PAUL: What is the name of the virtual environment?
Naga: Test. Test was the name of the virtual target.
PAUL: Then activate the test.
Naga: Okay, bye.
PAUL: We are using local vector TV, yes. Right now, I'm not switching to cloud, but later, like, after 2 weeks or 3 weeks, in cloud, in every… there is a limit of 2GB, Kartiki. Okay, like, 2GB, 3GB, I think, whoever is asking this question with respect to cloud.
PAUL: Okay, then comes over, if I give chunk size of 121,
PAUL: For ICKS, no. K can be any number. You can select the top K is represent for the top K chunks. So, how many number of chunks that you want to be retrieved? Okay, retrieved will be based on the similarity score.
PAUL: Even I don't know the solution, I have to then actually run by all the command moddas.
PAUL: Because in my case, I'll be just creating a virtual environment. I have no idea whether it's on Conda, okay, UV, VNV, really.
PAUL: Because this is a clear Pythonic issue, till now, nothing is related to AI or anything.
PAUL: So, right, what you are planning to do, at least tell me that.
Naga: No, no, I'm planning to… see, first I want to activate the, activate the…
PAUL: So, if you are trying to plan, then activate the environment. So, what you are thinking?
Naga: So… Activate. It was the command, original command for that, with, in which document?
PAUL: everything there is… Actually, that is the company.
Vaibhav Kumar: just type activate and the name of the virtual environment that should work. Activate space.
Naga: Activate slash test, okay?
PAUL: has not used conda.
Naga: But Gonda, I was not intending to use at the house.
Naga: Oh, he wasn't… I mean…
PAUL: Alright.
Naga: I can't open that.
PAUL: The idea is, you know your system, so you… whichever way, I told you UV, I told you VNB, I told you conda. Now, the idea is, for all those three steps, there is a way of activating that bar.
PAUL: Because… This is something not related to Lambjing. It's simple Python stuff.
Naga: Yeah, oh, that's…
PAUL: Okay, next, I think, who was the…
Naga: No, no, I mean, like, can I… no, no, can I please, I mean, like, I… this is a Windows one.
PAUL: You take your time, man. You take your time.
Naga: It's not a matter of taking time, like, that initial thing, right? So basically, Windows, if one person able to do, like, I mean, I can follow through, or at least I can…
Naga: It's a thing.
PAUL: Same thing, say, in Windows, Mac, if I'm talking about, for example, only your command activation, that might change. The rest of the stuff is pretty much the standard.
PAUL: Like, first of all, you have created a test environment. The basic requirement was to activate the test environment. Now, based on your system, so generally, like, how you have created that.
PAUL: Like, I don't know that thing only. Like, he told, like, active tests, so generally that is for quantum.
PAUL: You are already inside your land chain, so.
Naga: I'm inside right now.
PAUL: Okay, generally, it is inside a folder, call it scripts, inside that script, there is, I think, you have something like, test script activate, activate.bat, some file will be there. So, simply execute that file and activate the environment. So, why you were thinking so much?
PAUL: In the left-hand side, you can see all the folders. That folder, scripts folder is already opened.
PAUL: Now, these are really, like, nothing that I can do here.
PAUL: Because this is Pythonic stuff.
Naga: Activate.ps1, okay, this one is there under the, test scripts, okay, CD, test…
PAUL: Bevo? Yes, next.
Vaibhav Kumar: Let me share my screen. I am also having a problem of similar nature.
Naga: And I mean, like.
PAUL: I'm just…
Naga: one problem is solved for the Windows, at least, I mean, the people can… because the thing is, you went into Mac and went into different, different environments, and the people are, like, all over. I mean, the thing is, like, if you are doing on a day in, day out, that's a different thing.
PAUL: The steps are pretty much clear. You create an environment, you activate the environment, and you install the packages.
PAUL: Now, if I'm going to do so, simply delete. Delete everything. Delete your environment and everything, delete.
Naga: Because when I come, it's simple, the idea is from scratch.
PAUL: Okay, so first of all, any existing environment that you have deleted.
PAUL: Because this is nothing related to Langchen, that's why it's simple Saturday class that we are discussing.
PAUL: Simply, first of all, create an environment, show me the command.
PAUL: Like, Python-M, or U, V, V, and V, how you create it. I have no idea, so tell me that.
PAUL: Tell me quickly.
Naga: Yeah, and I think I noted down here.
PAUL: No, let's see, yes, so, like, how you created, just tell me.
Naga: Joe.
PAUL: You are not using contact.
Naga: Yikes.
Naga: I… yeah, I was… I mean, I… I… yeah, I can use Konda, I mean, actually, like, let me create this, okay? Create, okay, RG, no, let me try this again.
PAUL: Because I feel that you have used BNV somewhere, that's why.
Naga: yummy?
Jainika: Hold on,
Jainika: I have created… I was getting same issue, so after that, I create a virtual environment, and then link that.
PAUL: Regarding the kernel.
Jainika: So, yes, that is working fine, but after that, I got one issue, wherein the API key of OpenAI, it is, in my code, it is found that it is getting, it is loaded from .env file, but it is not…
Jainika: For authentication error I am getting. So, do I need to purchase OpenAPI key, or…
PAUL: Go to the credit section and check how much credits is left, first of all. That is the first step for OpenAI. Generally, for free accounts, I feel that they give you $5 credits. Once that gets exhausted, then you need to do a referral. So, for free users, yes. Like, I think $5. Please have a check on that.
Mudassar Hakim: I think it may…
Jainika: Almost 0.00 total spent 0.00.
Mudassar Hakim: Yeah.
PAUL: If it is 000, so nothing. It means that you have to do a refill operation. Otherwise, you can use Gemini for now.
PAUL: Just to do the initialization. In Gemini, you have that, Gemini Embedding 001 model. That model also you can use. That is free of cost.
Mudassar Hakim: Yeah, I think in my case, I have the key, I have the credits also, but it's not reading the .enf file. I directly post the… paste the key, and it works for me.
PAUL: Okay, you past the key, means, hard-coded.
Mudassar Hakim: Yeah, if I directly hard-coded the key when creating the…
PAUL: Have you created .env file?
Mudassar Hakim: Yes, I mean, I have an existing .env file. It was first env underscore example, so I renamed it to .env.
PAUL: Okay, fine, fine, fine, fine. It should work, actually, just show me it.
Naga: Sure, yeah, sorry, go ahead, go ahead, Naga. Yeah, I completed the activation of the RAG Naga, okay? I've done that one, I… and then now.
PAUL: No, I've heard that.
Naga: Hello, man.
PAUL: Yes.
PAUL: First, create the environment, activate the environment, install the backup.
Naga: I'm already there in the environment. Now I should, activate the…
Naga: Now I should install the line chain?
PAUL: Yes, all the packages that were mentioned, so simply you can.
Naga: in Guatemal.
PAUL: install hyphen R, that particular command that you can install, pip install hyphen R, space, REQ, yes.
PAUL: Alright, yeah, in the meantime, others who want to share their screen, please?
Vaibhav Kumar: My problem got auto-resolved with 2-3 reattempts. In one file, PyPDF is not working. In 01 introduction in simple langchain, it is able to read, I will not take time off the entire cohort, and let me debug it individually. More or less, it started working after 2-3 reattempts.
Vaibhav Kumar: Probably, immediately.
Rajat Khanna: Paul, can I share?
Salman: and I go.
PAUL: Yeah, yeah.
PAUL: Rajat, you want to share? Fine. Yes, Rajat, I am adding.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, thank you.
PAUL: Yes, now Naga, so… And with respect to the installation?
Naga: -
Naga: Yeah, the requirements was of your file.
PAUL: the requirements I have already provided, I think… have you updated that by deleting the versions in class when I told?
PAUL: Just scroll down, no? In the File Explorer, just scroll down on the left-hand side. Yes, scroll down, there is the requirement.txt.
Naga: This is in the land chain requirements, so-called land chain requirement.
PAUL: Including.
Naga: No, we've installed requirements, okay.
Naga: Let's… go through.
PAUL: Show me the requirements, have you updated versions or not?
PAUL: That's why. The versions are there. In class, I told so many times, please remove the versions.
PAUL: Open notion, first of all, open notion.
Naga: Okay, okay.
PAUL: In Notion, I have copy-pasted that without the version, copy and paste it, and quickly do the installation.
PAUL: Yeah, Salman, I know, but nothing that I can do. You can understand.
PAUL: Initially, I know one month… Python problems we need to face.
PAUL: Alright, next, I think, whoever wants to share screen, I think Rajat told no. Rajat, go ahead and share. I think multiple screen sharing I have enabled from my side.
Nirbhay Rana: I cannot say that, all nearby this side.
Naga: Yes, so… exploring the language…
PAUL: Okay, Muddhasara started sharing, just wait, I think 2 is there, let me look into Muddhasar's. Right now, yeah, Mudassar, tell me now. Incorrect API key.
PAUL: Alright, see, now your hard-quoted .env file, okay?
PAUL: Actually, load .env file, like, you don't need to mention .env. Keep it at the top only, the top part, the top part.
Naga: requirement of…
PAUL: Okay.
Naga: Oh, God.
PAUL: Rajat, I will look into his skin, just wait, okay? I'm looking into Mantas' screen right now.
PAUL: Okay, so this is the step which is important. Okay, so from .env import, okay, alright, load.env, I've specifically mentioned the file name also. This is fine, there is no issue in that. So, it's telling OpenAI API key found, alright, Google API key found.
PAUL: Okay?
PAUL: So, the program is telling, yes, it is found. Now, where it is telling that not found, again, tell me.
PAUL: You know?
Naga: Installation.
PAUL: Yes, tell me like that, because the Python program is detecting that.
Rajat Khanna: Okay. Paul, can I go now?
Rajat Khanna: Rajad, this…
PAUL: oest.getEnv.
PAUL: Adjust with Rajit. I'm looking into Mudhasa's screen.
Naga: Yes, sir.
Naga: could not find the version that satisfies the requirement of terms. So, where the…
PAUL: I think it's a smallish move, Jasa, just, look. Okay, otherwise, okay, Rajat, now just tell me. I'm looking into your screen.
Naga: Can I… just one question. This…
Naga: I'm supposed to keep the… and the…
PAUL: Remove the versions. Just copy-paste this entire thing and paste it in your requirement.txt.
Naga: That's how you pulled Oko.
Naga: This impacting, again, the public business.
PAUL: Rajab.
Rajat Khanna: So Paul, as you can see, the Langchain is installed, it's showing me the version, okay? Now if I go to this code, it shows, this error.
PAUL: Attribute error.
Rajat Khanna: Yeah.
PAUL: Alright, scroll down, scroll down, move down a little bit, yeah, the end at the end, here.
PAUL: Attribute Langchain has no attribute debug, okay, alright?
PAUL: It's probably a version issue only, that I feel. Okay, go above a little bit.
PAUL: Because exactly, what is the version that I'm using? Scroll up a little bit.
PAUL: Okay? Because when you are invoking the chain attribute error, chain.invoke, okay? So,
PAUL: With respect to change, just wait, let me check on that it was in the package.
Naga: a little bit.
PAUL: Good.
PAUL: The chain was available inside the package.
PAUL: Lanchan Core. Just check your, like, Lanshan Core version. It was showing 0.3.7, no?
PAUL: Check once.
PAUL: What is the version of your lanchein pool?
Rajat Khanna: 0.3.
PAUL: 7, 9.
Rajat Khanna: Yeah.
PAUL: Yeah, it was the same for me, also.
Naga: Quran.
PAUL: Beautiful.
PAUL: Yes, this is fine, there is no issue with that.
PAUL: But exactly… like, attribute error, because chain don't invoke when you are doing. And chain, we have defined it.
PAUL: put this…
PAUL: This is a version issue, basically, because I know
PAUL: Some package or some dependency package is failing because of that, it is unable to do it.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, so next question is, this is my environment file, is this the correct key?
PAUL: It cannot never be the correct…
Rajat Khanna: Yeah.
PAUL: It is always 60 to 20 characters, that's all.
Rajat Khanna: So, how to copy it from here?
PAUL: Delete, delete, delete, delete. Or otherwise, create a new key, rebook this one.
PAUL: Okay, and… okay, create a new key. It only shows once.
PAUL: That's me.
PAUL: Okay, yes.
PAUL: Default project, right second key. It will only show you once, remember.
PAUL: Okay.
Naga: fight, even though…
PAUL: Now, you will see that it will be a long key. Okay, and delete the key after the class.
PAUL: As you have exposed it, okay?
Rajat Khanna: Okay, and now, if I go here… So this… One minute.
PAUL: After doing Ctrl-S, you can try to load the environment.
PAUL: I will show you that API key.
Rajat Khanna: Okay.
Rajat Khanna: Why? Load environment EME file…
PAUL: Import, import, import. First of all, import load.env in the imports, and then execute.
PAUL: In the top cell, there will be import, no? First of all, import will be there. Execute this cell first.
PAUL: From .env import, load underscore, that is the main module. Under that module, you have that. Okay, now you click on this one.
Rajat Khanna: Okay. Okay, got it. Because I was getting, later, I was getting the authentication error. So, now here, I think it will work now.
PAUL: No.
Rajat Khanna: Now it's going authentication.
PAUL: Check how much credits you have in your OpenAI account.
Rajat Khanna: Where, where to, where's that option?
PAUL: click on the settings, I think somewhere the settings on your profile, I can just click.
PAUL: There is platform.openai only, no. Usage, go on usage then, at least. I think Manage Usage, yeah.
PAUL: In my case, it always shows that settings button inside.
Rajat Khanna: Budget.
Rajat Khanna: issuing $5, I think.
PAUL: Yes.
PAUL: Then you have $5, I think, in your account.
PAUL: Okay, because if you have $5, it should work. Let me just check that…
Rajat Khanna: You know…
PAUL: Because how you will do the refill for that, there is a specific ID.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, so that's why I feel that.
PAUL: You should've been in that URL, just wait.
PAUL: In my, URL, you'll just wait.
PAUL: Settings slash… API keys.
PAUL: Okay, yeah, so, like, is your account an organization one?
Rajat Khanna: No. No, it's just a normal Google, my personal Google account.
PAUL: No, no, no, no. The idea is, by default, every account has an organization attached to that. I've shared the URL, just tried to open this URL once.
PAUL: billing. The idea is I need to check that billing part.
PAUL: Now we will get to, so, credit remaining zero, because of this.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, so do I need to add some…
PAUL: Yes, if you are working with OpenAI, you need to add at least the bare minimum is, I think, $6. It has to be more than $5, so 6 is the bare minimum. Okay, otherwise, test it with Gemini.
PAUL: Okay?
Rajat Khanna: Okay, so for… just for the Gemini, I need to change, the code imports related to the Gemini.
PAUL: to change only two things, the LLM and the embedding model. Rest, everything is same.
Rajat Khanna: Okay. Okay, I'll do that. Thank you.
PAUL: Okay, alrighty.
PAUL: Next.
Nirbhay Rana: Yahai.
PAUL: Yes.
Naga: Nearby this site. Yeah, mine is insane.
PAUL: Nerva, you want to share?
Nirbhay Rana: Yep.
PAUL: Perfect, I will add you to the panelist. Yes, Naga, tell me.
Naga: Yeah, yeah, mine is installing the current, so after this, then I will execute that simple right chain notebook, right?
PAUL: Yes, just be sure you are in the correct environment.
PAUL: The environment which you have activated, in that environment only, everything is working fine. That is the main thing. If it is working fine, okay, then it will work.
PAUL: Okay?
Naga: And next is I have to buy the $5, the thing, right? The Google…
PAUL: It is not necessary, if you want to use, go with the free version of Gemini, both the versions I have shown.
PAUL: Okay, it's not necessary that you have to buy in Gemini also here. You need two things. One embedding model, one LLM. Both are things Gemini provides us for free. So simply, like, you can go ahead and use that.
PAUL: Okay, it's not necessary you have to purchase. If you want, then we…
Naga: Okay.
PAUL: Okay? Alright.
Nirbhay Rana: Yeah.
PAUL: Yes, ma'am, just for your issue resolved?
Mudassar Hakim: No, I don't know, I'm… maybe there's some naming mismatch? I… I can move if I do it in that same file.
Mudassar Hakim: But, strangely… I don't know why it's…
PAUL: It's not getting recognized, no.
PAUL: OpenAI key, show me.envify, just wait.
PAUL: APAC…
PAUL: OpenE underscore EP underscore key is equal to SK. Okay. Now, when you try to import, tell me, what is the error that you are getting? Here, because here it's telling…
Mudassar Hakim: It says your open API key name key here.
Mudassar Hakim: Very strange.
Mudassar Hakim: I have not given this text, but it says this.
Mudassar Hakim: Sweden.
PAUL: No, actually, in this… Right? Delete, delete .env5, recreate it.
Mudassar Hakim: Good.
PAUL: anything.
PAUL: Delete it, recreate it. Just a small thing.
Mudassar Hakim: Okay. Okay. TK.
PAUL: Generally, what happens, like.env, if you press, like, Ctrl-S, if the file is not saved, but you have already saved, so I feel that is it. So, delete .env file, and just recreate the file. I think that will be the best, yeah.
PAUL: The lower controllers completely?
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Now, first import, I think, because you have to restart, restart, always restart the kernel whenever you are doing these type of major changes.
Mudassar Hakim: Oh, okay, okay, okay, got it.
PAUL: Okay, and now,
PAUL: First, directly import section. Skip this, because this is not required. Import, import. Import, below, that one, that one. Below that.
PAUL: environment setup, after this, after this, this is not required, this is just a Python check.
PAUL: This is also not required, this is the Langchen version. Okay, yes, this is the main part.
Mudassar Hakim: Oh, we're doing.
PAUL: God quickly.
Mudassar Hakim: Some glitch, most probably, then.
PAUL: That's why. Whenever you feel that, delete. Because there are certain glitches even I feel, okay? Like, sometimes this not detected, this not detected, it happens. I feel so sad, sometimes I skip it. Just delete it, and it's always better.
Mudassar Hakim: Yep, correct, thanks.
PAUL: Okay, alright. Yes, nearby.
Salman: I can't see share screen button enabled for me.
PAUL: I'm not enabled. First, let me just complete few of the panels, then only I will add you, okay? Just because I think…
Naga: Not firm. For me, like, if I run this, it's still saying modular error, not form.
PAUL: So, how do you know…
Naga: How do I install the…
PAUL: So right now, the installation is going on, it looks like.
Naga: Yeah, but, like, the initial packages might have installed, right? Already the Langston, these packages might have already installed, the core one. Right now, the one going on is very…
PAUL: Let's see, right now I can see you are in the test environment.
Naga: Yeah, right now, I'm not in the test standard length.
PAUL: I can see on the coroner it's written test.
Naga: Yeah, test, I need to change that test to the Naga environment. Whichever environment?
PAUL: Click on select another kernel, select another kernel.
Naga: Select another channel. Okay, yeah, I'm going. Then…
PAUL: You can… yes, existing Jupyter servers.
PAUL: Conda integration is not there.
PAUL: Because you need… do you have any .py scripts, generally?
PAUL: Because you need to select that Python compiler, as simple as that.
Naga: Yeah, that one is in Conda, but I'm not seeing that. Select another kernel, okay, and I'm seeing existing Jupyter server.
Naga: Okay.
PAUL: Okay, no, this is a server, it's an online one. It is not required. You have to actually give the path of that python.exe. Okay, that path, that needs to be fed there.
PAUL: That is the main thing.
PAUL: Okay, nearby, tell me, what is the issue that you are facing?
Nirbhay Rana: So, yeah, so Paul, I'm getting this error in, like, this, your first LLM call cell. So, in this length in OpenAI, it… I have already, like, installed this using the pip install in my environment, but it is still showing this kind of error, like.
Nirbhay Rana: Initialization.
PAUL: OAS error, this is OAS error.
Nirbhay Rana: DLL, okay, this is another error, this is system-related issue.
PAUL: Okay.
Nirbhay Rana: So, how can I resolve that one?
PAUL: Because this error is something like OS level that we do face, it's something, like, really not related to Python.
PAUL: One thing, just try to delete the entire environment, okay? And one thing, just try to do, copy that import line, copy that import line, which was failing.
Nirbhay Rana: Obviously, what's physically matter?
PAUL: Yeah, yeah, yeah, the first that, from Langchen OpenAI, I copied that line. As you have opened the terminal, just write there Python and hit enter.
PAUL: right there, Python initiative.
PAUL: Python… Python and hit enter. Python and hit enter.
Nirbhay Rana: Okay.
PAUL: You have to delete.
PAUL: Just write Python.
PAUL: And hit enter. Later on, we will paste that once the shell is open.
Naga: Oh, yeah, I'm dead.
Naga: Okay, now I switched, huh? Okay.
PAUL: Okay. Now, this is Python-related, because your Python is only not getting called. That's why. Okay, delete the environment, create a new one. That is the only solution for now.
PAUL: This is… somehow the virtual environment got corrupted, okay?
Naga: Okay, Paul, I changed to the rag now, okay?
Nirbhay Rana: So, I will do that, and then if any issue persists, then I will, again.
PAUL: Okay, welcome.
Nirbhay Rana: the call. Okay.
Naga: Boom.
PAUL: Yes, Amit, do you want to share?
Naga: Oops.
Amit Singh: Am I audible?
PAUL: Yeah, okay. Yes, yes, you were already evalamita, I'm adding Sid, Rohan, Joe.
Sid: Yeah, bro.
PAUL: Janika, you guys can let me know.
Sid: Yeah, so can I…
Rohan: Ice cream?
PAUL: Rohanie.
PAUL: Rohan, yes, you can share your screen.
Sid: out here.
PAUL: Is it fun?
Naga: And this is…
Rohan: My issue is not related to installment.
PAUL: Okay, Rowan, ask your question there.
Naga: Mine's powerful.
Rohan: Yeah, I was able to execute the notebook completely, and I'm using Gemini, not OpenAI. My question is related to the chunking strategy that you're saying, that you use dynamic chunking based on the type of the file, or the file name, different chunking size. Can you elaborate on that, please?
PAUL: You have to do the research for each type of file type, for example, for Markdown, JSON, CSV. Based on different file types, you will be keeping different chunk sizing.
PAUL: So, you never keep it static, like, for every type of file type, you keep that fixed formula, which will be used. It's better to have a dynamic level chunking, okay? If this file comes into the picture, please follow this chunking rule. If this file comes into the picture, follow this rule.
PAUL: It totally depends upon your data. You have to analyze your data, and then you have to take that decision.
PAUL: All these data files go into… all these go into one data source, right? In one vector database? So we can… Yes.
Rohan: So we keep.
PAUL: Oh.
Rohan: Even after every… even if different chunking size, we still have the same vector embedding size, and everything goes in the same vector source.
PAUL: Yes.
Rohan: Okay, another question I had was, so when we were doing the chunking, it was showing, like, we were providing a chunk size of, 2024, but the average chunk size is very small compared to that, like…
Rohan: Even if it was 512, the chunk size that we provided.
PAUL: It totally depends upon you. I told you that is a hyperparameter, and you only take the 10%, 10 to 20%, you can select any person between that, that will be the chunk overlap. 1024, like, it's pretty much common. 768, common. These are pretty common numbers that people test it out.
Rohan: Oh, no, sorry, the average chunk size that it shows, even if you put a thousand chunk size, and when you run the chunking, the average chunk size that you see in the output, it's very, less.
PAUL: It will be low, because, generally what happens, you'll see.
PAUL: In chunking, what happens? I told you, in chunking, there is a concept of separators.
PAUL: If in the separators, by default, just think about only one lanking.
PAUL: Okay, or probably at the end of the document, it was only there. So, when the average is calculated, that number will always go down. So, don't think about, it will be always so many. It means that it cannot maintain that, it has to drop. Nobody can maintain that.
Rohan: Okay.
PAUL: Because, see, at the end of the day, if there are 10 different pages, and probably in some paragraph, it was only one line or two lines, but at the end of the day, the separation is taking place based on that text splitter mechanism.
PAUL: No.
Rohan: Okay, so the is the splitter, separated?
PAUL: Yes, yes, that is the main thing. In the splitter, you were telling that, okay, this is the Mac.
PAUL: 1024, but it's not necessary, it can be lesser also. If it could find a paragraph, it will break.
PAUL: So, analyze the chunk. So, what you can do, you… I only showed you 3 chunks. You tried to print out, at least 50 chunks, and try to analyze the data.
Rohan: Okay, yeah, yeah, I think, my conviction was, we start… I was thinking we start with a chunk size, and that's how it splits, but, now it's clear that we first start with the separator, and then if it's more than the chunk size, then we chunk it back.
PAUL: not… that is the max limit of the chunk that you provide. It's not that, it has to be more. It is the max size. It can be lesser, but not more.
Rohan: So, if my passage size, a paragraph, I split by paragraph, and if the paragraph size is 2000, and my chunk size is 1000, so it will split into two separate chunks.
PAUL: The first one, based on your chunk size, for example, your chunk size is 1000, and your total size is 2000. Yes, the first, if it is a single paragraph, then I can say that, yes, it will be in two parts.
PAUL: Okay, but just think about if you have that 2000 into 7 different paragraphs. So I can say that, yes, based on the paragraph, it is divided into 7 different chunks, and each chunk might have small sizes.
Rohan: Okay, okay, got it. Thank you so much.
Naga: Whoa.
Sid: Eyeball.
Naga: Paul, I have this question here.
PAUL: Yes, Salman. Salman, please share your screen.
Salman: Yeah.
PAUL: I think you're saving it.
Salman: You are able to see my screen, yeah? No.
PAUL: Yes, yes, yes, yes.
Salman: Okay, so let me…
Salman: So what the error I'm getting here is… see this, when I was running this requirement.txt,
PAUL: Fire CPU, okay? Just, do a pip install file CPU and show me, like, a work.
PAUL: Why this is fake is a little bit tough. Okay, just… Do it in the terminal.
PAUL: You can do it there also, but I prefer the terminal always.
PAUL: For package installation. Because you can restart the kernel after the execution, yeah.
PAUL: Just to pip install.
PAUL: Fire hyphen CPU.
PAUL: A F-A-I-S-S, no spelling, just be sure it is correct here, hyphen sequel.
PAUL: Okay.
Salman: Yeah.
PAUL: Now, the build is failing, and there is probably a problem with PIP.
PAUL: Oh, okay.
Salman: Do I need to update the PIP?
PAUL: Really, because they're just 0.2 to 0.3, not a big one.
Salman: So I need to update the pip from outside the environment, or inside it?
PAUL: This is a build field error, probably some C++ packages, as I can see, Swig, Python, C++ override.
PAUL: You have to look for this package, and you have to install, like, brew install. Okay, so this is a… because FISE has a C++ requirement.
PAUL: And during the installation, it could not do the C++ build, so I feel that in your system, there are certain C++ dependencies which are missing that needs to be installed. After that, you can do the installation.
Salman: Okay, okay, so I need to troubleshoot it. Just upgrading the pip will not help.
PAUL: No, no, no, just that build error that you got, no, for Swig. Generally, for C++ builds, Swig is used. Take that screenshot and just paste it in ChatGPT, it will tell you, like, brew, install, Swig, and a few other commands will be there. Okay, please try to do that execution. It's a C++ build issue.
Salman: Okay, and I didn't get a chance to ask some questions yesterday, so can I ask it now?
PAUL: Mmm, okay, go ahead.
Salman: Okay. So, yesterday, you know,
Salman: I was just trying to understand the whole flow. So, as I understand, you know, first the ingestion pipeline works. You, just pick all the documents, split it into the chunk, and then
Salman: load it into some vector DB after applying embedding on it. And then comes the retriever part. So, retrieval part starts from the query, user query, and the user goes
Salman: and hit the vector DB, and the context is returned. So, context has the user query part, because when you… yesterday, when you were showing the diagram, you just mentioned the context plus query.
PAUL: So I'm just trying…
PAUL: after, as you told, once the context is retrieved, okay? So there, now, that retrieved contract, that retrieved context needs to be sent to the LLM.
PAUL: So, in… so, when you are sending the information to the LLM, we sent three things. One, the query, the other one is basically the prompt, and the other one is the retripped context. That part.
PAUL: Okay, because…
Salman: The context has the query in it, in the vector.
PAUL: No, no, no, no, no, no, that is different, no. Retrative context is totally different. It's basically the chance, so how it will know what is the question? It's just based on your question, it did the similarity score, and it told you, this is the retrieve context.
PAUL: Now, when you are sending the information to the LLM, so LLM will know the question, the context, and as well as the prompt, how you want that particular output to be structured.
Salman: Okay, okay. And context is the output of the retriever.
PAUL: The top K chunks, that is only context that we are telling.
Salman: And retriever is somewhere where non-parameter memory is built upon.
PAUL: Retriever, you cannot see it. Let's say, right now you are doing a fetching operation on and on the non-parametric memory directly.
PAUL: Okay, so don't say that, because right now, you are just doing a similarity score operation, where you are trying to compare two embeddings based on the similarity score. That is the main thing.
Salman: Okay, let's say my parametric memory is, like, you know, is a part of my LLM, is stored in my LLM.
PAUL: Yes, correct.
Salman: Where is my non-parametric memory?
Salman: In vector database.
Salman: Okay, okay.
PAUL: all your PDFs have been converted into numbers, and those numbers are saved in your VectorDB, that becomes your non-parallel.
Salman: Non-parametric setup. Okay, and in adaptive approach, you said that there are two judges, right? LLM as a judges, which can help me to find the optimal parameter. Is that the right understanding? Or it will just.
PAUL: It's not the…
PAUL: parameter, it decides that… it will decide, first of all, whether should I invoke the retriever or not. If the LLM knows the answer, it is fine, then directly you can generate. If it doesn't know, then it will take the path of entire retrieval process.
PAUL: With query decomposition.
Salman: But we cannot build a judge which gives me the optimal parameter. Hyperparameter.
PAUL: Bob.
PAUL: Optimal… what is a hyperparameter you are referring to?
Salman: let's say, suppose if I… I mean, I build a judge, which gives me, you know, this output is not up to the mark, go back and take another iteration.
PAUL: That is the second judge who… that is the second judge who is doing that.
PAUL: There are two judges in adaptive. The first judge is only responsible to take the decision, that, okay, direct generation, or through retrieval. Okay, so then the second judge does that, the evaluation of the answer.
Salman: So, the second judge, after the evaluation, will it give me, or can I build it to give me the… what… like, okay, I need to go back, take another iteration, but will.
PAUL: Yes, yes, that there will be two tokens based on a threshold that we will decide. One will be the retrieve, one will be the continue. If it says continue, it means that your answer is fine. If retrieve comes into the picture, it means that, again, regeneration, or basically, again, retrieval will be triggered.
Salman: But with which parameter? Will it give me some threshold to adjust the… now try with this threshold?
PAUL: You have to set the threshold for that particular LLM. Okay, I need to try it myself. Yes.
Salman: Okay.
Salman: Okay, and…
PAUL: I will always tell the LLM that, okay, these are the rules that needs to be followed for this particular evaluation. Okay, now, based on that, LLM will do the evaluation.
Salman: Okay, and I was just trying to read the paper, which you, you know, tried to explain, in previous Saturday, or Sunday, I guess. There was terms like differential retriever… retriever. What does it mean, differential?
PAUL: See, the idea is that at any point of time, when you try to use, like, different… there are different architectures of retrieval. Very specifically, the one that we are using, it's pretty much based on, dense passage retrieval technique.
PAUL: But there are others also, where you change it, like, decoder-based, or encoder-decoder-based. So, based on that, the architecture changes. So, differential encoders, it includes, like, encoder as well as decoder.
PAUL: Okay, generally, we have seen people are using encoders much more in retrieval, but in few GPT-based architectures, we have seen that even then, because GPT is pretty much a decoder-based architecture, that's why.
Salman: Right, yeah.
Salman: Okay.
Salman: And also, let's say if you can use the embedding from Gemini, an LLM from OpenAI, or any open source from Hugging Face, is that compatible or advisable?
PAUL: No, no, no, no, no, you should've…
Salman: I'll be using…
PAUL: Yes, only one provider. Because that numbers which is generating, there are certain proprietary… they have a rule or a formula that you can think.
Salman: Yeah, in that vector space, okay.
PAUL: Yes, so the similarity score results will be highly impacted. Because of that, the results of the RAG will be very bad.
Salman: We cannot do cross-c connection, okay. And the simple rack notebook which you shared today, you will be deploying it in AWS, or it ends here?
PAUL: Simple… for now, I won't be doing any deployment. This is just a simple one. I'll be developing programs, okay, where a lot of things, other things will be there. Here, it's written…
Salman: A little bit.
Salman: blank.
PAUL: Yes, it means complex logging and other stuff, modules, because I'll be creating modules at the end of the day, and those modules I'll be deploying. It's pretty much standard, because right now, because in those programs, you won't be seeing so much print statements.
PAUL: to the deployment now, as of now? Yes, yes, deployment will come at a later phase.
Salman: Okay, and in today's class also, you mentioned that, like, you know, large-scale building application. So, we'll be building some large-scale applications.
PAUL: Yes, when I…
Salman: Yeah, amazing.
PAUL: No, no. Mid-level you can think about. I won't be working with TVs of data. I will be working with GVs of data only.
Salman: But all the performance tweaking and all those things which you were talking about, we'll be applying it, right?
PAUL: It depends upon the use case that I am doing. So, in every use case, those things differ.
Salman: Okay.
PAUL: It depends upon the type of data also, no? If your data is pretty much used, then big data comes into the picture. I won't be taking those things into account. I'll be taking up pretty much the things which are done here.
PAUL: So, like, when you say…
Salman: That is where the real learning comes from, the performance tuning of the rack.
PAUL: If you are asking production, nobody can teach you production.
Salman: That is up to understanding.
PAUL: Production comes with an incremental phase.
PAUL: If you know that… if I'm building something, it takes 6 months, 3 months at least, then I have to make it better, so it's an incremental process. Once I know the cons, then I can fix it. So in one shot, I cannot say, this is the best.
PAUL: It really depends upon the use case, okay?
Salman: But we'll be building some mid-size application in this.
PAUL: Yes, yes, I'll be taking… probably I will take some GitHub only, for example. In GitHub, every file I will try to do, and then I will push it in that way. It will be complex. To teach that, I need at least 2 to 3 classes.
Salman: Okay, okay. So I'll just try to fix up this C++ error, and if anything is needed, I'll.
PAUL: Yes.
Salman: in the next class.
Salman: Okay. Thanks, Paul, and thanks for your patience.
PAUL: Alright, next, Naga, is your issue solved?
Naga: No, no, so I… I installed all the packages.
PAUL: And…
Naga: I… and then it was asking me to…
Naga: install this update force install. After this is completed, then when… whatever I executed is going in infinite loop, like this.
Naga: And… I don't know what it comes from.
Naga: Should I… is… is…
Amit Singh: Well, sir, am I audible?
PAUL: Yes, yes, you are audible.
Amit Singh: I just had a small query regarding this requirement at TXT, just wanted to understand the concept, like, and where am I going wrong?
Amit Singh: I mean, I just copy-pasted what you had in Notion, or do we…
PAUL: Because…
Amit Singh: Do we print command over? You can see my screen?
PAUL: Yes, yes, I can see.
Amit Singh: Should I write pip install, langchain, pip install, langchen Core, like that?
PAUL: No, no, see, see, see, that is individual package installation, when you do pay install this, paper install, but when you have your requirement.txtly, it means that all the packages will be listed in one file, and they will be installed in one shot.
Amit Singh: Right, right, right, that's the concept for a production… from a productionized, this thing, right?
PAUL: Later on, see, now this is a previous standard, now the standard has moved to PyProject.2ml. So, like, later on when I'll be talking about it, that is a very similar file, but you have more information about that.
Amit Singh: Pi project, you said, huh?
PAUL: pyproject.2ml.
Amit Singh: Okay, okay.
PAUL: Okay, so later on, I'll be discussing about that.
Amit Singh: So, what am I missing over here? Like, I mean, it's giving me errors every time that could not, open the requirement file, like.
PAUL: Okay, alright. Now, it's telling that the spelling of requirements. You are writing requirements, and there the name is
PAUL: One file is requirements, one is… okay, just do a simple LS, no, for now, just in terminal, write LS.
PAUL: You are on Windows or Mac?
Amit Singh: I'm on Windows.
PAUL: our idea.
Amit Singh: BIS?
PAUL: Hit enter.
Amit Singh: Okay, okay, okay, okay.
PAUL: is requirements.th, okay? Now write web install.
PAUL: Space hyphen R.
PAUL: space, REQ, press tab.
PAUL: Press tab.
PAUL: Okay? Hit enter.
Amit Singh: Hmm…
PAUL: But then also it's telling, okay, could not install package due to an OS error, no such file.
PAUL: This is Anaconda Anunusage, this is different.
PAUL: Due to an OS error. Now, OS error is coming… is it blocking something?
PAUL: like, this is always level error, because…
PAUL: You can see a C, ABA, C route in Anaconda, non-usage is going…
PAUL: It's going in different, it's… OS error, it means that's some type of permission that is getting blocked to execute this particular file.
PAUL: Okay…
Amit Singh: I activated this, I mean, I was unable to activate my… this thing.
Amit Singh: the virtual environment itself, so I went to PowerShell, I am in AGA.
Amit Singh: use Perplexity, I went to PowerShell, I ran it as an administrator.
Amit Singh: With all the commands that it gave, and then it got activated. So…
PAUL: Open the PowerShell once, like, show me that window.
PAUL: Because…
Naga: I like it. Oh!
PAUL: If you have to do run as admin, then that's a different thing, because here you don't have admin privileges in BScore.
Amit Singh: Can you see my PowerShell window?
PAUL: No, no, no, no. I can only see your VS Code window.
Naga: Or I can, I'm seeing this open API key not found is coming for me now. So, should I create an API option?
PAUL: Yes, you have to create, no, you have to create that .env file, and inside that file, you have to keep your API credentials for the OpenAI API.
Naga: Which one do you recommend, Google, sorry, Jiminy, or…
PAUL: I recommend both, always. Like, now it's your choice which one you want to use. There is no requirement.
Naga: You go to the gym, I will take the gym.
PAUL: Yes, if you want to go with Gemini, fine, then keep that Google API key.
Naga: Oh.
PAUL: We are going with Gemini, there will be certain code changes, so based on that, you have to do that.
PAUL: Alright, now, this is your partial, activate the environment, like last time, however you did, do that.
PAUL: Generally, like, in CMD, you are getting… another thing can you… you can also do that, no, run command prompt as an administrator.
Amit Singh: This is what, I mean, these are the comments it gave, like.
Naga: And your virtual environment is, created using Conda.
Amit Singh: Virtual environment is…
PAUL: how you created it, using UV, using Conda, or using VNB.
Amit Singh: Using UV.
Amit Singh: The way you told me.
PAUL: Okay, using UV only, you upgraded, fine.
PAUL: And now, Go to that path.
PAUL: Right now, it's less than 32. Go to the path.
PAUL: Alright, let me look into some other questions. Prasad Reddy, like, you are having some problems, as you wrote in the chat, I saw. Prasad, you can let me know that.
PAUL: You know?
Sid: Paul, can I go?
PAUL: Yes, go ahead, Sid.
Sid: Actually, I'm getting error in creating files index, so I'm using Google, embedding.
Sid: So, can I share my screen? So, actually, it is getting resource accessed, so is it about the quota for the day?
PAUL: What is the error?
Sid: Resource existed.
PAUL: Yes, that is the quota.
Sid: Okay, so it's per Google, like, what is the limit, if you can advise?
PAUL: Look…
PAUL: I think the limit is less, but at least you can do embeddings of at least 5 to 6 documents.
Sid: If you have done it 5 to 6 times, then it will expire.
Sid: Okay, then I need to wait, right?
PAUL: Yes. It's just like you can think about, generally it's 1 tenth of 1 million. That is the total number of tokens.
Sid: But generally, they do provide.
Sid: Okay, okay, alright, well, I'll check it later then. Thank you.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Yeah, Prasad, you can go.
Prasad Reddi: Yeah, hypothet.
PAUL: Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, Prasad. I saw your chat, ma'am. So, yes, tell me, like, where you got stuck, or anything.
Prasad Reddi: So, I'm just sharing my screen now.
PAUL: In just a bit, I will add you to the panelist, okay? Then tell me.
PAUL: Okay, Edith Vish is also there at Vishma Aishwari, Hari Kumar, yes.
Naga: Sweeta… can I take Sri Ta?
Jainika: What do you mean?
PAUL: Yes, yes. By default, it is the free tire. For your paid tire, you need to attach on credit card.
Naga: Okay.
Prasad Reddi: Yeah, hi Paul, can you see my screen?
PAUL: Yes, I can see.
Prasad Reddi: So the thing is, here I have.
PAUL: everyone in Canada.
Prasad Reddi: Yeah, open error. I have created one, ENV file, here.
Prasad Reddi: Where I have given my complete key.
PAUL: Google API key, alright, fine.
PAUL: So have you updated the code compatible to Google API?
PAUL: That is the main thing.
Prasad Reddi: Yeah, yeah, here it is given as GPT-5 Nano.
PAUL: GF.
PAUL: Okay, now…
Prasad Reddi: Is it more compatible.
PAUL: Open Notion. In Notion, I think Akush Agra shared, open notion.
Prasad Reddi: Yeah.
PAUL: In Notion, the code for Gemini is available. You can take that code.
PAUL: It's just one line, you have to change chat.
PAUL: Google generative AI, yes. See, here, once that import is there, you have to install this package, chain Google Gen AI. Go at the top, like, here, pip install hyphen U on top of that, on top of that, the above blank, yeah. See, this, no, no, no, don't do the uninstall package, the install line.
PAUL: Okay, that is the main one.
PAUL: Okay, now this package, do you have in your local machine?
PAUL: Just checking.
Prasad Reddi: Thank you, sir.
PAUL: Otherwise, you can do that UV install or install that, as simple as that.
Prasad Reddi: Okay, so I'm doing here directly.
PAUL: Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, do it, do it, do it, no worries.
Naga: Conviction… The configuration file, I have to change the… where is your API?
PAUL: you have to… I have shared no .env.example, you have to follow that particular pattern only.
Naga: He shared in the…
PAUL: I shared it in the zip file.
Naga: It does look funny, okay.
PAUL: Okay, it's been successfully installed, yeah, fine. Now, just for verification, if you feel that, okay, there can be, because it's showing some red lines here.
PAUL: Okay, probably some. One thing you can do, just write here Python and hit enter, and just try to, write your Python and hit enter in the shell.
PAUL: In the termination.
Prasad Reddi: Okay, okay. Compare that.
PAUL: And hit enter.
PAUL: Okay, now here, paste that import command. Okay, so go back to Notion. There was an import.
PAUL: From LandChain.
PAUL: That particular line just imported.
Prasad Reddi: One second.
PAUL: Just… this will help you to check that, yes, the package is working fine.
PAUL: Yes.
Prasad Reddi: Okay, so import…
PAUL: import, that one. Yes, from, only that, from, from line, no,
PAUL: Don't use that comment, it's that. Yeah, copy that and paste it in the template.
PAUL: This is just a verification, just to check that the package is up.
PAUL: I'm looking.
PAUL: Okay, Andrew.
Prasad Reddi: It says to win a single quarter.
Naga: Mr.
PAUL: No codes. Codes are not required. Directly, right? Gemini.
Naga: local.
PAUL: Or Google, I think, like…
Naga: Just save it, and no need to change anything, right? That's it. Save there and then run again.
PAUL: Save, and then restart the kernel, and then run.
Naga: Welcome, Steve.
PAUL: Now, you can see here it's taking some time, so… okay, it worked.
Prasad Reddi: Yeah, it's imported, yeah.
PAUL: Yeah, okay, now you can restart, restart the kernel, always restart the kernel.
Naga: I was instructed before.
PAUL: If you are doing any major changes, always do a restart.
Prasad Reddi: How to restart the kernel here?
PAUL: On top, there is a restart option, see, on top, where introduction and fundamentals, below that, there is a restart.
PAUL: Like a circular sign.
Naga: Yeah, restart or not.
PAUL: No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
PAUL: Just see where the name introduction and fundamentals.ip can be, the tab.
PAUL: Check the tab, the active tab. Below that, there is a restart button.
Prasad Reddi: Alright, got it, got it here, okay.
Prasad Reddi: Restrapped.
PAUL: Yes.
PAUL: Okay. Okay? Now, that from command that you… no, no, no, no, no. This is OpenAI, no, and you are using, that one, you have to update this import.
Prasad Reddi: Alright, updated the model. Updated the model.
PAUL: a model also that you have to update. So, those two lines you have to update. So, check here, below, it will be written somewhere, I think, LLM, yes, that part. Copy all lines, yes, copy all, the last bracket also.
Prasad Reddi: Alright, yes.
PAUL: Yes.
Naga: It's saying create a .env file. I think example will not work, actually. We have to create a .env.
PAUL: Update the import line, import line, import line. Yes, from Langchen, that also, that you pasted in terminal, that same thing.
Prasad Reddi: Oh, okay, okay.
Naga: burden…
PAUL: Yes, I feel with respect to marketing, I will…
PAUL: It depends upon the data, really. Like, directly, I cannot say common practices in marketing for this rack, like, which embedding model.
PAUL: Like, a few decisions need to be taken based on business only, it's not only always technical.
PAUL: Okay, so when you try to calculate, at least for 6-month usage, or long-term, based on that. So, always try to select somewhere in between. Don't try to always pick the best model, okay, or the one which is, like, performing the worst. It has to be a trade-off.
PAUL: So I always pick something from the top 10. You have to look into the MTV leaderboard, and you can always still look into the top 10.
PAUL: Hassan Khan is asking, can you please reshare the link to the notebook? Which notebook?
PAUL: Please, because I shared Google Drive link and Notion link, only two links are there, Hassan. So, I have not shared any notebook link.
Prasad Reddi: Paul, right, it seems now the code is working, however, like, there are some credential issues.
PAUL: Okay.
Prasad Reddi: I think one.
Prasad Reddi: Once I fill something into the account, I think it will work, right?
PAUL: Yes.
Prasad Reddi: Okay, I'll do that part. I'll do that part. I don't want to take this time, okay, for others. So, I have a few more questions, yeah.
PAUL: So, in this one, in this one, like, I try to understand, we do have some…
Prasad Reddi: Couple of, questions, like…
PAUL: react?
Prasad Reddi: One is the delimiters, delimiters, we have, we have few delimiters, right, for the paragraphs.
Prasad Reddi: For the paragraphs and for the lines here.
PAUL: Separators, separators.
Prasad Reddi: as a separator, separator series. So, are they limited to only these two, these few, or do we need to add.
PAUL: No, no, no. Like, these are the default ones for decursive character text splitter. Similarly, like, going forward, we'll be discussing more than 6 to 8 different types of splitters only.
PAUL: Like, because this is beginners. You cannot use it in production. In production, there are, yes, semantic, hierarchical, contextual, different type of other splitters out there.
PAUL: So, when we'll be discussing, very specifically, for chunking, there will be one separate class. There, I'll be telling you about those advanced topics. This is just the most basic
PAUL: You can think about it.
Prasad Reddi: Got it, got it, got it, got it. Because my question, my question arrived because right now we are only reading text documents, right?
PAUL: Yes, yes.
Prasad Reddi: So, let us say if we wanted to read some, Excels or CSV files, there we have… there we have some other…
PAUL: See, there are other notebooks. You can see I've shared multiple notebooks, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7. Okay, so if you look into document loaders, in the second file, 02, you will see I'm working with JSON. So these things will come slowly, slowly, like, in one day, everything I cannot complete, so…
Prasad Reddi: No, no, no, I'm just, you have to know this point.
PAUL: The code is there, I've shared with you. If you have time, you can go through that stuff, because in the next class, we'll be talking about that only.
Prasad Reddi: Okay, alright, okay, thank you.
Kiran Rathod: Yeah, hi everyone.
PAUL: Yes, correct.
Kiran Rathod: starting my embeddings, right?
Kiran Rathod: So that particular code, I'm using, Google Jiminy… Gemini API, so…
PAUL: Right?
Kiran Rathod: Is the code being shared for that particular part? Because further, I'm not able to execute anything, because there I can see in the API.
PAUL: For embedding creation part.
Kiran Rathod: Yes.
PAUL: Okay, I think for embedding creation part, it was not there.
PAUL: Okay, now we're not gonna…
Kiran Rathod: That part, creating embedding, right? So, from after that, I'm not able to execute.
PAUL: Yes, yes, okay, if you are working with Gemini, you have to update that particular package based on chat generative AI model. Okay, so what you can do, just wait, just share your screen. Probably two lines, I think you need to update it.
Kiran Rathod: Oh, okay.
PAUL: You just wait time.
PAUL: Yeah, myth. Okay, you are solving that issue, fine.
PAUL: Oh, good.
Amit Singh: I mean, Pulsar, if I had you… I don't know. Using Conda, then what command should I give? Like, I tried.
PAUL: Check Notion. Check the Saturday Note. See, everything is in Notion, if you keep it as notes. Open Notion once.
PAUL: Just check the tools under Installation class.
Amit Singh: Yeah, I'll do that, I'll do that.
PAUL: Okay, because all the commands are there. And generally, I feel OS-level errors are… it means that something is getting blocked, if it's an office laptop, if it's not.
Amit Singh: No, no, no, personal laptop. What should I do, then, if it is getting blocked?
PAUL: Because, some type of permission issues, because I can see, again, distribution not found.
PAUL: Okay, like, exactly what distribution it could not form, because…
PAUL: See, you are executing UV, and when you execute UV space hyphen f in version.
Naga: That'd be good.
PAUL: So, you know that it's showing the version.
PAUL: Yes, son.
Naga: location, okay.
PAUL: There is no space in version. Hyphen, hyphen, direct version, no space.
Naga: Incorrect API provider.
PAUL: Okay, so here you are getting the correct results. So, exactly, like, what is getting blocked, it's very hard to say in one shot.
PAUL: Okay.
Amit Singh: Okay, okay, okay.
PAUL: Okay, so, like, you need to check, like, what is getting blocked, because really, a data cannot debug in your system. Okay, you need to have that. Otherwise, you can try creating a different virtual environment with Conda, or probably with Python, to test it out.
Amit Singh: So, I can create in the root directory, no, like, I'm in multiple…
PAUL: Yes, yes, yes, there is no problem with that.
Amit Singh: Got it, got it, got it. Let me try. Okay, yeah.
Naga: All this, authentication error is coming, authentication 401…
Naga: But I gave the core of this API.
PAUL: Incorrect API key.
Naga: No, but I give… I mean, it came till the command number, 7.
PAUL: It is telling incorrect API key, it means that you have to parse the correct API key. Show me your .env file.
Naga: Yeah, it's right here, yeah. It's taken, right? That's why it came till here.
Naga: See? Google.
PAUL: Read the codes. First of all, read the code. You are not reading the code directly, you are executing. Here, it's Google API key. And look into the code, what it is trying to fetch.
Naga: Open API key, okay, okay, I understand. So, what… same… same code, same key, yeah?
PAUL: Same code, same keynote, you have to change that.
Naga: Yeah, yeah.
PAUL: By default, I am using the OpenAI API call. You need to switch to Google API key.
Naga: Okay. Oh, I understood, understood. Yeah, just change the code, okay?
PAUL: Okay, in the… just check, that's why, at least do it once, you will get the underlying.
Naga: Let me build one circle, this one.
PAUL: Yeah, Rahul Parihar and Vij Majvari, yeah.
Kiran Rathod: Paul, I have shared my screen.
Ritvij Maheshwari: Rahul and Redbits want to share? Yeah, I want to also share my screen.
Kiran Rathod: Paul, I have shared many.
PAUL: Yes, yes, yes, fine, fine, fine. Yes, I can see. Okay, now, in your case, what you have to do.
PAUL: embedding physical to this embedding class will change. Okay, I think it will be Gemini embeddings or something like that, because, just wait, I am telling you even…
PAUL: Gemini embeddings Church Group.
PAUL: And the name of the model is Gemini Embedding 003, so… I'm just great.
PAUL: Credentials… Yes, so, see, I'm just, sharing one piece of code in the chat, okay? So…
Naga: Much like…
PAUL: Rather than in the notion, only I'm sharing, okay?
Kiran Rathod: Yeah, sure.
PAUL: Others might also.
Naga: Premium.
PAUL: That, some things that needs to be updated, okay? So…
Naga: Google or people, some of the…
PAUL: in Notion… okay, alright. At the end, you will see that for embedding, I have added the code. Okay, do a hard refresh, you will see.
PAUL: Only the class has changed, and the model has changed.
Naga: Well, bless you, Bill.
Kiran Rathod: Okay, this one? From here.
PAUL: Notion… just wait, whose screen I am seeing, I'm getting confused. Yes, yes, the last… I see, yes, reload this page, reload.
PAUL: do a, okay, now we have two lines.
Kiran Rathod: At a party here, and last year.
PAUL: The last two lines, yes.
Kiran Rathod: But, chat Google Generative AI, we haven't used this, right? Okay.
PAUL: If you're using… if you want to use that LLM, that is very specifically for that LLM change, and this is for embedding change. You asked… you showed me the embedding, so I told you… shared the embedding code. The LLM code is already there.
Kiran Rathod: Only this part of the code, right? .
PAUL: Yes.
PAUL: This is the main import, which will help you to create the embeddings.
PAUL: Okay, just be sure that the variables, I think, yes, remove… you can comment the… comment this part. Okay, and try to exclude. Yes, others?
Kiran Rathod: Hold on just one minute. This one I need to give, and the rest code is the same, correct? From here?
PAUL: LLM, LLM also you need to update, no? Because… LLM.
PAUL: I think,
PAUL: create embeddings after this, LLM will come after this, because I think that part we were getting that kernel crash, so even I didn't execute it.
PAUL: No, yes, this is a simple reaction, yeah. We have not… but you can create the embeddings, at least create that, no? Because in the next step, we have to just update the LL.
PAUL: These things are fine, these things you do not need to delete.
Kiran Rathod: I've created another cell for that, yeah.
PAUL: Okay, okay, okay, fine. Now, prior to execute?
Naga: Paula, I'm getting the open air… open-air error. It's working.
Naga: Yeah, so…
Kiran Rathod: The next part is the same one, I just need to execute this, right?
PAUL: Yes, there's partisan, there is no change here.
Kiran Rathod: Okay, thanks, I'll try to run this.
PAUL: Okay.
Naga: In the ENV file, I commented the open… open API key, because I'm not using that one. I'm just using the Google API key.
PAUL: Yes, yes.
Naga: It went further, but it's still complaining that it needs OpenAPI key, because the error is showing is this OpenAI error, even though I restarted the kernel and everything done.
Naga: And it's true.
PAUL: Show me the code, show me the code, show me the code.
Naga: Yeah, code is right here. This one.
PAUL: So here, your code that is written, it is written for OpenAI.
Naga: Yes.
PAUL: Okay, so you have to update this piece of code for, Gemini. If you change the model, you have to update the code.
PAUL: The updated code is available in Notion, you can take it from Notion.
Naga: Oh, God.
Ritvij Maheshwari: Yeah, high point.
Ritvij Maheshwari: Hi, Paul, Ritvajay, are you able to see my screen?
PAUL: Thank you for fun.
Ritvij Maheshwari: So, Paul, I was just doing this command, and I've already loaded the environment.
PAUL: Show me your requirement.txt, have you removed that, version?
Ritvij Maheshwari: Yes. So, one second.
Ritvij Maheshwari: That… my requirement.txt.
PAUL: In VS Code, I think you have already opened it, no?
Ritvij Maheshwari: Oh, so I'll tell you one of the reasons also that why I'm getting this error. First, I can tell you this, because I just googled it, so I have removed all the versions. These are commented versions, so I don't think these might be implemented.
Ritvij Maheshwari: So, yeah, I have already done… when I googled this, the thing is that, the Gemini is telling me that, you are installing in OneDrive. So, is there any issue that if I create my projects in OneDrive and then I install this, I'm just getting the error in this particular library only?
Ritvij Maheshwari: And this is why it is not able to install it. Is it an issue? Because my…
PAUL: JSON patch, okay? JSON patch, probably, it is a dependency, I feel.
PAUL: Because if you try to directly install Langdain Core, then also, because this Langdain core has a dependency of JSON patch.
PAUL: Okay, because if you… you can try it yourself right now, you can just write UV space pip install and code. I think you will be getting the same check. UV, add UV, I think, previously.
Naga: It's saying undefined variable, Paul. Chat Google generative AI is saying undefined variable.
Ritvij Maheshwari: seem…
PAUL: Undefined means you have to do the import, na? Check Notion. In the Notion it is written.
Kiran Rathod: Sorry, the next part is not getting executed. I have done the embedding part.
Naga: Hmm.
Kiran Rathod: And the next part, right, where we're calling the vector.
Naga: So, whoa.
PAUL: Vector store, what is the… are you getting any error?
Kiran Rathod: Oh yeah, vector store, it is… it's not able to… for no…
PAUL: Exciting your current router.
Kiran Rathod: Yeah, because…
PAUL: Exceeding your current quota, generally means… Okay, share your screen, share your screen completely.
Kiran Rathod: Yeah.
Naga: punch in the league in.
PAUL: You try to do the installation of Langchen Core Respesh.
Ritvij Maheshwari: I already did, it is giving me the same error. So, what I did was, I… because my entire PC is connected to OneDrive, so I installed, means installer SSD, and I installed an SSD. Now, in SSD, I was able to install it, but do you know what is this issue that, do you have any idea that what… why we are not able to install this in OneDrive?
Ritvij Maheshwari: means my entire PC is in OneDrive, means all the folders and everything is in OneDrive, only it is directly synced to OneDrive, means I don't know how to fix that. I'm… right now, I'm doing it in an external SSD.
Ritvij Maheshwari: So, what should I do to fix this?
PAUL: really, like, it is only about one package, like JSON patch or any other package.
Ritvij Maheshwari: It is only about JSON package.
Ritvij Maheshwari: Means if I… let's say, if I install PIP install Pandas, it might not give me… give me any error.
Ritvij Maheshwari: Because this time…
PAUL: JSON patch is giving the error.
Ritvij Maheshwari: Yes.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Now, we have to check inside the JSON package.
PAUL: It's something like, this is a package-level, issue that, JSON patch…
PAUL: Okay, just on patch PYTI, when I go into…
PAUL: Okay, now here I have to look if there is some type of system dependency, Python JSON patch…
PAUL: Because it's, 1.33 is not getting installed, no?
Ritvij Maheshwari: Okay, okay, if I install, now it is, I think, fixed. When I installed PIP installed JSON patch, and then I installed 9Chain, I was, I think it was.
PAUL: It means that UV, through UV, you might get some issue, but without UV, it's working.
Ritvij Maheshwari: Yes. Okay. So, what I did was I installed in the secondary, the SSD. Now, the error that I am facing is, when I'm trying to load this environment, since I have created many environments, I don't know how to load that exact environment, because here it is Python 3.13.2, which is the exact thing that I'm working upon, but let's say if I'm installing the first, the version of the line chain.
Ritvij Maheshwari: it is giving me 0.3.7, but when I checked here, it is… it is also giving me 0.3.2.7, but in the… in my project, if I, directly check the PIP to show land chain.
Ritvij Maheshwari: this version is 1.0.7, which means why it is a different version. Even I checked with the .pwifi, and I was able to run the code, but in here, I was not able to select the proper kernel. Means, how should I get the proper kernel path?
PAUL: See, generally, like, when you are creating it within the folder, that is the best practice, actually. Okay, like, you have a .vng folder, so I know that this is 3.312, so this is the correct one that you have.
PAUL: Okay, but this VNB, again, but this is really, like, the one that you are doing, this is a standard format, but this .VNV, which is activated, this is indeed drive, okay? Now, here, if you are doing a pip show Langchen, then the version of Langchen is changing, but
PAUL: Here, in the notebook, it's showing a different one.
PAUL: Thank you.
Ritvij Maheshwari: add D drive, because there is no option of adding D, means if I go to here.py, here is the option of getting an enter interpreter path. But in IPYNB, it is just saying we directly select the kernel. Means, how should I get that exact interpreter loaded to the… yeah?
PAUL: Yes, okay, then it's a manual where you have to pass that particular path of python.ex.
Ritvij Maheshwari: Yeah, that I can also… I know the path, but where should I path? So, for example, here is the path, python.exe.
PAUL: really manually in VSport, in PyCharm, I do it not here, because most of the time it gets, by default, detected.
Ritvij Maheshwari: Exactly. Means, I can, when I'm going to IPYNB, then it is showing me to enter the interpreted path.
PAUL: She is. There you add the path of D-Drive then. Check.
Ritvij Maheshwari: just…
Ritvij Maheshwari: But how… what about that? Because this has already been added. Let me add that one second. Pivotypython.txi, there it is.
Naga: Paul, the introduction is completed. Introduction, phenomenal. Should I go to the next one?
PAUL: If it is completed, then go!
Naga: Which is the next one we talked about?
PAUL: Simple, simple, simple, simple shit.
PAUL: Yes, I'm here.
Naga: a simple roundup.
Naga: Yes, python.ex, yes.
Ritvij Maheshwari: But here it is added, but what about this? Means, how should I add Hikundel over here?
PAUL: No, no, no. Kernel automatically. First, you have to select the environment, then kernels automatically detect from the environment. Yes.
PAUL: No, no, the first one which was coming, that one only. You want to add… see, this is the default kernel.
Ritvij Maheshwari: Yeah, okay.
PAUL: Bye.
Ritvij Maheshwari: Let me check that one, so that, okay.
PAUL: Check the version once.
Ritvij Maheshwari: Yup.
PAUL: Generally, like,
PAUL: so much complexity in drives, I generally, like… it… everything gets automatically detected in VS Code. That's why I feel that manually you can do it.
PAUL: But again, like, sometimes I feel, it's a problem.
Ritvij Maheshwari: Then the same issue.
PAUL: 0.3.27.
Ritvij Maheshwari: And, in terminal, what is showing? Terminal, it is showing the right person.
Ritvij Maheshwari: 1.04%.
PAUL: 1.07 there. Can you do one thing? Delete, the current.env.
PAUL: That is the… let's start now. Do a deactivate from your terminal.
Ritvij Maheshwari: replicate.
PAUL: And let me see that, because somewhere, some other VNV… okay, deactivate.
PAUL: Delete this, complete.vnv folder, delete it.
Ritvij Maheshwari: Let me, you can answer the rest of the queries, let me just reinstall it once again.
PAUL: Okay, no, don't reinstall. First of all, check that in that Jupyter notebook, till that, like, the kernel is available now, because once you have deleted, it should not be available.
Ritvij Maheshwari: It is still available.
PAUL: So, the path… so, some… right now, it's loading. Just wait. Below the exposure, you can see there's blue color, it's loading. So, wait.
PAUL: Yes, others who are in the chat?
Naga: Yeah, this.
sahil: Fairhead.
PAUL: Yeah, yeah, Raul, yeah, Rahul, I'm adding just a bit. Saikeja, Joe… I hear… Luxury
PAUL: Janaika, and Sachin, Deba, Jagapati.
PAUL: Everybody I have unmuted, whoever wants to share their screen.
Naga: That's it.
Hari Kumar: Can I share screen? My screen pops. How can I share my screen?
PAUL: hurry.
Hari Kumar: Yes.
PAUL: Okay, honey, just…
Hari Kumar: You gotta pick me up.
Rahul Parihar: Yeah, Paul, can I get a…
Amit Singh: Paul, sir, just one simple query, like, in VS Code, I'm not able to see other folder, the base folder that… the root folder that I am in. How to get that?
Amit Singh: I'm not able to see, like, multiple folders.
PAUL: It's 2 o'clock, guys, I think. The session will be automatically ended, because the other mentor will start the class.
PAUL: Okay, so I'm looking into whose screen now.
Rahul Parihar: My… can I get…
PAUL: I'm looking into… yes, I'm looking into Ridwich, Ridwich is deleting files, yeah, you tell.
sahil: Sir, here I'm getting, select and repair. When I'm selecting kernel, it's not getting selected here.
PAUL: wait, wait, wait, it's loading, no? Wait for the loading, because it should come. If you have a .vnv folder, automatically, by default, VS Code detects the current one.
sahil: I am waiting for a long time, sir. It's not coming there.
PAUL: then this is an IDE problem.
PAUL: update your VS Code or switch to a different ID, at least for now side.
sahil: Yes, sir, and also, I have created this RAG project recently, can you give me a feedback about this project?
PAUL: share me the GitHub URL, okay?